<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_2.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.2</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/SOLIS/VSM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>The SOLIS Vector Spectromagnetograph</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The SOLIS Vector Spectromagnetograph (VSM) is an f/6.6
Ritchey-Chretien telescope having a 50-cm aperture.  VSM uses 256 by 1024 pixel
300 frames/s CCD cameras and ferroelectric polarization modulators.  VSM measures
Stokes I, Q, U and V profiles in FeI 630.15 and 630.25 nm lines, Stokes I and V
profiles in the CaII 854.2 nm line and Stokes I profile in the HeI 1083.0 nm line.
Spatial resolution is 1.0 by 1.0 arcsec over a 2048 by 2048 arcsec field
(covering the solar disk).  Scan rate is variable between 0.05 and 5.0 s/arcsec.
The VSM provides the following core science data products: (a) photospheric
full-disk vector-magnetograms using the FeI 630.15 and 630.25 nm lines
(field strength, azimuth, inclination, flux, Doppler velocity, continuum intensity);
(b) chromospheric full-disk magnetograms using the CaII 854.2 nm line (line-of-sight
magnetic flux, Doppler velocity, line core intensity); (c) full-disk HeI 1083.0 nm
line characteristics (equivalent width, continuum intensity, Doppler velocity, line
depth, line asymmetry, Doppler width, Si line width, Si line depth, Si Doppler
velocity); (d) photospheric full-disk longitudinal magnetograms using the FeI 630.15
and 630.25 nm lines (line-of-sight magnetic flux).  Data products (a) to (c) are
produced three times a day while data product (d) were expected to be be produced
once a day.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.W.Harvey</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>SOLIS/VSM web page at NSO</Name>
        <URL>https://solis.nso.edu/VSMOverview.html</URL>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ImagingSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>SOLIS_VSM</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/SOLIS</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
