<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISIS1/CEP</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The purpose of this experiment was to study the global variations of electron temperature and electron concentration at S/C altitudes during solar maximum, and to study characteristics of the S/C ion sheath. The measurements were made with two cylindrical probes, operating as Langmuir probes. There were a boom probe and an axial probe. The axial probe extended 48.3 cm from the S/C, along the spin axis, and was centered among the four telemetry antennas on the underside of the S/C. This probe was capable of measurements undisturbed by the satellite motion only when the probe preceded the S/C in its motion through the plasma. The boom probe extended horizontally and outward (in S/C frame of reference) from a boom 1 m long, which in turn extended from an upper surface of the S/C at an angle of about 45 deg to the spin axis. This probe provided some observations during each S/C spin cycle that were free of S/C wake effects. The probes consisted of three concentric, electrically isolated, stainless steel tubes. The outer (0.24-cm diam and 23-cm long) tube floated at its own equilibrium potential and served to place the collector well away from the S/C plasma sheath. The middle tube (0.165-cm diam) extending 23 cm outward from the outer tube acted as an electrical guard for the collector. Its electrical potential was controlled. The collector (0.058-cm diam) extended 23 cm outward from the driven guard. During each 2-min sequence, a volt-ampere curve was obtained from the sawtooth voltage (-2 to +10 V) applied to the collector. This was interpreted in electron densities over a range from 1.E2 to 1.5E6 electrons per cc, and temperatures from about 400 to 5.E4 deg K. NSSDC has all the useful data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Larry.H.Brace</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1969-009A&amp;ex=7</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes experiment on the ISIS 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>LangmuirProbe</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes on ISIS 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISIS1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
