<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <Instrument>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Apollo12-LM/SWS</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Solar Wind Spectrometer</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>The solar wind spectrometer, designed to measure protons and electrons at the lunar surface, was part of the Apollo 12
                ALSEP package left on the Moon. It consisted of seven modulated Faraday cups opened toward different, but slightly overlapping,
                portions of the lunar sky. The instrument was used to observe the directional intensities of the electron (6-1330 eV) and positive
                ion (18-9780 eV) components of the solar wind and magnetotail plasma that strike the surface of the Moon. The scientific objectives
                of the Solar Wind Spectrometer Experiment were to study the existence of the solar wind plasma on the Moon, the properties of the
                lunar surface and interior, general solar wind properties, and the magnetospheric tail of the Earth.

                Each Faraday cup had a circular opening, five circular grids, and a circular collector. The five circular grids were an aperture
                grid, a modulator grid, a screen grid, a screen plate, and a suppressor grid. These served to apply an AC modulating field to
                incoming particles and screen the modulating field from the sensitive preamplifiers. Sensor covers were over each cup to protect
                against dust during the EVA's and lunar module ascent. Charged particles entered the cup and a current amplifier determined the
                resultant current flow. Energy spectra of positively and negatively charged particles were obtained by applying fixed sequences of
                square-wave AC retarding potentials to a modular grid and measuring the resultant changes in current. One cup was oriented vertically
                and the other six cups surrounded it symmetrically facing 60 degrees off vertical. The electronics were in a temperature-controlled
                container below the sensor assembly attached to a radiator. The instrument had deployed dimensions of 30.5 x 28.2 x 34.5 cm, a mass
                of 5.7 kg, used 12.5 W total power, and had an average data rate of 66.2 bits/sec.

                A sequence of plasma measurements was made every 28.1 seconds, consisting of 14 energy steps spaced a factor of square root of 2
                apart for positive ions and 7 steps a factor of 2 apart for electrons. Flux rates of 2.5E6 to 2.5E11 particles cm^-2 sec^-1 could be
                measured. A large number of internal calibrations are provided. The instrument as deployed had the east-west axis of the instrument
                2.8 degrees north of east and 2.5 degrees off level with the west edge low. The north-south axis was self-leveling. These were well
                within the specifications for the instrument. The ALSEP central station was located at 3.0094 S latitude, 23.4246 W longitude. The
                solar wind spectrometer was situated 4 meters south of the central station.

                The instrument was turned on with the sensor covers in place to provide background data and the covers were removed automatically on
                20 November at about 15:30 UT, approximately one hour after lunar module ascent. The instrument was turned to standby mode during the
                lunar night starting on 3 March 1976 to provide more power to heat the central station electronics and was turned off on 15 January
                1977 to increase power for central station thermal control.</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.R.Williams</PersonID>
                <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
</Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
                <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1969-099C-02</URL>
                <Description>Information about Apollo 12 Solar Wind Spectrometer</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
        <InstrumentType>Spectrometer</InstrumentType>
        <InvestigationName>Apollo 12 solar wind measurement at the lunar surface</InvestigationName>
        <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Apollo12-LM</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>


