<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_6_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.6.0</Version>
  <Document>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Document/SPASE/DataModel/BaseModel</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Space Physics Archive Search and Extract (SPASE) Base Information Model</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.48322/E72C-5Y75</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2021-10-14T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2010-03-19T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.0.1. Update enumerations, update definitions, change occurence of RenderingHints, and other refinements.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2011-01-06T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.2.0. Update enumerations, change ObservatoryGroup to ObervatoryGroupID, add coordinate systems, and other refinements.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2018-05-31T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.3.0. Addition of DOI and PublicationInfo, and Style to AccessURL.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2019-11-14T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.3.1. Additions to multiple enumerations.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2020-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.3.2. Additions to multiple enumerations.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2021-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.4.0. Major addition is Software resource.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2022-07-21T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.4.2. Add SpatialCoverage and add Title and LandingPageURL to PublicationInfo.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2022-08-29T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.5.0. Add Collection resouorce to SPASE Base Model.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2023-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Release 2.6.0. Merged the Simulation 1.0.0 SPASE Model Extensions with the SPASE 2.5.0 Base Model. Four simulation related SPASE resource types added: Model, ModelRun, DisplayOutput, and NumericalOutput. Updated the Description of Current under FieldQuantity and Added Current under ParticleQuantity. Added CurrentDensity under both FieldQuantity and ParticleQuantity. Added the Comet Enumeration List including three members. Added AccessInformtion to the Software SPASE resource type. Added AccessFilenameTemplate and AccessDirectoryTemplate to AccessInformation. Added AccessInformationOptional to the schema and under Model. Added Empirical under the ModelType enumeration list.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>Research in Heliophysics requires information from multiple sources which includes data from and about spacecrafts, groundbased observatories, models, simulations and more. The results from research are also invaluable in building up a body of knowledge and need to be available. All the different sources and types of information are considered a &quot;Resource&quot; The Resources exist, are shared, exchanged and used in a framework called the &quot;data environment&quot; The SPASE (Space Physics Archive Search and Extract) group has defined a Data Model which is a set of terms and values along with the relationships between them that allow describing all the resources in a heliophysics data environment. It is the result of many years of effort by an international collaboration of heliophysicists and information scientists to unify and improve on existing Space and Solar Physics data models. The intent of this Data Model is to provide the means to describe resources, most importantly scientifically useful data products, in a uniform way so they may be easily registered, found, accessed, and used.

The Data Model provides enough detail to allow a scientist to understand the content of Data Products (e.g., a set of files for 3 second resolution Geotail magnetic field data for 1992 to 2005), together with essential retrieval and contact information. It also allows for the incremental annotation of resources with expert assessments and the free association of resources to create bundles or networks of resources. Resource descriptions can be stored with the data or at remote locations. Sites can harvest the resource descriptions to enable services like a search engine or portal (Virtual Observatory). A typical use would be to have a collection of descriptions stored in one or more related internet-based registries of products; that can be queried with specifically designed search engines and ultimately link users to the data they need. The Data Model also provides constructs for describing components of such a data delivery system. This includes repositories, registries and services.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>SPASE Group</Acknowledgement>
      <PublicationInfo>
        <Authors>SPASE Group</Authors>
        <PublicationDate>2021-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</PublicationDate>
        <PublishedBy>SPASE Group</PublishedBy>
      </PublicationInfo>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
        <Role>Publisher</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/SPASE</RepositoryID>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>PDF</Name>
        <URL>https://spase-group.org/data/model/spase-2.6.0.pdf</URL>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>PDF</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/SPASE</RepositoryID>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>XML Schema</Name>
        <URL>https://spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.6.0.xsd</URL>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>XML</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <Keyword>SPASE</Keyword>
    <Keyword>Base Model</Keyword>
    <Keyword>Specification</Keyword>
    <DocumentType>Specification</DocumentType>
    <MIMEType>application/pdf</MIMEType>
  </Document>
</Spase>
