<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-1_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>1.2.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Polar/MFE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Magnetic Fields Experiment (MFE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>MFE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2008-06-18T16:52:28Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objective of this investigation is to make high precision measurements of the magnetic field in the high and low altitude polar magnetosphere (1) to study the morphology of the polar cusp; (2) to determine the site of reconnection; (3) to investigate the behavior of field-aligned current systems at high and low altitudes: how these currents communicate stresses within the magnetosphere, and the role they play in the acceleration of particles; (4) to examine the nature of waves and instabilities in the polar cusp; (5) to investigate the cusp magnetosheath interface and determine how magnetosheath plasma gains access to the magnetosphere; and (6) to provide accurate models of the magnetic field in the high latitude magnetosphere which depend on solar wind and magnetospheric conditions. The instrument consists of dual triaxial magnetometers with flippers. Dual microprocessors and random access memory are used to process the data so that the data sent to earth are immediately usable by all ISTP program investigators without extensive calculations, as well as available on board the spacecraft to other instruments in final corrected form. One million bits of internal storage under microprocessor control provide snapshots with up to 4-ms resolution on command or triggered by changes in the data. The instrument ranges are plus and minus 256, 4096, and 65,536 nT, with corresponding resolutions of 0.004, 0.06, and 1 nT.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christopher.T.Russell</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/database/MasterCatalog?sc=1996-013A&amp;ex=8</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Magnetic Fields Experiment (MFE) experiment on the Polar mission.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Magnetic Fields Experiment (MFE) on Polar</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Polar</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
