<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.7.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.7.1</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Alouette1</ResourceID>
    <NamingAuthority>SMWG</NamingAuthority>
    <ResourceType>Observatory</ResourceType>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Alouette 1</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1962-049A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Alouette-A</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2026-07-20T16:22:34Z</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Only known prior ReleaseDate of the metadata</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2026-05-22T16:40:59Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added new Contact:Role(s). Added ResourceType and NamingAuthority. Updated to 2.7.1. Changed http to https in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Fixed version number separator in top-level schemaLocation attribute. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2026-07-20T16:22:34Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added HelioData InformationURL. JWL</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>Alouette 1 was a small ionospheric observatory instrumented with an ionospheric sounder, a VLF receiver,
                an energetic particle detector, and a cosmic noise experiment. Extended from the satellite shell were two dipole
                antennas (45.7 m and 22.8 m long, respectively) which were shared by three of the experiments on the spacecraft.
                The satellite was spin-stabilized at about 1.4 rpm after antenna extension. After about 500 days, the spin slowed more
                than had been expected, to about 0.6 rpm when satellite spin-stabilization failed. It is believed that the satellite
                gradually progressed toward a gravity gradient stabilization with the longer antenna pointing earthward. Attitude
                information was deduced only from a single magnetometer and temperature measurements on the upper and lower heat shields.
                Attitude determination could have been in error by as much as 10 degrees. There was no tape recorder, so data were available
                only from the vicinity of telemetry stations. Telemetry stations were located to provide primary data coverage near the 80
                degree W meridian and in areas near Hawaii, Singapore, Australia, Europe, and Central Africa. Initially, data were recorded
                for about six hours per day. In September 1972, spacecraft operations were terminated. A data restoration effort began in the
                late nineties and successfully saved a considerable portion of the high-resolution data before the telemetry tapes were
                discarded.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.E.Jackson</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1962-049A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Alouette 1 mission</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>HelioData</Name>
        <URL>https://helio.data.nasa.gov/mission/Alouette1</URL>
        <Description>The HelioData mission page provides an overview of the mission and more, such as all SPASE dataset records associated with it.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
