<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ARTEMIS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ARTEMIS</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Acceleration, Reconnection, Turbulence, and Electrodynamics of
          the Moon’s Interaction with the Sun (ARTEMIS) mission is a spin-off from
          NASA’s Medium-class Explorer (MIDEX) mission THEMIS, a five identical
          micro-satellite (hereafter termed “probe”) constellation in high altitude Earth-orbit
          since 17 February 2007. By repositioning two of the five THEMIS probes (P1 and
          P2) in coordinated, lunar equatorial orbits, at distances of ~55-65 RE geocentric
          (~1.1-12 RL selenocentric), ARTEMIS will perform the first systematic, two-point
          observations of the distant magnetotail, the solar wind, and the lunar space and
          planetary environment. The primary heliophysics science objectives of the
          mission are to study from such unprecedented vantage points and inter-probe
          separations how particles are accelerated at reconnection sites and shocks, and
          how turbulence develops and evolves in Earth’s magnetotail and in the solar wind.
          Additionally, the mission will determine the structure, formation, refilling, and
          downstream evolution of the lunar wake and explore particle acceleration
          processes within it. ARTEMIS’s orbits and instrumentation will also address key
          lunar planetary science objectives: the evolution of lunar exospheric and sputtered
          ions, the origin of electric fields contributing to dust charging and circulation, the
          structure of the lunar interior as inferred by electromagnetic sounding, and the
          lunar surface properties as revealed by studies of crustal magnetism. ARTEMIS is
          synergistic with concurrent NASA missions LRO and LADEE and the anticipated
          deployment of the International Lunar Network. It is expected to be a key element
          in the NASA Heliophysics Great Observatory and to play an important role in
          international plans for lunar exploration.
</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>National Aeronautics and Space Administration/United States</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Vassilis Angelopoulos -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Vassilis.Angelopoulos</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!-- David Sibeck -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.G.Sibeck</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>ARTEMIS Mission Page</Name>
        <URL>https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/artemis/</URL>
        <Description>ARTEMIS Mission Homepage</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>ARTEMIS Description</Name>
        <URL>http://www.igpp.ucla.edu/public/THEMIS/SCI/Pubs/artemis/The_ARTEMIS_Mission_SSR_accepted.pdf</URL>
        <Description>Angelopoulos' paper describing the ARTEMIS mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Magnetotail</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
</Spase>
