<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2.xsd">
	<Version>2.2.2</Version>    <Observatory>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/BARREL</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>BARREL</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2014-04-04T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>BARREL (Balloon Array for Radiation-belt Relativistic Electron Losses) is a multiple-balloon 
			investigation to study particles that escape from the radiation belts and funnel down Earth's magnetic 
			field lines toward the poles. It involves two multi-balloon launches from the South African Antarctic 
			Station (SANAE IV) and the British station, Halley Bay, with an option for a third Northern Hemisphere 
			campaign. During each campaign, 5-8 long-duration balloons payloads (~20 kg) would be launched to an 
			altitude of 30-35 km simultaneously for three to 40 days. Each balloon will carry a NaI scintillator to 
			measure the Bremsstrahlung X-rays produced by precipitating relativistic electrons as they collide with 
			neutrals in Earth's atmosphere to allow an estimate of the total electron loss from the radiation belts. 
			The payload also includes a DC magnetometer. Besides the two scientific instruments, each payload includes 
			solar panels generating 6 W and an onboard battery for power, a number of sensors to monitor the operation of 
			the payload, a GPS receiver to track the position and altitude of the balloon, and an Iridium satellite link 
			that transfer all data at a rate of 2 kps. 

BARREL is the first NASA Living with a Star Geospace Mission of Opportunity.  Observations are planned for when the 
balloon-array will be conjugate with NASA's Van Allen Probes spacecraft, such that direct comparison is possible 
between one another.</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robyn.Millan</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact> 
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>BARREL's Home Page at Dartmouth College</Name>
                <URL>http://www.dartmouth.edu/~barrel/index.html</URL>
                <Description>Information about BARREL</Description>
            </InformationURL>
			<InformationURL>
				<Name>Space Science Reviews Article</Name>
				<URL>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11214-013-9971-z</URL>
				<Description>Detailed information about the BARREL mission.</Description>
			</InformationURL>
        </ResourceHeader>
        <Location>
            <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Stratosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
        </Location>
    </Observatory>
</Spase>


