<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CARISMA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>CARISMA</ResourceName>
	  <AlternateName>Canadian Array for Realtime Investigations of Magnetic Activity</AlternateName>
	  <AlternateName>CANOPUS</AlternateName>
	  <AlternateName>Canadian Auroral Network for the OPEN (Origins of Plasmas in Earth’s Neighborhood) Program Unified Study</AlternateName>
	  
      <ReleaseDate>2010-09-24T21:42:55Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>CARISMA (Canadian Array for Realtime Investigations of Magnetic Activity) is the magnetometer 
	  element of the Geospace Observatory Canada project.

It is the continuation and expansion of an original magnetometer array that was part of the CANOPUS 
ground based instrumentation array. The data from the array has contributed to the publication of 
hundreds of scientific papers and helped to establish CARISMA as an essential international resource 
for magnetospheric physics.

The CARISMA network is an array of magnetometers—devices that are used to measure disturbances in the 
Earth's magnetic field, caused by activity occurring in a region of space near the Earth, known as the 
magnetosphere.  From these measurements, the nature of the event can be determined, and, by using a 
distributed array of magnetometers, more information can be calculated about their time and spatial evolution.

The Northerly CARISMA station, Taloyoak, NUThe CARISMA array spans a range of longitude from Dawson 
City, YK (near the Alaska border, 220.89°E) to Rankin Inlet, NU (267.89°E) and a range of latitude 
from Taloyoak, NU (69.54°N) to Osakis, MN, USA (45.87°N).  Currently most of these sites are on a 
North-South meridian known as the 'Churchill Line'.  By arranging the magnetometers in this way, 
it is possible to investigate the radial propagation of events, because the field measured at higher 
latitudes is affected by regions further from the Earth than those measured at lower latitudes.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>I.R. Mann, D.K. Milling and the rest of the CARISMA team for use of GMAG data. CARISMA is operated by the University of Alberta, funded by the Canadian Space Agency.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ian.Mann</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
	  <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Andy.Kale</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
	  <InformationURL>
        <Name>Canadian Array for Realtime Investigations of Magnetic Activity Homepage</Name>
        <URL>http://www.carisma.ca</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the CARISMA Array.</Description>
	  </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
