<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cassini</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cassini</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Cassini Orbiter's mission consists of delivering a probe (called Huygens, provided by ESA) to Titan,
   and then remaining in orbit around Saturn for detailed studies of the planet and its rings and satellites. The principal
   objectives are to: (1) determine the three-dimensional structure and dynamical behavior of the rings; (2) determine the
   composition of the satellite surfaces and the geological history of each object; (3) determine the nature and origin of
   the dark material on Iapetus' leading hemisphere; (4) measure the three-dimensional structure and dynamical behavior
   of the magnetosphere; (5) study the dynamical behavior of Saturn's atmosphere at cloud level; (6) study the time
   variability of Titan's clouds and hazes; and, (7) characterize Titan's surface on a regional scale.

Spacecraft and Subsystems

The spacecraft was originally planned to be the second three-axis stabilized, RTG-powered Mariner Mark II, a class of
spacecraft developed for missions beyond the orbit of Mars. However, various budget cuts and rescopings of the project
forced a more specialized design, postponing indefinitely any implementation of the Mariner Mark II series.


Cassini is the largest interplanetary spacecraft ever constructed by NASA. It measures 6.8 m in length with a 4 m high
gain antenna. At launch the spacecraft had a mass of 5,655 kg, of which 3,132 kg were propellant.


Cassini is three-axis stabilized. Orientation is maintained through the use of either three reaction wheel assemblies
mounted along orthogonal axes on the spacecraft (for fine pointing control) or via 16 0.5 N thrusters (for coarse
pointing control). The thrusters are arranged in four groups of four and use hydrazine. Orientation is determined
through the use of either three inertial reference units (using solid-state gyroscopes) or a star tracker (which
detects stars in its field of view and compares them with an on-board catalog of 5,000 stars). The thrusters are also
used in the alteration of the spacecraft trajectory of less than 5 m/s. For trajectory corrections greater than 5 m/s, one of two identical
main engines (one serves as a backup) is used. The engines are gimbaled so that thrust can be maintained through the
spacecraft center of mass and burn the bipropellants nitrogen tetroxide and monomethyl hydrazine.


Power is provided to the spacecraft through the use of three radioisotope thermoelectric generators (RTGs). Each RTG
uses the heat generated by the decay of 10.9 kg of plutonium dioxide (PuO2) to generate electrical power to be used
throughout the spacecraft. At the beginning of the mission, each RTG was capable of producing 300 W of electrical
power. By the end of the nominal 11 year mission, the output is expected to degrade to around 210 W per RTG. The
resultant electricity, a regulated 30 V DC, is used not only to provide power to the various science instruments
and spacecraft subsystems, but also to one-time pyrotechnic devices used in the course of the mission, such as to
separate the the spacecraft from the Centaur launch vehicle or to separate the Huygens probe from Cassini.


Although some data will be transmitted in real time, much science data and spacecraft health and status information
are recorded on a solid-state data recorder. Although such systems had been used previously on other missions, Cassini
is the first to use one in deep space. The spacecraft is equipped with two recorders, each of which has a capacity of
2 Gb (gigabits) in the form of dynamic random access memory (DRAM). Because such memory is vulnerable to radiation
effects, the recorders are encased in half-inch thick aluminum. Nonetheless, degradation of the recorders (due to
solar and cosmic ray activity) is expected to reduce their capacity by about 10% by the end of the mission. Recorded
data are then periodically transmitted to Earth via the HGA and erased.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Dennis.L.Matson</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
   <InformationURL>
     <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1997-061A</URL>
        <Description>Information on the Cassini spacecraft.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
     <Name>Jet Propulsion Laboratory Cassini hompage.</Name>
        <URL>https://solarsystem.nasa.gov/missions/cassini/overview/</URL>
        <Description>Cassini page at JPL</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://nssdc/observatory/1997-061A</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Saturn</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
</Spase>
