<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CLIMAX</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>CLIMAX</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T18:19:17Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Walter Orr Roberts, later first director of NCAR and president of UCAR, erected the Harvard 
	  College Observatory's coronagraph in 1940 at Fremont Pass, near the mining town of Climax, Colorado. 
	  Situated on the Continental Divide at an elevation of 11,500 feet, the location provided favorable 
	  conditions for studies of the solar corona due to reduced atmospheric scattering. The Climax Molybdenum 
	  Company donated the land for the Observatory, as well as funds for constructing buildings and a $6,000 grant. 
	  Roberts was the sole resident scientist at the isolated mountain Observatory, and he and his wife Janet 
	  remained the only residents in the early years.

During World War II, coronagraph observations of solar activity made by Walter Roberts at Climax had important 
implications for wartime communication over long distances. The relationship between sun weather and radio 
transmissions was used by the U.S. military in predicting favorable times for scheduling large-scale military 
operations that depended on good radio communications. After the war, the Climax station became the first scientific 
corporation, the High Altitude Observatory of Harvard University and the University of Colorado. HAO's administrative 
offices and Roberts moved to Boulder. The Observatory moved in 1952 to a new location three miles north of the 
town of Climax, where a new larger dome was built. In 1960, the High Altitude Observatory became a research division of NCAR.

The Climax Observatory would serve as NCAR’s high altitude site for solar research for 31 years, closing in 
July 1972 as the observing facilities at Climax had gradually became non-competitive with more modern observatories 
due to the increasingly demanding requirements of solar research programs. </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/UNKNOWN</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
	  <InformationURL>
        <Name>Climax Observatory Homepage</Name>
        <URL>https://www.archives.ucar.edu/exhibits/hao/facilities/climax-observatory</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Climax observatory.</Description>
	  </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
