<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Dynamics Explorer 1</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1981-070A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Explorer 62</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>DE-A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>DE 1</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Dynamics Explorer-A</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
          The Dynamics Explorer (DE) mission's general objective is to
          investigate the strong interactive processes coupling the hot,
          tenuous, convecting plasmas of the magnetosphere and the
          cooler, denser plasmas and gases corotating in the earth's
          ionosphere, upper atmosphere, and plasmasphere. Two
          satellites, DE 1 and DE 2, were launched together and were
          placed in polar coplanar orbits, permitting simultaneous
          measurements at high and low altitudes in the same field-line
          region.
         
          The DE 1 spacecraft (high-altitude mission) uses an
          elliptical orbit selected to allow
         
          * (1) measurements extending
          from the hot magnetospheric plasma through the plasmasphere to
          the cool ionosphere;
          * (2) global auroral imaging, wave
          measurements in the heart of the magnetosphere, and crossing
          of auroral field lines at several earth radii; and
          * (3) measurements for significant periods along a magnetic field
          flux tube.
         
          The spacecraft approximated a short polygon 137 cm
          in diameter and 115 cm high. The antennas in the X-Y plane
          measured 200-m tip-to-tip, and on the Z-axis are 9 meters tip-
          to-tip. Two six-meter booms are provided for remote
          measurements. Power is supplied by a solar cell array, mounted
          on the side and end panels. The spacecraft is spin stabilized,
          with the spin axis normal to the orbital plane, and the spin
          rate at ten plus or minus 0.1 rpm. A pulse code modulation
          (PCM) telemetry data system is used that operates in real time
          or in a tape-recorder mode. Data have been acquired on a
          science-problem-oriented basis, with closely coordinated
          operations of the various instruments, both satellites, and
          supportive experiments. Data acquired from the instruments are
          temporarily stored on tape recorders before transmission at an
          8:1 playback-to-record ratio. Additional operational
          flexibility allows a playback-to-record ratio of 4:1. The
          primary data rate is 16,384 bits per second. Since commands
          are stored in a command memory unit, spacecraft operations are
          not real time, except for the transmission of the wideband
          analog data from the Plasma Wave Instrument (81-070A-02).
         
          On October 22, 1990 science operations were terminated. On
          February 28, 1991 Dynamics Explorer 1 operations were
          offically terminated.
         
          Additional details may be found in R. A.
          Hoffman et al., Space Sci. Instrum., v. 5, n. 4, p. 349, 1981.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.A.Hoffman</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1981-070A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Dynamics Explorer 1 mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DE</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
</Spase>
