<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/FAST</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>FAST</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1996-049A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Small Explorer/FAST</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Explorer 70</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>SMEX/FAST</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Fast Auroral SnapshoT Explorer</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Fast Auroral SnapshoT Explorer (FAST) was successfully
   launched on 1996-08-21 into its intended orbit. FAST investigates the
   plasma physics of auroral phenomena at extremely high time and spatial
   resolution using the full complement of particle and fields instruments.
   FAST is the second spacecraft (SAMPEX was first) in the Small Explorer
   (SMEX) program at NASA-GSFC. SMEX was established to provide rapid (3 year
   development) low cost ($35M development) mission opportunities (1 per year)
   to the space science community using a single designated Principal
   Investigator (PI).

      In order to capture the auroral phenomena over small time (microseconds) and spatial
      scales, FAST utilizes high speed data sampling, a large, fast-loading ("burst")
      memory, and a smart, on-board software to trigger on the appearance of various
      key phenomena. Using a 1 Gb solid-state memory and a data acquisition rate of 8
      Mbs (almost two orders of magnitude faster than previous satellites), FAST
      produces high-resolution "snapshots" of auroral arcs and other interesting auroral
      events. FAST flies in a highly eccentric, near-polar orbit precessing nominally
      one degree per day. Scientific investigations are operate in a campaign mode
      (about 60 days long) as apogee transitions through the northern auroral zone and
      in less intense survey mode during the rest of the orbit.

      The FAST mission uses a unique (not a SAMPEX derivative), lightweight, orbit-normal
      spinner spacecraft developed by the SMEX project. The spacecraft has body-mounted
      solar arrays, and is spin-stabilized, rotating at 12 rpm with the spin axis normal
      to the orbit plane ("cartwheel"). The four FAST experiments are: (1) the
      Electrostatic Analyzers (ESA) for measuring the electron and ion distribution
      function, (2) the Time-of-flight Energy Angle Mass Spectrograph (TEAMS) for
      measuring the full 3-dimensional distribution function of the major ion species,
      (3) the Tri-Axial Fluxgate and Search-coil Magnetometers for measuring magnetic
      field data, and (4) the Electric Field/Langmuir Probe Instrument for obtaining
      electric field data and plasma density and temperature. The FAST electric field
      instrument stopped providing meaningful data around 2002, all other instruments
      and systems continue to function nominally.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.W.Carlson</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1996-049A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the FAST mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
</Spase>
