<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.7.1</Version>
   <Observatory>
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/FERMI</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2025-03-19</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2025-03-19</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Initial SPASE 2.7.1 XML resource description submission, metadata submitted by Rebecca Ringuette</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>The Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope is a probe-class international and multi-agency observatory launched in 2008 that surveys the dynamic gamma-ray sky across energies from about 8 keV to over 300 GeV. Equipped with the Large Area Telescope and the Gamma-ray Burst Monitor, Fermi delivers rapid all-sky coverage roughly every three hours while retaining the ability to point at specific targets. Its science program includes mapping the gamma-ray sky and its background, investigating blazars and other active galactic nuclei, studying pulsars, tracking gamma-ray bursts, exploring the nature of dark matter, and examining particle acceleration in novae. As the successor to the Compton Gamma-ray Observatory from NASA's Great Observatories program, Fermi has operated with high reliability and no significant performance degradation, has no mission-limiting consumables, and makes its data immediately and publicly available to enable a broad range of astrophysical research.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Marcos.Santander</PersonID>
            <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Fermi Home Page</Name>
            <URL>https://fermi.gsfc.nasa.gov/overview.html</URL>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <Location>
         <ObservatoryRegion>Earth</ObservatoryRegion>
         <ObservatoryRegion>Sun</ObservatoryRegion>
      </Location>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>2008-06-11</StartDate>
      </OperatingSpan>
   </Observatory>
</Spase>
