<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.6.0.xsd">
   <Version>2.6.0</Version>
   <Observatory>
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GIRO</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>GIRO Group</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory Group</AlternateName>
         <ReleaseDate>2024-01-17T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-10-20T14:47:31</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Edited Acknowledgement, added Information URL, Contact, and updated SPASE version LNG.</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>GIRO provides accurate specification of the electron density in the Earth&#039;s
   ionosphere at &gt;60 locations in the world. 37 GIRO locations provide real-time ionospheric
   data to the central server in Lowell, Massachusetts within several minutes. GIRO sites
   are equipped by Digisonde instruments that use the high frequency remote sounding
   technique to probe the bottomside ionosphere from 80 km up to the peak of ionospheric
   plasma density. Real-time and retrospective data from GIRO locations are ingested in Lowell
   Digital Ionogram DataBase (DIDBase) GIRO data are open for public access via DIDBase and
   DriftBase Web Portals, and custom software tools for digisonde data analysis, SAO Explorer
   and Drift Explorer.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Heavy investments of time, effort, expertise,
      and funds continue to be made to produce, collect, quality
      control, interpret, and archive ionosonde data. It is therefore
      important that the data suppliers and Lowell GIRO Data Center
      (LGDC) are appropriately acknowledged in scientific publications
      that include analysis of data obtained from LGDC servers.

      Please read Rules of the Road
      https://giro.uml.edu/didbase/RulesOfTheRoad.html for license
      information and refer to Acknowledgements List
      https://giro.uml.edu/didbase/acknowledgements.htm to use GIRO
      data per license requirements.</Acknowledgement>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Bodo.W.Reinisch</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ivan.A.Galkin</PersonID>
            <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Leonard.N.Garcia</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>GIRO (Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory) Home Page.</Name>
            <URL>https://giro.uml.edu/</URL>
            <Description>Access to real-time data and software tools</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory (GIRO) Article</Name>
            <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.5047%2Feps.2011.03.001</URL>
            <Description>Detailed information about the Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>DIDBase Fast Station List</Name>
            <URL>https://giro.uml.edu/ionoweb</URL>
            <Description>A listing of observatories, locations and date ranges of available data from each. Links provide access to ionograms.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <Location>
         <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion>
      </Location>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>1987-01-01T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
         <Note>Different GIRO locations have come online on different
      dates. See the individual location descriptions for more
      information. </Note>
      </OperatingSpan>
   </Observatory>
</Spase>
