<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES8</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GOES 8</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1994-022A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>GOES-NEXT</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>GOES-I</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-11-20T23:08:50Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>GOES 8 is the 11th in a series of NASA-developed, NOAA-operated, geosynchronous and operational spacecraft. The triaxis-stabilized spacecraft carries (1) Imager and Sounder system to provide visible and infrared images of cloud cover, and to determine atmospheric temperature and water vapor content at various levels, (2) a meteorological data collection system to relay processed data from central weather facilities to regional stations equipped with APT and to collect and retransmit data from remotely located earth-based platforms, (3) a space environment monitor (SEM) system to measure proton, electron, and solar X-ray fluxes and magnetic fields, (4) a Search and Rescue (SAR) system to detect and relay distress calls from land and ocean, and (5) a WEFAX system to disseminate weather information to the user community via FAX. The cylindrically shaped spacecraft measures 190.5 cm in diameter and 230 cm in length, exclusive of a magnetometer that extends an additional 300 cm beyond the cylindrical shell. The imaging telescope is mounted on the equipment shelf and views the earth through a special aperture in the side of the spacecraft. The solar array of 1,057 W supplies two nickel-cadmium batteries of 12 Ampere-hour each. The CCSDS-compliant telemetry is in real-time at 2.0 kbs through S-bands. The eventual parking longitude of the spacecraft will be over 75 deg W. The SEC package (X-rays, H+, e-, monitors, and the Magnetometer) became inoperational on or before April 2003.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/UNKNOWN</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/database/MasterCatalog?sc=1994-022A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the GOES  8 mission</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroup>GOES</ObservatoryGroup>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
