<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <Observatory>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/IRIS</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Interface Region Imaging Spectrograph (IRIS)</ResourceName>
     <AlternateName>2013-033A</AlternateName>
            <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>The Interface Region Imaging Spectrograph (IRIS) is a NASA Small Explorer class solar mission. It was launched from a Pegasus XL flying out of Vandenberg AFB in California. The rocket was deployed from an Orbital L-1101 carrier aircraft flying over the Pacific Ocean at an altitude of 39,000 feet (about 12 km), roughly 100 miles northwest of Vandenberg. The rocket was dropped at 7:27 p.m. PDT on 27 June 2013 (02:27 UT, 28 June).

IRIS is intended to advance Sun-Earth connection studies by tracing the flow of energy and plasma into the corona and heliosphere for which no suitable observations exist. To achieve this IRIS will obtain high-resolution UV spectra and images of the sun's chromosphere, specifically on the non-thermal energy that creates the corona and the solar wind.

IRIS seeks to determine: (1) the types of non-thermal energy which dominate in the chromosphere and beyond; (2) the means by which the chromosphere regulates mass and energy supply to the corona and heliosphere; and, (3) how magnetic flux and matter rise through the lower solar atmosphere, and the role played by flux emergence in flares and mass ejections. To answer these questions, IRIS will utilize a single intrument, a multi-channel imaging spectrograph. See the experiment description for details on the IRIS instrument.</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alan.M.Title</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
                <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=2013-033A</URL>
                <Description>Information about IRIS</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
        <Location>
            <ObservatoryRegion>Sun.Chromosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
            <ObservatoryRegion>Sun.TransitionRegion</ObservatoryRegion>
            <ObservatoryRegion>Sun.Corona</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
</Spase>


