<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_1.xsd">
 <Version>2.3.1</Version>
 <Observatory>
  <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/SipleExperiment</ResourceID>
  <ResourceHeader>
   <ResourceName>Siple Experiment</ResourceName>
   <ReleaseDate>2020-12-29T15:51:48</ReleaseDate>
   <Description>
     During its operation from 1973 to 1988, the Siple Station
     experiment provided numerous observations of magnetospheric
     wave's particle and wave's interactions and it remains the
     preeminent source for validating computer simulations of whistler
     mode wave's particle interactions.  The Siple Station Experiment
     consisted of a transmitting station in Antarctica and a
     receiving station located at the conjugate point in Quebec,
     Canada. Siple Station, Antarctica was located at 75.93 deg. S,
     84.25 deg. W geographic, corresponding to an invariant latitude
     of 60.4 deg. S, at L = 4.2. The facility operated a  100 kW, 21.2
     Km elevated dipole transmitting between 1 to ~6kHz. In 1986 the
     Siple station facility was upgraded with the addition of crossed
     dipoles for the generation of variable  polarization.

 
   The main observation point for the whistler mode signals
   from Siple station was near the geomagnetic conjugate point 
   first (1973-1985) at Roberval, Quebec (48.52 deg. N, 72.23 deg. W)
   and from 1986 to 1988
   near Lake Mistissini, Canada (50.42 deg. N, 73.87
   deg. W). The receiver system consisted of two delta-shaped crossed loops
     mounted on a central 30-foot-high(~9 m) support with a base of 60
     feet (18.3 m). 

    Complete results of the Siple
   station experiment are summarized in Helliwell, R. A.,(1988)
   Rev. Geophys., 26, 551-578, but analysis
   work on this dataset continued well after the experiment
   ended. These data were originally stored on Ampex magnetic tapes
   then converted over to a digitized format with some error
   correction applied as described by Li et al., (2014) JGR, 119,1837-1850.  </Description>
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.A.Helliwell</PersonID>
    <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
   </Contact>
  <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Morris.Cohen</PersonID>
    <Role>ArchiveSpecialist</Role>
   </Contact>
   <InformationURL>
    <URL>http://waldo.world/description-of-data/</URL>
   </InformationURL>
  </ResourceHeader>
  <Location>
   <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion>
  </Location>
  <OperatingSpan>
    <StartDate>1973-01-01T00:00:00</StartDate>
    <StopDate>1988-01-01T00:00:00</StopDate>
  </OperatingSpan>
 </Observatory>
</Spase>
