<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_1.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.1</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/SNOE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Student Nitric Oxide Explorer (SNOE)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Student Nitric Oxide Explorer (SNOE) project was the first satellite to be launched in NASA's Student Explorer
                Demonstration Initiative (STEDI) program. STEDI, managed for NASA by USRA, is a pilot program to demonstrate that high-quality
                space science can be carried out with small, low-cost (less than $4.4 Million) free-flying satellites on a time scale of two years
                from go-ahead to launch. The scientific objectives of the Student Nitric Oxide Explorer were a detailed study of variations in
                nitric oxide (NO) in the Earth thermosphere. NO is an important minor constituent that strongly affects the ion composition of the
                ionosphere and the thermal structure of the thermosphere. Specific objectives were to: (1) determine how variations in the solar
                soft X-radiation produce changes in the density of nitric oxide in the lower thermosphere; and, (2) determine how auroral activity
                produces increased nitric oxide in the polar regions. The spacecraft is a compact hexagonal structure, approximately 0.9 m high
                and 1 m across it widest dimension, weighing a maximum of 100 kg. It was launched into a sun-synchronous circular orbit at
                530-580 km altitude and 97.7 degrees inclination. It span at 5 rpm with the spin axis normal to the orbit plane and carried
                three instruments: an ultraviolet spectrometer to measure nitric oxide altitude profiles, a two-channel auroral photometer
                to measure auroral emissions beneath the spacecraft, and a five-channel solar soft X-ray photometer. SNOE also carried a GPS
                receiver for accurate orbit and attitude determination.

                The SNOE spacecraft and its instrument complement were designed, built, and operated entirely at the Laboratory for Atmospheric
                and Space Physics (LASP) of the University of Colorado at Boulder.

SNOE re-entered the atmosphere on 12/13/03 at 09:34Z +/- 6 minutes, descending over 2.9 deg S, 273.8 deg E, on orbit 32248, after 5 years and 290 days.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.A.Barth</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1998-012A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Student Nitric Oxide Explorer (SNOE)</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Thermosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
</Spase>
