<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_5_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.5.0</Version>
   <Observatory>
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/SolarOrbiter</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Solar Orbiter Spacecraft</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2021-05-30T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2021-05-30T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Updated to SPASE Version 2.3.2 if needed, Applied quality conntrol for DOI usage, LFB</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-07-26T13:03:03.588</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Corrected Launch Date to Feb 10, SY</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>The European Space Agency, ESA, Solar Orbiter mission will study the Sun from a highly elliptical orbit getting as close as 0.28 AU or 42 million km from which it will use a suite of instruments to make high-latitude observations of the Sun and heliosphere, including the magnetic field, energetic particles, solar wind, and transient phenomena.

The Solar Orbiter primary science objectives are to study:

* 1) the drivers of the solar wind and the origin of the coronal magnetic field to determine how solar transients drive heliospheric variability
* 2) learn how solar eruptions produce the energetic particles that fill the heliosphere
* 3) how the solar dynamo works and drives connections between the Sun and the heliosphere

Solar Orbiter comprises a 2.5 m ⨯ 3.0 m ⨯ 2.5 m box-shaped bus with two solar panel wings spanning 18 m to supply power. Total launch mass is 1800 kg. There is a 4.4 m instrument boom and three 6.5 m antennas protruding from the spacecraft body. A carbon fiber composite, titanium layered solar shield covers one side of the spacecraft. The shield has apertures for various instruments. The spacecraft is 3-axis stabilized to keep the heat shield oriented towards the Sun. Telemetry is dual X-band through steerable medium and high-gain antennas. Low gain antennas are used in the launch and early orbit phase and are available for backup.

Solar Orbiter carries two types of instruments, in-situ instruments making direct measurements of the heliospheric environment, and remote sensing instruments, which view the Sun and heliosphere from a distance.

The in-situ instruments comprise: 

* 1) Energetic Particle Detector, EPD
* 2) Magnetometer, MAG
* 3) Radio and Plasma Waves sensor, RPW
* 4) Solar Wind Plasma Analyser, SWA

The remote-sensing instruments comprise: 

* 1) Extreme Ultraviolet Imager, EUI
* 2) Coronagraph, METIS
* 3) Polarimetric and Helioseismic Imager, PHI
* 4) Heliospheric Imager, SoloHI
* 5) Spectral Imaging of the Coronal Environment, SPICE
* 6) X-ray Spectrometer/Telescope, STIX

The total massm of the scientific payload is 209 kg.

Solar Orbiter launched from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station on 10 February 2020 at 04:03 UT or at 23:03 Eastern Standard Time, EST, on February 9th. The spacecraft launched on an Atlas 5-411 (AV-087) into a short Earth parking orbit followed by injection into an elliptical heliocentric orbit. The first perihelion will be in June 2020. The mission will use six gravity assist maneuvers during the 7-year nominal mission: 

+---------------------------------+
| Flyby | Planet | Encounter Date |
|---------------------------------|
|   1   | Venus  |   2020-12-26   |
|   2   | Venus  |   2021-08-08   |
|   3   | Earth  |   2021-11-26   |
|   4   | Venus  |   2022-09-03   |
|   5   | Venus  |   2025-02-18   |
|   6   | Venus  |   2026-12-28   |
+---------------------------------+

The series of encounters will tilt the spacecraft orbit to an inclination of 25° and will yield an orbit with a perihelion of 0.28 AU, an aphelion of 0.91 AU, and a period of 168 days. Solar Orbiter will make fourteen perihelion passes during the nominal mission. If a three year extended mission is approved, Solar Orbiter will make three more Venus flybys that will bring the inclination to 33°.

+---------------------------------+
| Flyby | Planet | Encounter Date |
|---------------------------------|
|   7   | Venus  |   2028-03-17   |
|   8   | Venus  |   2029-06-10   |
|   9   | Venus  |   2030-09-02   |
+---------------------------------+

The extended mission will involve an additional eight more perihelion passes.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge the European Space Agency, ESA</Acknowledgement>
         <Funding>
            <Agency>European Space Agency, ESA, and National Aeronautical and Space Agency, NASA, Programs</Agency>
            <Project>Solar Orbiter Mission</Project>
         </Funding>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Cesar.Garcia.Marirrodriga</PersonID>
            <Role>ProjectManager</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Seiji.Yashiro</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Solar Orbiter Mission Web Page, ESA</Name>
            <URL>https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Solar_Orbiter</URL>
            <Description>Solar Orbiter overview with links to more detailed information, hosted by the European Space Agency, ESA</Description>
            <Language>en</Language>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Solar Orbiter Mission Web Page, NASA</Name>
            <URL>https://www.nasa.gov/solar-orbiter/</URL>
            <Description>Solar Orbiter overview with links to more detailed information, hosted by the National Aeronautical and Agency, NASA</Description>
            <Language>en</Language>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>SolarOrbiter Spacecraft paper, Published by Sol. Phys., Date: 2005-05-23</Name>
            <URL>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11207-012-0085-7</URL>
            <Description>Author List: Muller, D., Marsden, R. G., St. Cyr, O. C., Gilbert, H. R., &amp; the Solar Orbiter Team</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Solar Orbiter Spacecraft, NSSDC Master Catalog Listing</Name>
            <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=2020-010A</URL>
            <Description>NSSDC Master Catalog Listing for the Solar Orbiter Spacecraft, NSSDCA/COSPAR ID: 2020-010A</Description>
            <Language>en</Language>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <Location>
         <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservatoryRegion>
         <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
      </Location>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>2020-02-10T04:03:00</StartDate>
         <Note>The start date and time listed here correspond to when Solar Orbiter was launched</Note>
      </OperatingSpan>
   </Observatory>
</Spase>
