<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-1_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>1.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://VMO/Observatory/ST5</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ST5</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Wind/GGS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2007-05-30T19:15:57Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
      ST5 mission was a part of the NASA New Millennium Program to flight-validate new concepts and technologies. ST5 project designed, built and operated three 25 kg spacecraft utilizing breakthrough technologies. It demonstrated the ability to achieve accurate, research-quality scientific measurements while operating the 3 micro-satellites as a single constellation.
      
      ST5 launched on March 22, 2006 onboard the Pegasus rocket out of Vandenberg. Approximately 10 min after launch, ejected 3 min apart frisbee-style. Mission duration was 90 days, 7 day launch and early orbit period, mission completed June 20, 2006. The orbit was 105.6 deg inclination (full sun orbit), ~300 km perigee, ~4500 km apogee, 136 minute period.
      
      The ST5 micro-satellites were developed by NASA/GSFC in partnership with industry, other NASA centers and academia. They were built within tight volume and mass constraints, low-power and low voltage, size ~50 cm x 48 cm, integral card cage structure (for C&amp;DH, PSE), mass ~25 kg. Spacecraft-induced magnetic field effects as measured at the magnetometer
sensor location less than 10 nT (d.c.), 5 nT (a.c.). The spacecraft carried a science demonstration instrument, a high-resolution, high-precission, three-axis flux-gate magnetometer.

      The ST5 constellation returned unprecedented data on the Earth's auroral currents as well as on the crustal magnetic field. ST5 provided for the first time simultaneous multi-point measurements of auroral electric currents at low altitudes, which allow us to separate temporal and spatial variations of these currents. ST5 provided a unique data set on the Earth's crustal magnetic field, which is a consequence of both the constellation flying, and the enhanced resolution from the low perigee, lower than any previous geomagnetism mission.
      </Description>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Guan Le -->
        <PersonID>spase://nssdc/person/???</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>WIND spacecraft home page</Name>
        <URL>http://pwg.gsfc.nasa.gov/wind.shtml</URL>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/database/MasterCatalog?sc=1994-071A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Wind mission</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Magnetotail</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
