<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Service>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Service/POLAR/UVI/KP-Mosaics</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Polar UVI KP Mosaics</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-10-08T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
The Ultraviolet Imager (UVI) is a small camera that detected and produced images of the ultraviolet light of the aurora, day and night.  
Using any of five specially designed filters the UVI camera imaged an eight degree circular field of view.  Key Parameter (KP) images 
are calculated at nominal 5-10 minute intervals at spacecraft altitudes above 6 Re.  The UVI KP image is background subtracted and 
calibrated to radiance values (photon cm^-2 cm^-1). The data is a rectangular two-dimensional array (228 rows x 200 columns). Only a 
circular region of the rectangular array contains valid image data.  The UVI KP Image Archive 
(http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/kpgs-Data.htm) allows the user to look at all the KP Mosaics for a selected month.  The gif or png 
plot files contain the up to 35 KP images taken with the LBHL (160-190 nm) filter.   Reference images are also provided showing the 
location of the UVI field of view relative to continental outlines.  UVI Key Parameters are summary data only.  In some cases parameters 
such as pointing and calibration were not adequate to support quantitative scientific analysis.  They should not to be used for presentation, 
publication, or analysis. The UVI KP CDF files only contain output for normal instrument mode when the spacecraft is in 9.2 second science 
telemetry mode.  No Key Parameters are produced when the spacecraft is in maneuver telemetry mode, when UVI is in star (fast) mode, 
and when the despun platform is pointed away from the earth.
	 </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/George.K.Parks</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peggy.Sloan</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI Home Page</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/</URL>
        <Description>
The Polar Ultraviolet Imager (UVI) Home Page contains links that describe the instrument, its operation, allow the 
user to view 36 second images and key parameter mosaics from the mission and download software, plus links 
to the UVI data archive, to lists of UVI publications and presentations, and several miscellaneous mission sites.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessURL>
      <Name>UVI KP Image Archive</Name>
      <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/kpgs-Data.htm</URL>
    </AccessURL>
  </Service>
</Spase>
