<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Service>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Service/POLAR/UVI/Software</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Polar UVI Processing and Viewing Software</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-08-01T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
The Polar UVI Processing and Viewing Software packages are archived on the NSSTC UVI Data Archive where they are availble for 
downloading. 
      </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/George.K.Parks</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peggy.Sloan</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI Level-one Processing/Viewing Software: studio</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/uvidata/software/studio</URL>
        <Description>
studio is a widget-based IDL program used to analyze and view single Polar UVI level-one images found in the 
po_level1_uvi_yyyymmdd_vnn.cdf files.  These files are available from on the NSSTC UVI Data Archive 
(http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/uvidata/), and the cdaweb (ftp://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/istp/polar/uvi_level1/).  studio allows 
presentation of images in MLT-dial format or projected against continental outlines on an Earth projection.  Multiple images can be 
outputted as single image frames that can be concatenated into a movie. 
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI Level-one Viewing Software: l1vu</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/uvidata/software/l1vu</URL>
        <Description>
l1vu is a widget-based IDL program used to view Polar UVI level-one images found in the po_level1_uvi_yyyymmdd_vnn.cdf files.  
These files are available from on the NSSTC UVI Data Archive (http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/uvidata/), and the cdaweb 
(ftp://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/istp/polar/uvi_level1/).  l1vu allows access to instrument housekeeping values and detailed 
examination of image pixel values.  Though it includes functionality to display images in mlt-dial or geodetic lat/lon formats, its 
primary role is as an engineering tool to examine the raw image values.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI Level-one Viewing Software: revu</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/uvidata/software/revu</URL>
        <Description>
revu is a widget-based IDL program used to view Polar UVI level-one images found in the po_level1_uvi_yyyymmdd_vnn.cdf files.  
These files are available from on the NSSTC UVI Data Archive (http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/uvidata/), and the cdaweb 
(ftp://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/istp/polar/uvi_level1/).  Unlike studio and l1vu which focus on single image frames, revu is designed 
to quickly show multiple frames in a movie format.  This allows quick scans of image data and highlights changes.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI L0 to L1 Software: l0tol1</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/uvidata/software/revu</URL>
        <Description>
l0tol1 is C/IDL software used to process UVI level-zero data.   The output is the UVI level-one CDF files.  The l0 files
are available at ftp://pwgdata.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/compressed/po/uvi/lz/.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI Home Page</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/</URL>
        <Description>
The Polar Ultraviolet Imager (UVI) Home Page contains links that describe the instrument, its operation, allow the 
user to view 36 second images and key parameter mosaics from the mission and download software, plus links 
to the UVI data archive, to lists of UVI publications and presentations, and several miscellaneous mission sites.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessURL>
      <Name>Polar UVI Software Archive</Name>
      <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/uvidata/software/</URL>
      <Description>The Polar Ultraviolet Imager (UVI) Software Archive.</Description>
    </AccessURL>
  </Service>
</Spase>
