<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Service>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Service/POLAR/UVI/Website</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Polar UVI Website</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-08-01T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
The Polar Ultraviolet Imager (UVI) Website contains a UVI image viewer, information about the UVI camera and its operations, an 
image search tool, key parameter description, a list of publications and presentations, access to data and software archives, and a 
list of contacts and related sites. 
      </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/George.K.Parks</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peggy.Sloan</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI Home Page</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/</URL>
        <Description>
The Polar Ultraviolet Imager (UVI) Home Page contains links that describe the instrument, its operation, allow the 
user to view 36 second images and key parameter mosaics from the mission and download software, plus links 
to the UVI data archive, to lists of UVI publications and presentations, and several miscellaneous mission sites.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Polar UVI Browse Images</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/brwseimages.html</URL>
        <Description>
The Browse Image viewer allows the user to scan all the images by specifying a year and day-of-year.  The gif plot files contain the 
UVI image in geometric coordinates and in magnetic latitude / magnetic local time.  At the bottom of each plot is a plot of Polar 
Spacecraft altitude in Re versus time for the day with a red line indicating the time/altitude when the image was taken.  Below the plot 
is list of instrument parameters and spacecraft location.   The user can user arrow keys to move back and forth through the images
for a day and use the listed image times (hhmmss.gif) to select a specific image.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI KP Image Archive</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/kpgs-Data.htm</URL>
        <Description>
The UVI KP Image Archive allows the user to look at all the KP Mosaics for a selected month.  The gif or png plot files contain the up to 
35 KP images nominally taken with the LBHL filter.  Reference images are also provided showing the location of the UVI field of view 
relative to continental outlines.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>UVI On-line Search</Name>
        <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/ost/</URL>
        <Description>
The UVI Online Search Tool (OST) provides an online search and visualization tool of UVI auroral and geophysical metadata covering 
the solar cycle 23.  Data is available from  March 1996 through July 2004. OST is used to find times of UVI image data that match 
specific research requirements.  Search by time, UVI operational mode, geophysical indices, location, or image content.  Search 
results can be viewed in tabular form, in summary plots, or as a downloadable text file. Once the search is complete, the digital 
image data and software to work with the data can be downloaded.
		</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessURL>
      <Name>Polar UVI Home Page</Name>
      <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/uvi/</URL>
    </AccessURL>
  </Service>
</Spase>
