<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ulysses/COSPIN</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cosmic Ray and Solar Particles (SIM/COSPIN)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>COSPIN</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>SIM</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objectives of this investigation are to study the energy, charge, and mass spectra of energetic
        charged particles (both electrons and nuclei) in interplanetary space in the energy range from (for protons) approximately 0.5 MeV/nucleon  to
        approximately 100 MeV/nucleon with high resolution, extending to the order of 1 GeV with more basic low resolution measurements of flux  and/or intensity; and to study spatial gradients and the propagation of charged particles throughout the
        heliosphere by measuring absolute flux and vector anisotropy. COSPIN consists of a suite of five seperate instruments,
        each targeted at a distinct population of particles in the cosmic radiation.  All telescopes share a common power supply
        and interface to the spacecraft telemetry system through a common Data Processing Unit.  COSPIN consists of:
       
        Low Energy Telescope (LET): ~1-20 MeV/n P, He, and heavier nuclei using a dE/dx vs. E telescope with pha capability
       
        Anisotropy Telescopes (ATs): ~0.7-7 MeV/n P and He with telescopes oriented in two directions with respect to
        the spin axis to provide 3-dimensional anisotropy information
       
        High Flux Telescope (HFT): ~0.3-7 MeV protons, 0.4-4 MeV/n He with a small aperture single detector telescope for use in
        very high flux situations
       
        High Energy Telescope (HET): ~10-90 MeV/n P, He, and heavier nuclei with same range, and also ~3-10 MeV electrons using a large
        geometry factor high resolution dE/dx vs. E and trajectory determining telescope with pha capability optimized for studies of the chemical and isotopic abundances in the cosmic radiation
       
        Kiel Electron Telescope (KET): ~3-200 MeV electrons and ~3-2100 MeV/n protons and He using a Large dE/dx vs. E and cerenkov telescope
        with pha capability optimized for studies of high energy electrons, protons, and helium.
       

</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/R.Bruce.McKibben</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-090B&amp;ex=2</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cosmic Ray and Solar Particles (SIM/COSPIN) experiment on the Ulysses mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cosmic Ray and Solar Particles (SIM/COSPIN) on Ulysses</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Ulysses</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
