<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
	xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
	<Version>2.0.0</Version>
	<Repository>
		<ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NSSTC/POLAR.TIDE</ResourceID>
		<ResourceHeader>
			<ResourceName>NSSTC POLAR TIDE Repository</ResourceName>
			<ReleaseDate>2009-08-01T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
			<Description>
Polar TIDE Resident Archive web server and data archive located at the National Space Science and Technology Center (NSSTC) in 
Huntsville, Alabama..   There is a mirror site at GSFC, see spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/POLAR.TIDE
			</Description>
			<Contact>
				<PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.E.Moore</PersonID>
				<Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
			</Contact>
			<Contact>
				<PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.D.Craven</PersonID>
				<Role>GeneralContact</Role>
			</Contact>
			<Contact>
				<PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peggy.Sloan</PersonID>
				<Role>MetadataContact</Role>
			</Contact>
			<InformationURL>
				<Name>TIDE Home Page</Name>
				<URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/tide/</URL>
				<Description>
The Polar Thermal Ion Dynamics Experiment (TIDE) Home Page contains links to that allow users to view summary 
plots of the entire mission (View Summary Plots and View Thumbnails), analyze, plot, and dump data (Custom Plots 
and Data Dumps), download processing software and datafiles, plus links to mission operations, documentation, 
publications, data archives, and instrument description.    
				</Description>
			</InformationURL>
	  		<Association>
	  			<AssociationID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/POLAR.TIDE</AssociationID>
	  		</Association>
		</ResourceHeader>
		<AccessURL>
			<Name>TIDE Data Archive</Name>
			<URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/tide/archive/</URL>
			<Description>
The TIDE Data Archive contains all TIDE data and plot files.  They can most easily be accessed through the appropriate 
links on the TIDE website but they can be accessed directly.  See http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/tide/data_archive_desc.html 
for the location of the files used in the TIDE level-zero processing software (level-zero, orbit, attitude, mask, and 
spacecraft potential) and the location of the spectrogram summary plot files (gif, jpeg, and pdf).  The archive contains 
copies of the TIDE H1and H0 CDF files (also available at the CDAWeb).  Documentation, software, and miscellaneous
files are also kept on the archive. 
			</Description>
		</AccessURL>
	</Repository>
</Spase>
