<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_0.xsd">
 <Version>2.3.0</Version>
 <Instrument>
  <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ParkerSolarProbe/ISIS</ResourceID>
  <ResourceHeader>
   <ResourceName>ISIS</ResourceName>
   <AlternateName>Integrated Science Investigation of the Sun</AlternateName>
   <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
   <Description>
    The science objective of the Integrated Science Investigation of the Sun, ISIS,
    experiment is to explore the physical mechanisms that produce, accelerate, and
    transport energetic particles in the inner heliosphere. This will be achieved by
    observing energetic electrons, protons, and heavy ions in the Sun's
    atmosphere and inner heliosphere to learn about the origin and seed population
    of solar energetic particles, how these and other particles are accelerated, and
    what mechanisms are responsible for transporting the different particle
    populations into the heliosphere. It will also contribute to tracing the flow of
    energy that heats and accelerates the solar corona and solar wind, and
    determining the structure and dynamics of the plasma and magnetic fields at the
    sources of the solar wind. The Integrated Science Investigation of the Sun
    consists of two instruments, EPI-Lo and EPI-Hi, mounted on the side of the
    spacecraft near the back ram-facing side, protected by the heat shield.


    The EPI-Lo instrument is disc-shaped and divided into 8 sections, or wedge
    assemblies, each section holding 10 foil-covered apertures. Each aperture faces
    a slightly different direction, together they provide coverage of nearly a full
    hemisphere. The apertures allow particles to enter the wedge interior, which
    contains a time-of-flight mass spectrometer. Ions pass through the thin foils in
    the apertures and then hit a stop foil backed by a solid-state detector.
    Electrons are detected by independent solid-state detectors covered by ~2 micron
    thick aluminum flashing. Epi-Lo measures energetic ions from 0.02 MeV/n to 15
    MeV total energy, protons from about 0.04 MeV to 7 MeV, and energetic electrons
    from approximately 25 keV to 1000 keV. It measures the ion composition and
    pitch-angle distributions from 30 keV/n up to 0.3 MeV/n or 1.0 MeV/n every 5 or
    30 seconds. It can return data for up to 64 energy bins and 80 angular ranges
    (one for each aperture).

    The EPI-Hi instrument system is based on ion-implanted solid-state detectors. It
    comprises three detector stacks (particle telescopes). One is designated a High
    Energy Telescope (HET) and two are designated Low-Energy Telescopes (LET1 and
    LET2).

    The HET is a cylinder containing a central stack of detector disks and two
    single detector disks, one at each end. The individual detectors in the central
    stack have thicknesses of 1000 microns. Three of the detectors in the central
    stack comprise two 1000-micron disks connected to act as single 2000 micron
    detectors. The end detector disks are 500 microns thick. The front end detector
    and the outermost detectors at each end of the central stack are each divided
    into five active elements, a central bulls-eye and four quadrants, each of equal
    area. Which active area hit on different disks gives directional information on
    the particle. An outer annular segment of each detector acts as an
    anti-coincidence shield to detect particles that exit the cylinder before
    passing through all the detectors. The HET covers electrons up to approximately
    6 MeV and protons and heavy ions to at least 100 MeV/n. The lower range overlaps
    the high end of the Low Energy Telescopes.

    LET1 and LET2 are similar in design to the HET, cylinders containing a central
    stack of detector disks and positionally sensitive detectors at the ends. LET1
    has 1000-micron thick detector disks in the central stack, except for the end
    disks which are 500 microns. At the front of the cylinder, separate from the
    central stack, is a 12 micron thick disk and then a 25 micron disk. The back of
    the detector has the same arrangement. The front of the detector also has a thin
    window (~3 micron silicon equivalent). The 12, 25, and 500 micron thick disks
    are all separated into five active elements in the same way as the HET for
    positional determination. LET2 is similar to LET1 but does not have the end 12,
    25, and 500 micron disks. The Low-Energy Telescopes can measure protons and
    heavy ions from approximately 1 MeV to greater than 20 MeV/n and electrons from
    about 0.5 MeV to 2 MeV.
</Description>
   <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, NASA</Acknowledgement>
   <PublicationInfo>
    <Authors>D.J. McComas, N. Alexander, N. Angold, S. Bale, C. Beebe, B. Birdwell, M. Boyle, J.M. Burgum, J.A. Burnham, E.R. Christian, W.R. Cook, S.A. Cooper, A.C. Cummings, A.J. Davis, M.I. Desai, J. Dickinson, G. Dirks, D.H. Do, N. Fox, J. Giacalone, R.E. Gold, R.S. Gurnee, J.R. Hayes, M.E. Hill, J.C. Kasper, B. Kecman, J. Klemic, S.M. Krimigis, A.W. Labrador, R.S. Layman, R.A. Leske, S. Livi, W.H. Matthaeus, R.L. McNutt, Jr, R.A. Mewaldt, D.G. Mitchell, K.S. Nelson, C. Parker, J.S. Rankin, E.C. Roelof, N.A. Schwadron, H. Seifert, S. Shuman, M.R. Stokes, E.C. Stone, J.D. Vandegriff, M. Velli, T.T. von Rosenvinge, S.E. Weidner, M.E. Wiedenbeck, and P. Wilson, IV</Authors>
    <PublicationDate>2014-07-05T00:00:00</PublicationDate>
    <PublishedBy>Space Science Reviews</PublishedBy>
</PublicationInfo>
   <Funding>
    <Agency>National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Living With a Star, LWS, Program</Agency>
    <Project>Parker Solar Probe ISIS Investigation</Project>
    <AwardNumber>NNN06AA01C</AwardNumber>
</Funding>
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.J.McComas</PersonID>
    <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Eric.R.Christian</PersonID>
    <Role>DeputyPI</Role>
</Contact>
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID>
    <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
</Contact>
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
    <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
</Contact>
   <InformationURL>
    <Name>Parker Solar Probe Mission Instrument Web Page, JPL</Name>
    <URL>http://parkersolarprobe.jhuapl.edu/Spacecraft/index.php#Instruments</URL>
    <Description>Parker Solar Probe Mission Instrument Web Page, NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory, JPL</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
    <Name>Parker Solar Probe Mission Instrument Web Page, NASA</Name>
    <URL>https://www.nasa.gov/content/goddard/parker-solar-probe-instruments/</URL>
    <Description>Additional information on the Parker Solar Probe Instruments</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
    <Name>Parker Solar Probe ISIS Instrument Suite, NSSDC Master Catalog Listing</Name>
    <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2018-065A-02</URL>
    <Description>NSSDC Master Catalog Listing for the Parker Solar Probe Integrated Science Investigation of the Sun, ISIS, Instrument Suite, NSSDCA/COSPAR ID: 2018-065A-02</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
    <Name>Parker Solar Probe ISIS Instrument Suite Space Science Review Article</Name>
    <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs11214-014-0059-1</URL>
    <Description>Integrated Science Investigation of the Sun (ISIS): Design of the Energetic Particle Investigation. Space Sci Rev, 204(1-4), 187-256, 2016.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
  <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
  <InstrumentType>SolidStateDetector</InstrumentType>
  <InvestigationName>Parker Solar Probe ISIS Investigation</InvestigationName>
  <OperatingSpan>
   <StartDate>2018-08-12T07:31:00</StartDate>
   <Note>Parker Solar Probe Launch Date and Time until data are available</Note>
</OperatingSpan>
  <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ParkerSolarProbe</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
