<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/PROMICS3</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Ion Composition 3D Spectrometer (PROMICS-3)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>PROMICS-3 is a plasma experiment and performs three-dimensional measurements of ions in the energy range 4 eV to 70 keV with mass separation (M = 1 - 32), and of electrons in the energy range 12 eV to 35 keV. The instrument uses toroidal electrostatic analyzers. MEPS is the electron spectrometer, and TRICS is the ion mass spectrometer.
Interball Tail Probe and Interball Auroral Probe both carry identical PROMICS-3 instruments, thus facilitating direct comparisons of the particle distributions.
See the web page at http://www.irf.se/rpg/interball.html for further information.
PROMICS-3 Tail was one of the first instruments to measure the three-dimensional ion distribution function in the high latitude boundary layer regions of the magnetosphere.
The PROMICS-3 instrument was developed in cooperation between the Swedish Institute of Space Physics (IRF), the Finnish Meteorological Institute (FMI) and the Space Research Institute, Moscow (IKI). The major part of the hardware of PROMICS-3 was designed and built at IRF in Kiruna. Much of the electronics was built in Finland by FMI, Hollming OY, and VTT.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ingrid.Sandahl</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=8</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Ion Composition 3D Spectrometer (PROMICS-3) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Ion Composition 3D Spectrometer (PROMICS-3) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
