<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.2</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Galileo/PWS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Galileo PWS</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Galileo Plasma Wave Spectrometer</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Galileo Plasma Wave Subsystem</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Galileo Plasma Wave Investigation</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Galileo Plasma Wave Receiver</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>

The Galileo Plasma Wave Receiver is described by    


      Gurnett, D. A., W. S. Kurth, R. R. Shaw, A. Roux, R. Gendrin, C. F. Kennel,
    F. L. Scarf, and S. D. Shawhan, The Galileo Plasma Wave Investigation,
    Space Sci. Rev., 60, 341-355, 1992.
                         
                                                                             
Scientific Objectives:                                                       
                                                                             
The basic objective of this investigation is the study of plasma             
waves and radio emissions in the magnetosphere of Jupiter.  The              
Voyager 1 and 2 flybys of Jupiter have now clearly shown that many           
complex types of plasma wave and radio-emission phenomena occur in the       
Jovian magnetosphere.  These include electromagnetic whistler mode           
emissions called chorus and hiss, electromagnetic continuum radiation        
trapped in the magnetospheric cavity, electrostatic waves associated         
with harmonics of the electron cyclotron frequency, and a wide variety       
of escaping radio emissions.  Some of these waves, such as the whistler      
mode emissions, are believed to play an important role in the dynamics       
of the magnetosphere by controlling the pitch-angle scattering and loss      
of energetic charged particles.  In other cases plasma waves provide an      
important diagnostic tool by revealing various characteristic                
frequencies of the plasma, from which quantities such as the electron        
density can be computed.                                                     
                                                                             
Since the Galileo spacecraft will be the first orbiter of Jupiter,           
this spacecraft will provide a much more comprehensive study of the          
Jovian magnetosphere than was possible with the previous Pioneer and         
Voyager flybys of Jupiter.  Specifically, the orbit of Galileo will          
provide a survey of the magnetotail at distances of up to 150 RJ over a      
range of local times near local midnight, a region that has never            
previously been explored; repeated passes through the plasma sheet, and      
the tail lobes; and numerous close flybys of the Galilean satellites.        
Of particular importance will be a very close pass by the satellite Io.      
The Voyager flybys showed that volcanic gases escaping from this moon        
are the main source of plasma in the Jovian magnetosphere.  The primary      
energization of plasma in the Jovian magnetosphere is believed to occur      
in a dense plasma torus that surrounds Jupiter near Io's orbit.  This        
energization is associated with many complex plasma wave phenomena,          
including the generation of intense kilometric and decametric radio          
emissions.                                                                   
                                                                             
In addition to exploring regions never previously investigated,              
Galileo, by virtue of its long lifetime in orbit around Jupiter, also        
provides a unique new capability for carrying out studies of temporal        
variations on time scales that cannot be investigated with a single          
flyby.  For example, it is known that the kilometric and decametric          
radio emissions associated with Io and its plasma torus have temporal        
variations on time scales of weeks and longer. With Galileo these            
temporal variations can be monitored over periods of several years and       
compared with other remote sensing instruments. These measurements           
should be able to tell us, for example, whether the variations are           
associated with changes in the volcanoes on Io. Considerable interest        
also exists in searching for evidence of magnetospheric substorm             
phenomena, possibly comparable to auroral substorms in the Earth's           
magnetosphere.  With the Galileo plasma wave instrument, it should be        
possible to provide remote sensing of substorms in a manner comparable       
to the remote sensing of terrestrial auroral kilometric radiation,           
which is known to be closely associated with terrestrial substorms.          
                                                                             
To carry out comprehensive studies of plasma waves and radio                 
emissions at Jupiter, the Galileo plasma wave instrument incorporates        
several new features that provide improvements over the previous             
Voyager 1 and 2 measurements.  These improvements include (1) nearly         
simultaneous electric and magnetic field measurements to distinguish         
electrostatic waves from electromagnetic waves, (2) direction finding        
measurements to determine source locations, and (3) better frequency         
and time resolution to resolve fine structure in the plasma wave and         
radio emission spectrum.  The main instrument package and the electric       
dipole antenna system were designed and constructed at the University        
of Iowa, and the search coil magnetic antenna was provided by the            
Centre de Recherches en Physique de l'Environnement Terrestre et             
Planetaire (CRPE).                                                           
                                                                             
                                                                             
Calibration:                                                                 
                                                                             
                                                                             
An extensive series of calibrations and performance checks were              
performed on the plasma wave instrument both on and off the spacecraft.      
Since the logarithmic compressors used in the spectrum analyzers do          
not give a true logarithmic response, the transfer function of the           
logarithmic compressors must be calibrated.  Because of the large            
number of channels, it is not practical to calibrate each frequency          
channel separately.  Instead, the transfer function is measured for          
each logarithmic compressor, and a frequency response calibration is         
performed at a fixed amplitude for all channels using that compressor.       
This procedure provides accurate calibrations for each frequency step        
because each band of the receiver uses a single filter and logarithmic       
compressor.                                                                  
                                                                             
A look-up table can be constructed which converts the telemetry              
data number to input signal strength.  When combined with the overall        
frequency response across each band, these calibrations are sufficient       
to determine the signal strength in all channels served by this filter       
band and compressor.                                                         
                                                                             
In addition to the amplitude response of the compressors, a                  
frequency response is also performed for each frequency channel. All         
frequency channels are checked to confirm that the filter bands have         
the proper shape and no spurious responses.  The effective noise             
bandwidths are measured by stimulating the instrument with a white           
noise signal of known spectral density.                                      
                                                                             
For the electric field antenna, the electric field strength is               
computed by assuming that the antenna has an effective length of             
Leff = 3.5 meters. This length is the distance between the geometric         
centers of the two dipole elements.  For the search coil magnetic            
antennas, the magnetic field sensitivity and frequency response was          
calibrated in the IPG magnetic field observatory at Chambon La Foret,        
France.  These calibrations were performed using a Helmholtz coil            
driven by a known AC current source.  The absolute accuracy of the           
sensitivity calibration is estimated to be about 3 percent. The              
magnetic noise levels were measured by placing the search coils in a         
mu-metal chamber, which shields the sensors from external noise              
sources.                                                                     
                                                                             
                                                                             
Operational Considerations:                                                  
                                                                             
                                                                             
Nominally, the instrument is operated any time low rate science              
(LRS) or greater data rate capability is available.  When LRS is the         
maximum data rate, the instrument is operated in its power-up mode,          
with the SA and SFR toggling back and forth between the electric and         
magnetic antennas.  When wideband data can be recorded or transmitted        
to the Earth, then the wide range of instrument modes and antenna            
configurations are utilized based on the science objectives for a given      
time interval.  The UVS instrument has a stepper motor that drives its       
grating which is a major source of magnetic interference in the              
frequency range from about 100 Hz to 2 kHz.  Every attempt is made to        
work with the UVS team to minimize the times during which the grating        
is moved while PWS is observing on the magnetic antenna.  In many            
cases, this requires a time- sharing arrangement which allows for some       
percentage of magnetic viewing time in an interference-free                  
environment, but which also allows UVS to observe with a moving grating      
in order to achieve its science objectives.                                  
                                                                             
Detectors:                                                                   
                                                                             
                                                                             
The plasma wave sensors on Galileo consist of one 6.6 meter                  
tip-to-tip electric dipole antenna and two search coil magnetic              
antennas.  The electric dipole antenna is mounted at the end of the          
magnetometer boom approximately 10.6 meters from the spacecraft, and         
the search coil magnetic antennas are mounted on the high gain antenna       
feed.  The electric antenna consists of two graphite epoxy elements          
with a root diameter of 2.0 cm, tapering to 0.3 cm at the tip.  The          
dipole elements are mounted perpendicular to the magnetometer boom to        
minimize electric field distortion effects due to the spacecraft             
structure.  The antenna axis is also oriented perpendicular to the           
spacecraft spin axis in order to permit direction finding.  Each             
element is hinged 1.8 meters from the tip so that the antenna can be         
folded for launch.  A housing at the base of the dipole elements             
contains two preamplifiers.  These preamplifiers provide low impedance       
signals to the main electronics package. Each element is grounded to         
the spacecraft structure through a 250 MegOhm resistance to limit            
differential charging effects.                                               
                                                                             
The search coil magnetic antenna consists of two high permeability           
rods, 25.5 and 27.5 cm long, one optimized for low frequencies, 5 Hz to      
3.5 kHz, and the other optimized for high frequencies, 1 kHz to 50 kHz.      
The winding on the low frequency search coil consists of 50,000 turns of     
0.07 mm diameter copper wire and the winding on the high frequency           
search coil consists of 2000 turns of 0.14 mm diameter copper wire.          
The two search coils are mounted orthogonally to minimize the electrical     
coupling between the sensors.  Both search coils are mounted                 
perpendicular to the spacecraft spin axis.  The high frequency sensor is     
perpendicular to the electric dipole antenna and the low frequency           
sensor is parallel to the electric dipole antenna.  Two preamplifiers        
mounted in a housing near the search coil are used to provide low            
impedance signals to the main electronics package.  Frequencies below        
2.4 kHz are obtained from the low frequency search coil, and                 
frequencies above 2.4 kHz are obtained from the high frequency search        
coil.                                                                        
                                                                             
Electronics:                                                                 
                                                                             
All of the signal processing for the plasma wave experiment is               
performed in a single main electronics package.  The main electronics        
package is mounted in the spacecraft body near the base of the               
magnetometer boom. Signals from the electric dipole antenna and the two      
search coils are processed by a wideband receiver and three spectrum         
analyzers:  a high frequency spectrum analyzer also called the High          
Frequency Receiver (HFR), a medium frequency spectrum analyzer also          
called the Sweep Frequency Receiver (SFR), and a low frequency spectrum      
analyzer also called simply the Spectrum Analyzer (SA).  The HFR             
provides 42 frequencies from 100.8 kHz to 5.645 MHz with a fractional        
frequency spacing of delta-f/f ~ 10.0% and a bandwidth of 2 kHz.  One        
spectral sweep is provided every 18.67 seconds with a dynamic range of       
100 db.  The SFR provides 112 frequencies from 40 Hz to 160 kHz with a       
fractional frequency spacing of delta-f/f ~ 8.0%.  This analyzer gives       
one spectral sweep every 18.67 seconds with a dynamic range of 100 db.       
The low frequency SA provides 4 logarithmically spaced frequency             
channels from 5.62 Hz to 31.1 Hz.  All four channels are sampled once        
every 2.67 seconds with a dynamic range of 110 db.  The data from the        
HFR, SFR, and SA (and survey wideband data as described below) are           
transmitted to the ground via the low rate telemetry at a bit rate of        
240 bits/sec.                                                                
                                                                             
The wideband waveform receiver provides waveform measurements in             
three frequency bands, 5 Hz to 1 kHz, 50 Hz to 10 kHz, and 50 Hz             
to 80 kHz.  The frequency band to be used is controlled by the               
spacecraft Command and Data Subsystem (CDS).  An automatic gain control      
(AGC) circuit is used to control the amplitude of the output waveform.       
The AGC time constant is 0.1 seconds in the two high frequency bands         
and 1.0 second in the low frequency band.  The waveform from the             
wideband receiver is digitized by a 4-bit analog-to-digital converter        
(ADC).  The sample rate of the ADC is fixed at either 3,150, 25,200, or      
201,600 samples per second, depending on the frequency band selected.        
The waveform data can be transmitted in real time or recorded on the         
spacecraft digital tape recorder.                                            
                                                                             
The plasma wave instrument has several modes of operation and                
methods of data transmission.  These modes are also controlled by            
the spacecraft CDS. The medium and low frequency spectrum analyzers and      
the wideband waveform receiver can be connected to either the electric       
dipole antenna or the search coil magnetic antennas.  In the normal          
mode of operation, the SFR and SA are cycled between the electric and        
magnetic antennas so that alternate electric and magnetic spectrums are      
obtained.  Since the search coils do not provide signals in the              
frequency range covered by the HFR, this analyzer is always connected        
to the electric antenna.  In the cycling mode of operation, the time         
required for a complete set of electric and magnetic field spectrums is      
37.33 seconds.  The SFR and SA can also be locked on either the              
electric or magnetic antennas to provide improved time resolution at         
the expense of complementary electric and magnetic field coverage.  In       
all cases the HFR, SFR, and SA outputs consist of an 8-bit binary            
numbers that are approximately proportional to the logarithm of the          
received signal strength.  In the ground data processing the data from       
the HFR, SFR, and SA will be displayed in the form of color                  
frequency-time spectrograms.  The frequency scale of the Galileo             
spectrograms will extend from 5.6 Hz to 5.65 MHz, and variable time          
scales will be available, ranging from 30 minutes to more than 24            
hours, depending on the application.  Normally, 24-hour spectrograms         
will be used to survey the plasma wave data.  These survey spectrograms      
will be used to select specific intervals for more detailed analysis,        
such as comparison with charged particle or magnetic field data, or          
direction-finding analyses.                                                  
                                                                             
The greatest flexibility in the operation of the plasma wave                 
instrument is available in the wideband waveform receiver.  This             
receiver provides very high resolution measurements of electric and          
magnetic field waveforms during times of special interest, such as the       
pass through the Io torus and satellite encounters.  The waveform data       
provide the highest possible frequency and time resolution, subject          
only to the constraints of Fourier analysis, delta-f*delta-t ~ 1.            
Although the waveform receiver has only three frequency bands, with bit      
rates of 12.6, 100.8, and 806.4 kbits/sec, several spacecraft modes are      
available for recording and transmitting the data to the ground.  In         
the highest time resolution mode, an essentially continuous sample of        
the electric or magnetic field waveform can be obtained over a               
bandwidth of 50 Hz to 80 kHz for periods of up to 18 minutes (the time       
required to fill the spacecraft tape recorder).                              
                                                                             
On the ground the waveform data will be Fourier transformed in               
discrete packets, usually consisting of 1024 samples, and                    
displayed in the form of a frequency-time spectrogram.  These                
frequency-time spectrograms provide the highest time resolution data         
available from the Galileo plasma wave instrument.  In certain modes of      
operation, such as MPW, XPW, and PW4, the duration of the wideband           
recording can be extended at the expense of reduced duty cycle,              
frequency coverage, or analysis bandwidth.  To provide some wideband         
telemetry even when the high rate telemetry link is not available, a         
waveform survey output is included in the regular low rate telemetry         
data. This waveform survey output provides one block of 280 waveform         
samples every 18.67 seconds in two frequency bands, 5 Hz to 1 kHz and        
50 Hz to 10 kHz.                                                             
                                                                             
Filters:                                                                     
                                                                             
The following three tables describe the 158 frequency channels               
which make up the low rate science portion of the Galileo PWS.               
                                                                             
Table 1.  Spectrum Analyzer (SA) Channels                                    
                                                                             
Channel   MOD(mf,4) Center Frequency (Hz)    Bandwidth (Hz)                  
1         0 (4)           5.62               0.832                           
2         3              10.0                1.86                            
3         2              17.8                2.75                            
4         1              31.1                4.79                            
                                                                             
mf is the minor frame counted from 1 through 28.                             
                                                                             
                                                                             
Table 2.  Sweep Frequency Receiver (SFR) Channels                            
                                                                             
Chan mf        Freq. (Hz)     Bandwidth (Hz)                                 
                                                                             
Band 1                                                                       
1     1       42.1             4.26                                          
2     2       45.6                                                           
3     3       49.0                                                           
4     4       52.5                                                           
5     5       56.0                                                           
6     6       59.6                                                           
7     7       66.7                                                           
8     8       70.4                                                           
9     9       77.7                                                           
10    10      81.5                                                           
11    11      89.0                                                           
12    12      96.7                                                           
13    13     104.5                                                           
14    14     112.5                                                           
15    15     120.6                                                           
16    16     128.9                                                           
17    17     137.3                                                           
18    18     150.2                                                           
19    19     158.9                                                           
20    20     172.5                                                           
21    21     186.4                                                           
22    22     200.7                                                           
23    23     215.5                                                           
24    24     235.9                                                           
25    25     251.7                                                           
26    26     268.0                                                           
27    27     290.6                                                           
28    28     314.1                                                           
                                                                             
Band 2                                                                       
29    1      337.              6.76                                          
30    2      364.                                                            
31    3      392.                                                            
32    4      420.                                                            
33    5      448.                                                            
34    6      476.                                                            
35    7      534.                                                            
36    8      563.                                                            
37    9      622.                                                            
38    10     652.                                                            
39    11     712.                                                            
40    12     774.                                                            
41    13     836.                                                            
42    14     900.                                                            
43    15     965.                                                            
44    16       1.031k                                                        
45    17       1.098k                                                        
46    18       1.201k                                                        
47    19       1.272k                                                        
48    20       1.380k                                                        
49    21       1.491k                                                        
50    22       1.606k                                                        
51    23       1.724k                                                        
52    24       1.887k                                                        
53    25       2.013k                                                        
54    26       2.144k                                                        
55    27       2.325k                                                        
56    28       2.513k                                                        
                                                                             
Band 3                                                                       
57    1        2.70k           120.                                          
58    2        2.91k                                                         
59    3        3.14k                                                         
60    4        3.36k                                                         
61    5        3.58k                                                         
62    6        3.81k                                                         
63    7        4.27k                                                         
64    8        4.50k                                                         
65    9        4.98k                                                         
66    10       5.21k                                                         
67    11       5.70k                                                         
68    12       6.19k                                                         
69    13       6.69k                                                         
70    14       7.20k                                                         
71    15       7.72k                                                         
72    16       8.25k                                                         
73    17       8.78k                                                         
74    18       9.61k                                                         
75    19      10.17k                                                         
76    20      11.04k                                                         
77    21      11.93k                                                         
78    22      12.85k                                                         
79    23      13.79k                                                         
80    24      15.09k                                                         
81    25      16.11k                                                         
82    26      17.15k                                                         
83    27      18.59k                                                         
84    28      20.10k                                                         
                                                                             
Band 4                                                                       
85    1       21.6k            1520.                                         
86    2       23.3k                                                          
87    3       25.1k                                                          
88    4       26.9k                                                          
89    5       28.7k                                                          
90    6       30.5k                                                          
91    7       34.2k                                                          
92    8       36.0k                                                          
93    9       39.8k                                                          
94    10      41.7k                                                          
95    11      45.6k                                                          
96    12      49.5k                                                          
97    13      53.5k                                                          
98    14      57.6k                                                          
99    15      61.7k                                                          
100   16      66.0k                                                          
101   17      70.3k                                                          
102   18      76.9k                                                          
103   19      81.4k                                                          
104   20      88.3k                                                          
105   21      95.4k                                                          
106   22     102.8k                                                          
107   23     110.3k                                                          
108   24     120.7k                                                          
109   25     128.9k                                                          
110   26     137.2k                                                          
111   27     148.8k                                                          
112   28     160.8k                                                          
(Note that the same bandwidth applies to the entire set of channels in       
band.)                                                                       
                                                                             
                                                                             
Table 3.  High Frequency Receiver (HFR) Channels                             
                                                                             
HFR                  Center Frequency                                        
Channel    mf             (MHz)                                              
1          1, 2          0.1008                                              
2          5, 6          0.1134                                              
3          9, 10         0.1260                                              
4          13, 14        0.1386                                              
5          17, 18        0.1512                                              
6          21, 22        0.1638                                              
7          25, 26        0.1764                                              
8          3, 4          0.2016                                              
9          7, 8          0.2268                                              
10         1, 12         0.2520                                              
11         5, 16         0.2772                                              
12         9, 20         0.3024                                              
13         3, 24         0.3276                                              
14         7, 28         0.3528                                              
15         1             0.4032                                              
16         5             0.4536                                              
17         9             0.5040                                              
18         13            0.5544                                              
19         17            0.6048                                              
20         21            0.6552                                              
21         25            0.7056                                              
22         2             0.8060                                              
23         6             0.9070                                              
24         10            1.008                                               
25         14            1.109                                               
26         18            1.210                                               
27         22            1.310                                               
28         26            1.411                                               
29         3             1.613                                               
30         7             1.814                                               
31         11            2.016                                               
32         15            2.218                                               
33         19            2.419                                               
34         23            2.621                                               
35         27            2.822                                               
36         4             3.226                                               
37         8             3.629                                               
38         12            4.032                                               
39         16            4.435                                               
40         20            4.838                                               
41         24            5.242                                               
42         28            5.645                                               
(The bandwidth for all channels is 1340 Hz)                                  
                                                                             
Mounting Offsets:                                                            
                                                                             
The electric antenna is mounted at the end of the magnetometer               
boom such that its effective axis is parallel to the spacecraft X            
axis (perpendicular to both the magnetometer boom and the spacecraft         
spin axis.  The low frequency magnetic search coil is mounted with its       
effective axis parallel to the spacecraft X axis and the high frequency      
search coil is parallel to the spacecraft Y axis (perpendicular to the       
X axis and to the spacecraft spin axis.                                      
                                                                             
Field of View:                                                               
                                                                             
The field of view of the PWS, whether from the electric dipole               
antenna or one of the magnetic search coils is a standard dipole             
antenna pattern which has a maximum sensitivity to the field along the       
axis of the sensor.  For radio waves which propagate above the               
characteristic frequencies of the plasma and which do not interact with      
the local plasma, this means maximum sensitivity is to sources in a          
plane perpendicular to the antenna axis, since the electric and              
magnetic fields of a radio wave are normally perpendicular to the            
propagation vector.                                                          
                                                                             
Data Rates:                                                                  
                                                                             
The basic low rate science (LRS) data rate of the instrument is              
240 bps. Wideband waveform receiver data rates range from 19.2               
kbps to 806.4 kbps, depending on the telemetry mode.  Rates of 94._          
kbps and lower can be either recorded on the spacecraft tape recorder        
or transmitted directly to the ground; rates of 403.2 and 806.4 kbps         
can only be recorded onboard for later playback at lower rates.              
                                                                             
Instrument Modes:                                                            
                                                                             
The PWS has several modes of operation.  The SA and SFR can either           
monitor only the electric antenna, only the magnetic antenna, or toggle      
back and forth between the two, obtaining a complete spectral scan from      
each antenna before switching to the other.  This toggling mode is the       
most commonly utilized mode.  There is also a mode which enables the         
magnetic search coil calibration tone.  When enabled, the calibration        
signal is excited for 56 mf (37.33 sec) at the beginning of each             
MOD(RIM,8)=0 until disabled.                                                 
                                                                             
The wideband receiver has three basic modes (analysis bandwidths)            
and can be attached to either the electric antenna or the magnetic.          
The three modes provide analysis bandwidths of 10 kHz, 80 kHz, and           
1 kHz although there is an additional mode which toggles between the         
10 kHz and 1 kHz mode.  In this mode, the waveform data is collected         
for 14 mf (9.33 sec) in one bandwidth and then for 14 mf in the other        
bandwidth.                                                                   
                                                                             
A wide range of telemetry formats are available for the wideband             
data. For any one of the three wideband modes, the instantaneous             
data rate is fixed (806.4 kbps for the 80 kHz mode, 100.8 kbps for the       
10 kHz mode, and 12.6 kbps for the 1 kHz mode.  However, the different       
telemetry modes differ primarily in the number of consecutive samples        
collected during an RTI.  This results in a variation in the duty cycle      
depending on the data rate allocated to this data stream in the              
selected telemetry mode.                                                     
                                                                             
Phase 2 Software Implications:                                               
                                                                             
In response to the failure of the high gain antenna and the                  
resulting reduction in downlink telecommunications capabilities for the      
Galileo spacecraft, the Galileo Project undertook a massive                  
re-programming of onboard software in order to enable science                
observations in Jupiter orbit.  Coupled with flight software changes,        
modifications to the Deep Space Network were also undertaken to improve      
the overall downlink capability from the spacecraft.  Together, these        
actions increased the actual bit-to-ground capability from a maximum of      
about 10 bps to a maximum of 160 bps.  In addition, onboard data             
compression was implemented which increased the information content of       
the downlink by roughly a factor of 10.                                      
                                                                             
The PWS instrument has no microprocessor; all of its functions               
are hardwired, hence, no reprogramming of the instrument itself was          
possible.  One result of this is that the basic timing of the                
instrument is identical to that described in the section above.              
However, significant software additions in the CDS and AACS were             
implemented which enable the PWS to perform its basic observations at        
dramatically lower data rates.  These changes can be categorized simply      
as editing and compression. The LRS observations are edited as               
described below to reduce the observations retained for downlink from        
240 bps to 65 bps.  The remaining 65 bps LRS data stream is then             
compressed using the same integer cosine transform (ICT) algorithm as        
used for the Solid State Imaging (SSI) data.  The severity of this           
compression is variable and can range from 40 bps to 5 bps, with 5 bps       
being the most often utilized data rate. The wideband data are not           
compressed and are minimized through editing functions only.  In             
addition, a new wideband telemetry mode was developed which uses bit         
allocations in the original LRS telemetry frame originally reserved for      
Golay encoding to produce a mode with drastically reduced data rate          
requirements.                                                                
                                                                             
Realtime Science                                                             
                                                                             
LRS Editing and Compression:  The original PWS LRS data                      
stream is edited to reduce the data rate before compression from 240         
bps to 65 bps.  First, the 120 bits of waveform survey data are edited       
out of the data stream.  Second, all housekeeping and status                 
information is removed; if one assumes that the sequenced commands are       
executed properly and the instrument timing is maintained, the status        
of the instrument can be unambiguously determined from the most recent       
mode command and the current spacecraft clock.  A recorded mode like         
the original LRS but now called LPW preserves the full, original PWS         
LRS data stream and can be used to compare realtime science with the         
full data steam at limited times in case questions arise about the           
assumptions of correct command execution or instrument timing.  Third,       
only one sample per channel is preserved in a given 18.67-second             
instrument cycle.  Accordingly, only the first sample of the four SA         
channels are retained and only the first sample of the lower frequency       
HFR channels are retained.  Further, since there is an overlap between       
the upper frequency range of Band 4 of the MFR with the lower range          
of the HFR, and since the HFR has better sensitivity over this range,        
the highest frequency 6 channels of MFR band 4 are edited out.  What         
remains is a single sample of each of 152 of the original 158 channels       
in the low rate portion of the instrument.  This is the data stream          
which is forwarded to the AACS for ICT compression.                          
                                                                             
The ICT compression works on 8x8 pixel blocks of an image.                   
Since The PWS dynamic spectrogram can be thought of as an                    
image, the compression algorithm can be used to compress the                 
spectrogram prior to transmission to the ground.  One complication is        
that the PWS generally alternates between a magnetic and electric            
spectrum (at least for the SA and MFR channels) and the resulting            
alternating spectra add entropy to the 'image' and thereby reduce the        
compressibility of the data set.  Therefore, the electric and magnetic       
spectra are separated or 'unzipped' prior to compression.  Also, it is       
necessary to build up 8x8 blocks of the spectrogram.  152 channels can       
be broken into 19 8-channel segments, hence, 8 electric and 8 magnetic       
spectra are accumulated in order to make an 8x152 pixel strip (19 8x8        
blocks) of electric field data and a similar strip for the magnetic          
data.  (Note that the electric HFR data is included with the magnetic        
strip so that the 18.67-sec samples of the HFR channels are preserved.)      
 Hence, data is collected on 16 x 18.67 second time intervals (about 5       
minutes) in order to build the two 8x152 pixel strips.  Each of the          
strips is compressed individually with all 19 8x8 blocks in each being       
used to generate a downlink packet.  Since transmission errors will          
make decompression impossible for all data following the error, a            
5-minute gap will appear for any packet with a telemetry error.              
Fortunately, telemetry errors are very infrequent and the data which         
reaches the ground intact is virtually immune from the spikes typical        
of bursty bit errors in an uncompressed telemetry stream.                    
                                                                             
Once on the ground, the electric and magnetic strips are                     
decompressed and 'zipped' back together in the original time order.          
This allows sequential electric (or magnetic) spectra to be maintained       
together in the event the instrument is not cycled between E and B           
sweeps. The net result of this compression/decompression scheme is that      
the full temporal and spectral resolution of the PWS instrument is           
maintained even though the real data rate to the ground is as low as 5       
bps.  Of course, as in any lossy compression scheme, information is          
lost.  By maintaining the spectral and temporal resolution, the loss in      
the resulting data set is in amplitude inaccuracy.  Based on both            
ground experimentation and analysis of the Jupiter data, we believe the      
amplitude errors at 5 bps are no more than about 6 dB and are much less      
at the higher data rates (less severe compression).  At 5 bps these          
amplitude errors appear as 'tiling' in which all pixels in a given 8x8       
block have similar values but are different from adjoining 8x8 blocks        
or else the 8x8 blocks take on a checkerboard appearance.  The errors        
do not appear to be systematic, hence, we believe that averaging pixels      
in frequency and time over regions of the spectrogram where the              
spectrum appears to be 'simple' could provide a better estimate of the       
true signal strength.  Generally, however, the 5 dB accuracy will            
enable a wide range of studies without need to know the absolute             
amplitude better than a few dB.                                              
                                                                             
Recorded Data                                                                
                                                                             
LRS data:  When PWS data are recorded, the full LRS data stream              
is recorded and played back.  This includes all status bits,                 
additional samples of multiply-sampled channels (e.g. SA channels), and      
the waveform survey data.  The discussion of data in the original            
instrument description is fully applicable in this case.                     
                                                                             
Wideband data:  The wideband data suffered the most through the              
process of reducing the downlink requirements.  Nevertheless, a minimal      
wideband capability was retained.  Beginning with the Io flyby, a new        
data mode was introduced which replace the Golay encoding bits formerly      
used for the LRS data format with PWS wideband data in the LPW format.       
This mode is called LPW and is usually modified with the term Golay          
bits to distinguish these data from the low rate data.  All three of         
the bandwidths (wideband modes) can be used with the LPW format and for      
each, a total of 832(????) contiguous 4-bit samples are acquired.            
However, these 832 samples are recorded only once per 2 minor frames,        
or 2.67 seconds, hence, the best spectral temporal resolution (temporal      
resolution of Fourier transforms assuming 1 transform per set of             
contiguous samples) is 2.67 seconds.  The spectral resolution (416           
spectral components is very competitive with the HPW (94._ kbps mode)        
but the temporal resolution is poorer by a factor of about 50.  It           
is this mode, however, which is used for virtually all of the orbital        
tour recording.                                                              
                                                                             
Some of the original wideband telemetry modes were eliminated                
and those which remain (in addition to the LPW/Golay bits) are MPW,          
MPP, and HPW.  These provide 7.68, 19.2, and 94._ kbps, respectively.        
In practice, the LPW/Golay bits provides superior spectral resolution        
over the MPW mode at significantly reduced bit rate (due to the              
poor temporal resolution) and the MPW mode is not utilized in the            
tour.  Limited use of the MPP and HPW modes is included in the tour          
data set, however.                                                           
                                                                             
For all the wideband telemetry modes, an additional capability               
for reducing the downlink requirements was implemented.  This is             
an editing function often referred to as '1 of n-line editing' and           
consists of returning 1 of every n sets of contiguous samples recorded.      
Most of the tour data were returned with n = 2 or n = 4 so that              
the temporal resolution of the Fourier transformed spectra are a factor      
of 2 or 4 poorer than the original recorded data.  For example, in           
the LPW/Golay bits mode, if n = 2, the time between returned spectra         
is not 2.67 seconds, but 5.33 seconds.  Reducing the number of samples       
in a contiguous set of samples by returning every nth sample was             
never considered because this would under sample the waveform and            
lead to aliasing problems.  Likewise, truncating the number of               
samples in a set would reduce the spectral resolution, thereby               
defeating the remaining attribute of the wideband data."                     


</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.S.Kurth</PersonID>
                <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Instrument home page at The University of Iowa</Name>
        <URL>http://www-pw.physics.uiowa.edu/galileo/</URL>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Experiment Details at the National Space Science Data Center (NSSDC)</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1989-084B-07</URL>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>SearchCoil</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma Wave Spectrometer</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Galileo</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
