<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
  <Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version> 
  <Observatory>
	  <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Ground/IMAGE</ResourceID> 
		  <ResourceHeader>
		  <ResourceName>International Monitor for Auroral Geomagnetic Effects</ResourceName> 
		  <AlternateName>IMAGE</AlternateName>
		  <ReleaseDate>2019-04-24T12:34:56.789Z</ReleaseDate> 
		  <Description>IMAGE consists of 41 magnetometer stations maintained by 10 institutes 
		  from Estonia, Finland, Germany, Norway, Poland, Russia and Sweden. The prime objectives 
		  of IMAGE are to study auroral electrojets and moving two-dimensional current 
		  systems. The long profile covering geographic latitudes from 51 to 79 degrees 
		  is especially favourable for electrojet studies. Together with other ground-based 
		  recordings (by radars, riometers, all-sky cameras) and satellite observations, 
		  IMAGE is an essential part in the investigations of high-latitude 
		  magnetospheric-ionospheric physics. Together with its predecessor, the EISCAT 
		  magnetometer cross started in 1982, IMAGE also provides high-quality data useful 
		  for studies of geomagnetic induction and long-term geomagnetic activity in the 
		  auroral region. </Description> 
		  <Acknowledgement>Finnish Meterological Institute (FMI); 
		  Polar Geophysical Institute (PGI); Swedish Institute for Space Physics (IRF);
		  Helmholtz Center Potsdam, German Research Centre for Geosciences;
		  Institute for Geophysics, Polish Academy of Sciences; Geological Survey Sweden; 
		  University of Oulu; University of Tromso; Technical University of Braunschweig;
		  Adolf-Schmidt Observatory</Acknowledgement>
		   <Contact>
			  <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Liisa.Juusola</PersonID> 
			  <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role> 
		   </Contact> 
		   <Contact>
			  <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID> 
			  <Role>MetadataContact</Role> 
		  </Contact> 
		  <InformationURL>
			  <Name>International Monitor for Auroral Geomagnetic Effects Homepage</Name> 
			  <URL>http://space.fmi.fi/image/www/index.php?page=home</URL> 
			  <Description>About the IMAGE program.</Description> 
		  </InformationURL>
		</ResourceHeader>  
		<Location>
		  <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface.AuroralRegion</ObservatoryRegion> 
		  <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservatoryRegion> 
		  <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion> 
		</Location>
  </Observatory>
  </Spase>