<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/6</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GOES 6</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1983-041A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>GOES-F</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>GOES 6 was the eighth in a series of NASA-developed, NOAA-operated, geosynchronous,
   and operational spacecraft. The spin-stabilized spacecraft carried (1) a visible infrared spin-scan
   radiometer (VISSR) atmospheric sounder (VAS) to provide high-quality day/night cloudcover data,
   to take radiance-derived temperatures of the earth/atmosphere system, and to determine atmospheric
   temperature and water vapor content at various levels, (2) a meteorological data collection
   system to relay processed data from central weather facilities to regional stations equipped
   with APT and to collect and retransmit data from remotely located earth-based platforms, and (3)
   a space environment monitor (SEM) system to measure proton, electron, and solar X-ray fluxes and
   magnetic fields. The cylindrically shaped spacecraft measured 190.5 cm in diameter and 230 cm in
   length, exclusive of a magnetometer that extended an additional 83 cm beyond the cylindrical
   shell. The primary structural members were a honeycombed equipment shelf and a thrust tube. The
   VISSR telescope, which was mounted on the equipment shelf, viewed the earth through a special
   aperture in the side of the spacecraft. A support structure extended radially from the thrust tube
   and was affixed to the solar panels, which formed the outer wall of the spacecraft to provide
   the primary source of electrical power. Located in the annulus-shaped space between the thrust
   tube and the solar panels were stationkeeping and dynamics control equipment, batteries, and most
   of the SEM equipment. Proper spacecraft attitude and spin rate (approximately 100 rpm) were
   maintained by two separate sets of jet thrusters mounted around the spacecraft equator and activated
   by ground command. The spacecraft used both UHF-band and S-band frequencies in its telemetry
   and command subsystem. A low-power VHF transponder provided telemetry and command during launch
   and then served as a backup for the primary subsystem once the spacecraft attained synchronous
   orbit. GOES 6 was moved from its 135 deg W position to a more central 98 deg W position when GOES
   5 failed on July 29, 1984. It was turned off on November 12, 1994.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.E.Shenk</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1983-041A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the GOES  6 mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Earth Observation Resources Webpage on GOES</Name>
        <URL>https://earth.esa.int/web/eoportal/satellite-missions/g/goes-2nd-generation</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about GOES Series.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES6</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
 <OperatingSpan>
   <StartDate>1983-04-28T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
   <StopDate>1989-01-21T23:59:59</StopDate>
   <Note>Useful operating span.</Note>
</OperatingSpan>
</Observatory>
</Spase>
