<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/7</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GOES 7</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1987-022A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>GOES-H</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>PEACESAT</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>GOES 7 was the tenth in a series of NASA-developed, NOAA-operated, geosynchronous and
   operational spacecraft. The spin-stabilized spacecraft carried (1) a visible infrared spin-scan
   radiometer (VISSR) atmospheric sounder (VAS) to provide high-quality day/night cloudcover data,
   to take radiance derived temperatures of the earth/atmosphere system, and to determine atmospheric
   temperature and water vapor content at various levels, (2) a meteorological data collection system
   to relay processed data from central weather facilities to regional stations equipped with APT and
   to collect and retransmit data from remotely located earth-based platforms, and (3) a space
   environment monitor (SEM) system to measure proton, electron, and solar X-ray fluxes and magnetic
   fields. The cylindrically shaped spacecraft measured 190.5 cm in diameter and 230 cm in length,
   exclusive of a magnetometer that extended an additional 83 cm beyond the cylindrical shell.
   The primary structural members were a honeycombed equipment shelf and a thrust tube. The VISSR
   telescope was mounted on the equipment shelf and viewed the earth through a special aperture in
   the side of the spacecraft. A support structure extended radially from the thrust tube and was
   affixed to the solar panels, which formed the outer wall of the spacecraft to provide the primary
   source of electrical power. Located in the annulus-shaped space between the thrust tube and the
   solar panels were stationkeeping and dynamics control equipment, batteries, and most of the SEM
   equipment. Proper spacecraft attitude and spin rate (approximately 100 rpm) were maintained by
   two separate sets of jet thrusters mounted around the spacecraft equator and activated by ground
   command. The spacecraft used both UHF-band and S-band frequencies in its telemetry and command
   subsystem. A low-power VHF transponder provided telemetry and command during launch and then
   served as a backup for the primary subsystem once the spacecraft attains synchronous orbit.

      August 1999

      NASA's 12-year-old Geostationary Observational Environmental Satellite, GOES-7, is being
   relocated to a position over the Pacific Ocean southwest of Hawaii to become part of PEACESAT,
   the Pan Pacific Education and Communications Experiment by Satellite. More information on this
   story can be found at:

      http://pao.gsfc.nasa.gov/gsfc/gnews/062599/062599.htm#goes7</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.E.Shenk</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1987-022A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the GOES  7 mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Earth Observation Resources Webpage on GOES</Name>
        <URL>https://earth.esa.int/web/eoportal/satellite-missions/g/goes-2nd-generation</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about GOES Series.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES7</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
 <OperatingSpan>
   <StartDate>1987-02-26T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
   <StopDate>1996-08-13T08:30:00</StopDate>
   <Note>Useful operating span.</Note>
</OperatingSpan>
</Observatory>
</Spase>
