<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/IMS-LO</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Low Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer (IMS-LO) was designed to measure the energy and mass spectra in the energy/Q range 0.1 - 32 keV/Q and in the mass range 1.0 - 32 amu/Q. The design was very similar to the spectrometers of the Lockheed group on board the SCATHA and S3-3 satellites. Two identical instruments, IMS-LO-1 and IMS-LO-2 were used: one looking at 45 deg and the other at 75 deg with respect to the spin axis of the satellite. The field of view was 5 deg, conical. Each IMS was actually a triplet of spectrometers, covering the three ranges, 0.1 - 0.6 keV/Q, 0.7 - 4.5 keV/Q, and 5 - 32 keV/Q. In turn, each energy range was covered by 15 discrete energy steps, with a duration of 2.084 s at each step. Each of the 6 (3 x 2) spectrometers consisted of a Wein velocity filter, followed by an electrostatic energy analyzer (EEA) and then by a channel multiplier. The geometric factor at any energy was about 4.E-4 sq cm-sr. At each energy step, the velocity filter sequentially sampled for 2.084 s the masses in 32 mass steps. The instruments could also be operated in a LOCK submode, in which the mass was held fixed and the range of 0.1 - 32 keV/Q was swept in steps during a total duration of 1.024 s. The two IMS-LO systems could be independently commanded to operate in the SWEEP or the LOCK submode. Four fixed-energy electron detectors were attached to each IMS-LO system, and together the eight electron detectors covered the energy range 50 eV - 25 keV, in 512 ms.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.R.Vondrak</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=22</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
