<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/RPD</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Relativistic Proton Detector</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment package was changed before launch and then became a group of Cerenkov and solid-state silicon sensors based on earlier Pioneer 10/11 experiments (NSSDC ID 72-012A-05 and 73-019A-05). It was designed to measure energetic electrons above 200 keV and higher energy electrons and protons in trapped radiation belts. The two Cerenkov sensors employed alcohol-water and fused-silica radiators, viewed by photomultiplier tubes, with respective refractive indices of 4/3 and 3/2 and with corresponding proton energy thresholds of 440 and 320 MeV. These sensors were also sensitive to electrons above 7-8 MeV. An electron scatter sensor measured electrons above 200 keV by using a V-shaped brass collimator and a gold aperture plug to guide scattered electrons into the silicon E detector. A similar detector (M) behind E was heavily shielded and responded to penetrating electrons above 35 MeV and protons above 80 MeV. A photometer system was also included in this package to view GTO chemical releases and measured narrow-band emissions from lithium, barium, and europium in four wavelength channels simultaneously using a split-anode microchannel plate photomultiplier tube. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Wojciech.A.Kolasinski</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=13</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Relativistic Proton Detector experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Relativistic Proton Detector on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
