<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" 
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.2</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ground/MaunaLoaSO/CHIP</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>MLSO_ACOS_CHIP</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>CHP</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>CHIP</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2015-10-23T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Chromospheric Helium-I Imaging Photometer (CHIP) 
was installed at MLSO in April 1996. CHIP is a differential device using 
properties of the Helium-I line at 1083 nm as an indicator of both 
chromospheric and coronal structures. CHIP records images of the sun at 
1083 nm, as well as at a number of other nearby wavelengths (for 
calibration purposes). It is basically composed of a liquid crystal 
variable retarder (tuneable) Lyot filter connected to an IR CCD.
CHIP is unique compared with other Helium-I imagers, in that it obtains 
images every 3 minutes, the high cadence crucial to study the rapid 
evolution of CMEs. In addition, observations from CHIP should provide 
better understanding of coronal holes, coronal arcades, and the 
interaction between open and closed magnetic field structures.
Seven line and continuum exposures are recorded within 2 seconds. The 
difference of line and one continuum exposures is computed every 3 minutes 
to produce one 1083 nm image.
The CHIP FOV is approximately 1.8 solar radii. The CCD pixel size is 
2.29 arcseconds and the measured spatial resolution is ~8 arcseconds. 
For additional information on the tuneable filter see Kopp et al. 
(1996).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.E.Holzer</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MaunaLoaSO/CHIP</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>Photometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>ACOS/CHIP at MLSO</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Ground/MaunaLoaSO</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>