<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" 
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.2</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ground/MaunaLoaSO/MK4</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>MLSO_ACOS_MK4</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2015-10-23T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Mark-III instrument was the third generation white 
light K-coronameter instrument at MLSO, and it operated from 4 February, 
1980, through 30 September, 1999.  The field of view of the Mark-III 
K-Coronameter (Mk3) was 1.122 to 2.44 solar radii (as measured from sun 
center). The sun's corona was scanned by a linear array detection system 
which is rotated in solar position angle about the center of the solar disk. 
It took about three minutes to acquire one coronal image.
The Mark-III K-Coronameter data are scaled such that 104.4 pixels 
corresponds to one solar radius. Spatial sampling is 10 arcseconds 
radially by 0.5 degrees in azimuth. All data are rotated so that solar 
north is oriented straight up; solar north is known to within three degrees. 
Daily averaged images and mass ejection images from the K-Coronameter have 
instrumental `vignetting' left in the data to offset the coronal radial 
density gradient, allowing for better viewing of the corona. Calibrated 
images in units of polarization brightness (pB) are available and may be 
requested via the E-mail address listed above.
The Mark-IV K-coronameter, was constructed by HAO in collaboration with 
Rhodes College (Memphis, Tennessee). It has been in operation since 
October, 1998, at MLSO.
The Mark-IV K-coronameter replaces its predecessor, the Mark-III and 
features a high speed liquid crystal polarization modulator, a low noise 
CCD line array detector, and an achromatic polarizing beam splitter to 
measure Stokes I, Q, and U. Mark-IV produces polarization brightness maps 
of the lower corona in white light (700 to 900nm) from about 1.14 to 2.86 
solar radii at a 3-minute cadence. Its plate scale is 5.95"/pixel, with 
data accuracy of approximately %15 and a noise level of approximately 
4x10-9 B/Bsun.
The Mark-IV instrument is a significant improvement over its predecessor 
in the following ways: lower system noise due to an improved detector and 
associated electronics, better sky noise rejection due to improved 
polarization optics and faster polarization modulation rate, higher 
spatial resolution, and a wider field of view.
These improvements result in higher quality polarization-brightness 
images which may be taken over a greater range of sky conditions than 
was heretofore possible.
For information about the Mk4 K-Coronameter calibration technique, see 
Elmore et al. (199?).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.E.Holzer</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MaunaLoaSO/MK4</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>Coronograph</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>Photopolarimeter</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>ACOS/MK4 at MLSO</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Ground/MaunaLoaSO</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>