<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" 
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.2</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ground/MaunaLoaSO/PICS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>MLSO_ACOS_PICS</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2015-10-23T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The first H-alpha [656.3 nm] telescope at MLSO 
was the Prominence Monitor (PMON), which went into operation on 
4 February 1980. It acquired both disk and limb images on B/W 35mm film.
On 20 February 1994, the Acme 35mm film camera was upgraded to a Kodak 
Megaplus [Model 1.6] CCD detector (1534x1030 pixels) with a sample size 
of 3 arcseconds, and the telescope was renamed the Digital Prominence 
Monitor (DPM).  On 25 September 1997, the PICS instrument replaced the 
DPM at MLSO. It provides several improvements over the DPM instrument, 
including optics for polarization measurement (since removed), improved 
temperature control, a narrower bandpass filter for disk observations, 
and improved optics for limb observations. PICS takes images at 656.3 nm, 
with a FOV of 2.3 solar radii, a spatial resolution of 2.9"/pixel, 
and a nominal cadence of 3 minutes.
PICS was decommissioned on 23 Feb, 2010 to make room on the tracking 
spar for the Coronal Multi-channel Polarimeter (CoMP). In its place, 
a small Coronado SolarMax60 Halpha imager was installed. The Coronado 
has a full FOV out to 2.25 Rsun at low latitudes and 1.6 Rsun over the 
poles before cropping (for large EPLs, the full FOV can be provided). 
Its spacial resolution is 1.77 arcseconds per pixel, with a nominal 
cadence of 3 minutes (capable of obtaining an image per 
second).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.E.Holzer</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ground/MaunaLoaSO/PICS</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>ACOS/PICS at MLSO</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Ground/MaunaLoaSO</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>