<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES/5/EPS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Energetic Particle Sensor</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-07-02T15:25:42Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The energetic particle monitor consisted of three detector assemblies, each covering limited regions of the overall energy spectrum. The first two detector assemblies monitored protons in seven energy ranges between 0.8 and 500 MeV and alpha particles in six energy ranges from 4 to &gt;400 MeV. There was also one channel for the measurement of electrons in the energy range above 500 keV. The third detector, high energy proton and alpha detector (HEPAD), monitored protons in four energy ranges above 370 MeV and alpha particles in two energy ranges above 640 MeV/nucleon. In all, there were 25 channels of data, each channel sampling at a slow rate of once in a few seconds, or once in a few minutes.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Herbert.H.Sauer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Terry.Onsager</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-049A-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Energetic Particle Monitor experiment on the GOES 5 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Data Provider README</Name>
        <URL>https://satdat.ngdc.noaa.gov/sem/goes/goes_docs/avg/readme.txt</URL>
        <Description>Caveats and more information about data from this instrument.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES5/GOES/EPS</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energetic Particle Monitor on GOES 5</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/5</ObservatoryID>
    <Caveats>From http://goes.ngdc.noaa.gov/data/avg/readme.txt:

Energetic Particle Sensor (EPS)

Solid-state detectors with pulse-height discrimination measure proton, ?-
particle, and electron fluxes.  E1 and I1 channels are responding primarily to
trapped outer-zone particles.  The I2 channel may occasionally respond to
trapped particles during magnetically disturbed conditions.  The remaining
proton integrals measure fluxes originating outside the magnetosphere -- from
the Sun or the heart of the Galaxy.

Users of GOES particle data should be aware that significant secondary responses
may exist in the particle data, i.e. responses from other particles and energies
and from directions outside the nominal detector entrance aperture.  The
integrated protons displayed in these plots have been partially corrected for
these effects.

Ion Data Quality

Users of GOES particle data should be aware that significant secondary responses
may exist in the particle data, i.e. responses from other particles and energies
and from directions outside the nominal detector entrance aperture. A
description of the algorithm that partially corrects for these effects is
described below.

Electron Data Quality

The Electron detector responds significantly to protons above 32 MeV; therefore,
electron data are contaminated when a proton event is in progress. Beginning
with GOES-8 the electron data have had a preliminary correction applied,
however, even these data are not to be considered research quality at this time.

The GOES-5 electron channel is noisy from 1986 onwards and readings are a
possible factor of 2 high. One component of the GOES-6 particle detector system
has had radiation damage since 1986 that reduced its counting efficiency
progressively. At present the E1 and P4 channels derived from this component
record at only a few percent of their proper rates. In 1991 the telescope
component of the GOES-7 energetic particle detector system experienced episodes
of malfunction (noise). The first period began at 0330 UT, October 18, 1991 and
extended to November 5, 1991. The detector was commanded off for 12 hours. At
turn-on the detector appeared to have recovered, but failed again on November
11, with a rerecovery on November 12 after a second turn-off of three hours. The
detector has since operated normally. The noise periods may be identified by
unusually high rates being shown by the P1 channel and the derived &gt; 1 MeV
integral channel. Currently, the GOES-7 Energetic Particle Sensor is left turned
off for 4 hours after eclipse to minimize bad data.
</Caveats>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
