<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_3.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.3</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Oersted/OESM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Overhauser Effect Scalar Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Overhauser Effect Scalar Magnetometer is one of four instruments onboard the Oersted spacecraft.  The purpose of the scalar magnetometer is to provide an in-flight, absolute calibration of the vector magnetometer, independent on environmental conditions. The measuring range of the instrument is from 16000 nT to 54000 nT with an accuracy of better than 1 nT. Rate of measurements will be 1 sample per second. Power consumption is limited to 3 W in CW mode and less than 0.5 W in stand-by mode. Weight of the instrument including electronic box is less than 2.5 kg. The scalar magnetometer is provided by Centre National d`Etudes Spatiale (CNES) in Toulouse, and developed by Laboratory for Electronics, Technology and Instrumentation (LETI) in Grenoble.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Dr. Jose J Achache; Dr. Ib Laursen; The European Space Agency; Danish Meteorological Institute (Denmark); Danish Ministry of Commerce (Denmark); Danish Ministry of Transportation (Denmark); Centre National d'Etudes Spatiales (France); National Aeronautics and Space Administration (United States); Danish Ministry of Science (Denmark); Danish Space Research Institute (Denmark)</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jose.J.Achache</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ib.Laursen</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1999-008B-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Overhauser Effect Scalar Magnetometer.</Description>
        <Language>en</Language>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Overhauser Effect Scalar Magnetometer</Name>
        <URL>http://www.geophysik.uni-bremen.de/statisch/downloads/254/Overhauser-Magnetometers.pdf</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Overhauser Effect Scalar Magnetometer including some theory.</Description>
        <Language>en</Language>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Oersted/OESM</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Overhauser Effect Scalar Magnetometer on the Oersted spacecraft</InvestigationName>
    <OperatingSpan>
      <StartDate>1999-03-15T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
      <StopDate>2009-03-25T23:59:59Z</StopDate>
      <Note>It is not clear if this mission is still active.</Note>
</OperatingSpan>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Oersted</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
