<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.4.0</Version>
   <Observatory>
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/BARREL/1L</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>BARREL Balloon 1L</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2022-02-20T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2022-02-20T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>BARREL Observatories: Delete obsolete www.dartmouth.edu Information URL, Resource Header Description reformated. Metadata submitted by J.M. Weygand on 2022-01-28, reviewed by LFB</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>This Document describes BARREL Balloon 1L.

BARREL, which is an Acronym for Balloon Array for RBSP Relativistic Electron Losses, is a Multiple Balloon Investigation to study Particles that escape from the Radiation Belts and funnel down Earth&#039;s Magnetic Field Lines toward the Poles. It involves two Multi-Balloon Launches from the South African Antarctic Station, SANAE IV, and the British Station, Halley Bay, with later for a Northern Hemisphere Campaigns. During each Campaign, 5-8 long-duration Balloon Payloads (~20 kg) would be launched to an Altitude of 30 km to 35 km simultaneously for three to 40 Days. Each Balloon will carry a NaI Scintillator to measure the Bremsstrahlung X-Rays produced by precipitating Relativistic Electrons as they collide with Neutrals in Earth&#039;s Atmosphere to allow an Estimate of the total Electron Loss from the Radiation Belts. The Payload also includes a DC Magnetometer. Besides the two Scientific Instruments, each Payload includes Solar Panels generating 6 W and an onboard Battery for Power, a Number of Sensors to monitor the Operation of the Payload, a GPS Receiver to track the Position and Altitude of the Balloon, and an Iridium Satellite Link that transfer all Data at a Rate of 2 kps.

BARREL is the first NASA Living with a Star Geospace Mission of Opportunity. Observations are planned for when the Balloon Array will be conjugate with the NASA Van Allen Probes Spacecraft, such that direct Comparison is possible between one another.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robyn.Millan</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>BARREL Mission Overview Poster (Reference #2)</Name>
            <URL>https://barrel.rmillan.host.dartmouth.edu/documents/BARREL.foldout_v2.pdf</URL>
            <Description>BARREL Mission Foldout Sheet Overview Poster</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>JASTP Publication: Understanding Relativistic Electron Losses with BARREL (Reference #3)</Name>
            <URL>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1364682611000071</URL>
            <Description>Understanding Relativistic Electron Losses with BARREL, J. Atmos. and Sol.-Terr. Phys., 73(11-12), July 2011, pages 1425-1434 by R. Millan et al. Description of Science Output from BARREL Test Flights, includes Discussion of Instruments and Usage. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jastp.2011.01.006</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>BARREL Science Team Information</Name>
            <URL>http://www.dartmouth.edu/~barrel/team.html</URL>
            <Description>Site used for BARREL Science Team Information</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/BARREL</ObservatoryGroupID>
      <Location>
         <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Stratosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
      </Location>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>2012-12-01T00:00:00.000Z</StartDate>
         <StopDate>2016-09-01T23:59:59.999Z</StopDate>
         <Note>The Operating Span corresponds to the Time Interval spanned from the Date of the first Balloon Launch of the first BARREL Campaign to the Date of the last Balloon Launch of the fourth BARREL Campaign. BARREL is a Balloon based Mission of Opportunity to augment the Measurements from the NASA Van Allen Probes by measuring the Precipitation of Relativistic Electrons from the Radiation Belts during four Multi-Balloon Campaigns. The Balloons will be launched from the Antarctic. During each Campaign, 5 to 8 Long Duration (5 day to 10 day) Balloons would be aloft simultaneously over a one Month Period to provide Measurements of the Spatial Extent of the Relativistic Electron Precipitation and to allow an Estimate of the total Electron Loss from the Radiation Belts.</Note>
      </OperatingSpan>
   </Observatory>
</Spase>
