<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_7_1.xsd">
  <Version>2.7.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/FERMI/GBM</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>GBM</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>Fermi Gamma-ray Burst Monitor</AlternateName>
         <ReleaseDate>2025-03-19</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2025-03-19</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Initial SPASE 2.7.1 XML resource description submission, metadata submitted by Rebecca Ringuette</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>The Fermi GBM provides simultaneous low-energy spectral and temporal measurements for all GRBs within the LAT FOV. The combined GBM and LAT effective energy range spans more than 7 energy decades from 10 keV to 300 GeV. The GBM extends the energy coverage from below the typical GRB spectral break at ~100 keV to above the LAT's low-energy cutoff for inter-instrument calibration. Furthermore, the GBM's sensitivity and FOV are commensurate with the LAT's to ensure that many bursts will have simultaneous low-energy and high-energy measurements with similar statistical significance. The GBM also assists the LAT in detecting and localizing GRBs rapidly by providing prompt notification to the ground of a burst trigger. Finally, the GBM provides coarse GRB locations over a wide FOV that can be used to repoint the LAT at particularly interesting bursts (both inside and outside the LAT FOV) for gamma-ray afterglow observations. These locations are also sent to the ground to notify external follow-up observers.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/C.A.Wilson-Hodge</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>GBM Home Page</Name>
            <URL>https://fermi.gsfc.nasa.gov/science/instruments/gbm.html</URL>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>ScintillationDetector</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Fermi Gamma-ray Burst Monitor</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/FERMI</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
