<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_8.xsd">
   <Version>2.2.8</Version>
   <Observatory>
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DMSP_5D-3/F15</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Defense Meteorological Satellite Program, DMSP-F15</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>DMSP_5D-3/F15</AlternateName>
         <AlternateName>DMSP-F15</AlternateName>
         <AlternateName>USA 147</AlternateName>
         <AlternateName>25991</AlternateName>
         <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>DMSP F15 (USA 147) was launched by a Titan rocket from Vandenberg AFB on December 12,
   1999 into a 101 minute, sun-synchronous near-polar orbit at an altitude of 840km and with the Local
   Time nodes of 21:10 and 9:10. The Defense Meteorological Satellite Program (DMSP) is a Department
   of Defense (DoD) program run by the Air Force Space and Missle Systems Center (SMC). The program
   designs, builds, launches, and maintains satellites monitoring the meteorological, oceanographic,
   and solar-terrestrial physics environments. Each DMSP satellite has a above the surface of the earth.
   The visible and infrared sensors (OLS) collect images across a 3000 km swath, providing global
   coverage twice per day. The combination of day/night and dawn/dusk satellites allows monitoring of
   global information such as clouds every 6 hours. The microwave imager (MI) and sounders (T1, T2)
   cover one half the width of the visible and infrared swath. These instruments cover polar regions at
   least twice and the equatorial region once per day. The space environment sensors (J4, M, IES)
   record along-track plasma densities, velocities, composition and drifts. The data from the DMSP
   satellites are received and used at operational centers continuously. The data are sent to the
   National Geophysical Data Center&apos;s Solar Terrestrial Physics Division (NGDC/STP) by the Air Force
   Weather Agency (AFWA) for creation of an archive.
</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>DMSP Data Manager, NOAA National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service, NESDIS</Acknowledgement>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Dieter.K.Bilitza</PersonID>
            <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
</Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
</Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Defense Meteorological Satellite Program, DMSP-F15 Web Site</Name>
            <URL>https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/satellites/view/62/</URL>
            <Description>Defense Meteorological Satellite Program, DMSP-F15, Information and Details</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
            <Name>Defense Meteorological Satellite Program, Block 5D-3 Spacecraft Overview</Name>
            <URL>http://spaceflight101.com/spacecraft/dmsp-block-5d-3/</URL>
            <Description>Detailed information on the Defense Meteorological Satellite Program 5D-3 satellite series.</Description>
</InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>NSSDC&apos;s Master Catalog</Name>
            <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1999-067A</URL>
            <Description>Information about the DMSP 5D-3/F15 mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
      <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DMSP</ObservatoryGroupID>
      <Location>
         <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>1999-12-12T00:00:00</StartDate>
</OperatingSpan>
</Observatory>
</Spase>
