<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/LEE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low-Energy Electrons (LEE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>LEE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment provided direct measurements of the energy input into the upper
   atmosphere due to electrons and protons in the energy range of 0.2 to 25 keV. The experiment
   acquired differential measurements of the energy influx and angular distribution. There were
   two detectors measuring electrons and protons from 0.2 to 25 keV in 16 logarithmically spaced
   steps, and one detector measuring 5 keV electrons continuously. Each detector consisted of a
   cylindrical electrostatic analyzer for species and energy selection, and a Spiraltron electron
   multiplier for particle detection. Energy distributions were obtained by applying different
   fixed or stepped voltages to the deflection plates. Distributions in angle were measured using
   the spacecraft spin and the analyzers' positions on the spacecraft. In the despun modes,
   measurements were obtained at 45 deg to the spacecraft equator, and radially away from the
   earth. Detector look angles were chosen to give optimum magnetic pitch-angle coverage when the
   spacecraft was moving either poleward or equatorward. All detectors were identical in construction
   and used 1- x 6-mm entrance apertures. Counts were accumulated over 55.7 ms and read out each
   main telemetry frame (62.5 ms). The two stepped detectors moved one energy step once each main
   frame with the same accumulation time, requiring about 1 s for a complete cycle of steps. More
   complete details of this experiment may be found in
   R. A. Hoffman et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 393, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that
   exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.A.Hoffman</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-12</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low-Energy Electrons (LEE) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00393</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Low-Energy Electrons experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low-Energy Electrons (LEE) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
