<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <Instrument>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ROCSAT-1/IPEI</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>ROCSAT1,IPEI, Ionospheric Plasma and Electrodynamics Instrument</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2021-07-21T14:08:31Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>The Ionospheric Plasma and Electrodynamics Instrument (IPEI) is a joint project of the National Space Program Office of the Republic of China, the University of Texas at Dallas, The National Central University, and the National Chiao-Tung University. The IPEI sensors consist of an ion-trap (IT), a pair of ion drift meters (IDM), and a retarding potential analyzer (RPA). The instrument is designed to measure the ion density, temperature, and drift velocity in order to study the large-scale electrodynamics, plasma distribution, and the small-scale plasma structure in the low-latitude ionosphere with emphasis on the equatorial region above Taiwan. The high-resolution measurements will enable detailed studies of equatorial bubbles, Rayleigh-Taylor instability, the ExB drift instability, and the Perkins instability.</Description>
            <Contact>
              <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Dieter.K.Bilitza</PersonID>
              <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
           <InformationURL>
                 <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
                 <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1999-002A-03</URL>
                 <Description>Information about the ROCSAT1,IPEI, Ionospheric Plasma and Electrodynamics Instrument experiment on the ROCSAT-1 mission.
</Description>
</InformationURL>
           <InformationURL>
             <Name>Scientific Mission of the IPEI Payload Onboard ROCSAT-1</Name>
             <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1999-002A-03</URL>
             <Description>Published in the TAO, Supplementary Issue, 19-42, March 1999</Description>
             <Language>en</Language>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
     <InstrumentType>IonChamber</InstrumentType>
     <InstrumentType>IonDrift</InstrumentType>
     <InstrumentType>RetardingPotentialAnalyser</InstrumentType>
     <InvestigationName>ROCSAT1,IPEI, Ionospheric Plasma and Electrodynamics Instrument on ROCSAT-1</InvestigationName>
     <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ROCSAT-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
