<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <Instrument>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Equator-S/EDI</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Electron Drift Instrument (EDI)</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>This instrument measures the displacement of a weak (&lt; 1 microA) beam of test electrons, after one
                gyration in the ambient magnetic field, that is induced by electric fields or magnetic gradients. This displacement
                causes the beam to return to a detector on the spacecraft only when emitted in one of the two precisely determined
                directions. By employing two beam and two detectors, these directions can be monitored continuously and the displacement
                obtained by triangulation. For small magnetic fields the triangulation degenerates and the displacement is obtained
                instead from the difference in the travel times of the electrons in the two beams. As a by-product, the measured
                times-of-flight provide a precise measurement of the magnetic field magnitude. To separately determine the electric
                fields and the magnetic field gradients, the electron energy is varied between 1.0 and 0.5 keV. Time-resolution varies
                with ambient conditions, but should typically be 100 ms or better. The electron drift instrument on EQUATOR-S is identical
                to the instrument developed for CLUSTER.   
</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Goetz.Paschmann</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
                <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-075B-02</URL>
                <Description>Information about the Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) experiment on the Equator-S mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
        <InstrumentType>ElectronDriftInstrument</InstrumentType>
        <InvestigationName>Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) on Equator-S</InvestigationName>
        <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Equator-S</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>