<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-D/NATE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>NATE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was designed to measure the kinetic temperature of the neutral atmosphere by
   determining the instantaneous density of molecular nitrogen in a spherical chamber coupled to the
   atmosphere through a knife-edge orifice. Analysis of the measured molecular nitrogen density variation
   over a spin cycle with a knowledge of the satellite's motion and orientation led to a determination of
   the ambient temperature, independent of scale height. The NATE also provided measurements of the neutral
   composition, when commanded into the appropriate mode. In addition, values for the zonal wind were
   obtained, from measurement of the "stream" position relative to the satellite velocity. An alternate
   measurement of neutral temperature also was undertaken, using a baffle inserted in front of the orifice
   to intercept a portion of the gas particle stream entering the chamber. When the satellite was in the
   despun mode, the baffle was made to oscillate in the stepwise fashion in order to interrupt the particle
   stream seen by the orificed chamber. These chamber density variations were interpreted to yield the
   neutral gas kinetic temperature also. A dual-filament ion source sampled the thermalized molecular
   nitrogen in the chamber and produced an ion beam density proportional to the nitrogen chamber density.
   From the source, the ionized beam was directed to a quadrupole analyzer, tuned to pass those particles
   whose mass-to-charge ratio (M/Q) was 28. This ionized nitrogen beam then passed on to an electron
   multiplier. The output pulses were amplified and counted in a 16-bit accumulator. The sensor was
   vacuum-sealed prior to launch and opened to the atmosphere after the spacecraft was in orbit. More
   experiment details can be found in N. W. Spencer et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 287, 1973. NSSDC
   has all the useful data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nelson.W.Spencer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1975-096A-09</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE) experiment on the AE-D mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00287</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Neutral Atmosphere Temperature experiment on the AE-D mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE) on AE-D</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-D</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
