<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-D/PES</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Photoelectron Spectrometer (PES)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>PES</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was designed to provide information on the intensity, angular distribution,
   energy spectrum, and net flows along field lines, of electrons in the thermosphere with energies between
   1 and 500 eV. The instrument consisted of two identical oppositely directed hemispherical electrostatic
   analyzers, and it had 30 operating modes. Each spectrometer had a relative energy resolution plus or
   minus 2.5% and a geometric factor on the order of 0.001 sq cm sr, independent of electron energy.
   Three separate energy ranges could be sensed: 0 to 25, 0 to 100, or 0 to 500 eV. Measurements from
   these intervals could be sequenced in 5 different ways. Data could be taken from either sensor
   separately, or alternately with time resolution varying from 0.25 to 8 s. There were two deflection
   voltage scan rates determined by spacecraft clock. This voltage was changed in 64 steps, and was done
   at 4 or 16 steps per telemetry frame. With 16 frames/s, this allowed a choice of either one 64-point
   spectrum, or four 16-point spectra in 1 s. The longest (8 s) cycle of data involved observations using
   increasing voltage steps for the lowest, middle, lowest, then highest energy ranges (in that order)
   for 1 s each. A repeat for decreasing voltage steps completed the cycle. A more detailed description
   of this experiment may be found in J. P. Doering et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 387, 1973.
   NSSDC has all the useful data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.P.Doering</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1975-096A-03</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Photoelectron Spectrometer (PES) experiment on the AE-D mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00387</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Photoelectron Spectrometer (PES) experiment on the AE-D mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Photoelectron Spectrometer (PES) on AE-D</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-D</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
