<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-2/IMAP3</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Three-Axis Magnetic Field (IMAP-3)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The IMAP-3 magnetic field experiment is designed to study the following processes in the Earth's plasma environment: structure of the inner magnetosphere magnetic field; structure of the small scale field-aligned currents; dynamics of the field-aligned currents during substorms; and relation of the processes in the auroral zone and in the tail.
The IMAP-3 was designed and manufactured under cooperation of IZMIRAN (http://www.izmiran.rssi.ru), NPL SDS (Bulgaria) and PIC GPI of RAS.
The instrument is designed to measure three components of the DC magnetic field in two ranges: +/- 6800 nT with resolution 1 nT and +/- 68000 nT with resolution 10 nT. Usually magnetometer data are transmitted to the scientific SSNI telemetry system at a rate of one vector per 3 seconds; during special intervals data are transmitted to telemetry at 2 or 8 vectors second depending on the instrument operating mode.
The spacecraft was launched on 29 August 1996. The IMAP-3 was initially tested on the 9th of September and started to work regularly on the 14th of September.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ivan.S.Arshinkov</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1996-050C&amp;ex=5</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Three-Axis Magnetic Field (IMAP-3) experiment on the Interball Auroral Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Three-Axis Magnetic Field (IMAP-3) on Interball Auroral Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-2</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
