<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-2/MEMO</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Analyzer of Wideband Electromagnetic Waves (MEMO)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The MEMO (Mesure Multicomposante des Ondes) experiment is a part of the wave consortium of experiments on Interball 2. It provides waveforms associated with the measurement of two to five components in three freuency bands: ELF (5-1000 Hz), VLF (1-20 kHz), and LF (20-250 kHz). Due to the memory capacity and allocated bit rate (about 10 kbps), the main operational mode of MEMO is a snapshot mode. Preliminary results show that, despite a functional degradation and a fatal failure four months after switching on, the MEMO experiment has fulfilled part of its initial objectives.
The MEMO instrument is closely associated with three other experiments: POLRAD in the LF/MF frequency range; NVK-ONCH in the ELF and VLF ranges; and IESP in the ULF range. The MEMO experiment mainly deals with the digitized waveform data it produces internally. However, it is also used to transmit: the ELF NVK_ONCH filter-bank data on a regular basis; and the VLF-ONCH filter data and the POLRAD sounder data via specific modes.
This information was taken from the paper by Lefeuvre et al., Ann. Geophysicae 16, 1117-1136 (1998), which contains a much more detailed description of these complex instruments and also presents preliminary results.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Francois.Lefeuvre</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1996-050C&amp;ex=8</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Analyzer of Wideband Electromagnetic Waves (MEMO) experiment on the Interball Auroral Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>WaveformReceiver</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Analyzer of Wideband Electromagnetic Waves (MEMO) on Interball Auroral Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-2</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
