<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Yohkoh/WBS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Wide Band Spectrometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Wide Band Spectrometer (WBS) consists of three subinstruments that together span the energy range from 2 keV to 100 MeV. They are (1) the soft X-ray spectrometer (SXS), a gas proportional counter filled with Xe and CO2 that covers the 2 to 30 keV band, (2) the hard X-ray spectrometer (HXS), a NaI scintillator that covers the energy range 20 - 600 keV, and (3) the gamma-ray spectrometer (GRS), a pair of identical BGO scintillators (Bi4 Ge3 O12), that cover the 0.2 - 100 MeV band. SXS has a FOV 10 deg square, has a sensitive area of approximately 12 cm**2, divides its energy range into 128 channels, and records 128-channel spectra every 2 s, 2-channel spectra every 0.25 s. The energy resolution at 5.9 keV is approximately 20% (FWHM). The HXS records pulse height data in 32 quadratically spaced channels over the 20 - 400 keV range every 1 s, and 2-channel pulse count data for the bands 20 - 50 keV and 50 - 600 keV every 0.125 s. The GRS has a resolution approximately twice that of the HXS, and records a 128-channel energy-loss spectrum, which is processed via spectral deconvolution to yield the incident gamma- ray spectrum. 128-channel spectra are recorded every 4 s. An assortment of other time resolutions apply for various energy channels. GRS also has detection sensitivity to solar flare neutrons.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jun.Nishimura</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1991-062A&amp;ex=3</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Wide Band Spectrometer experiment on the Yohkoh mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Spectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Wide Band Spectrometer on Yohkoh</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Yohkoh</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
