<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema    http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_1.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/THEMIS/Ground/GIMA/BETT/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>THEMIS Ground-based Vector Magnetic Field GIMA Network at Bettles</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>THEMIS GBO University of Alaska Geophysical Institute Magnetometer Array (GIMA) network at Bettles</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2011-12-02T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description> The magnetometer is at the THEMIS/Bettles station. This magnetometer was provided by the University of Alaska Geophysical Institute as part of the Geophysical Institute Magnetometer Array (GIMA). The THEMIS network of ground magnetometers (GMAGS) consists of 28 stations in the Northern United States and Canada. Ten of these systems were installed as part of the Ground-Based Observatory (GBO) systems for THEMIS. Eleven are installed in schools and are part of the THEMIS Education and Public Outreach (E/PO) program (GEONS). The GBO and GEONS networks use the same type of fluxgate magnetometer that measures the vector magnetic field with 0.01 nT resolution at 2 samples/second.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>We acknowledge NASA contract NAS5-02099 and V. Angelopoulos for use of data from the THEMIS Mission. Specifically:S. Mende and C. T. Russell for use of the GMAG data</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Vassilis.Angelopoulos</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christopher.T.Russell</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Stephen.B.Mende</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>THEMIS Ground Magnetometer Data Center at UAF Geophysical Institute</Name>
        <URL>http://magnet.asf.alaska.edu/access_data_back.html</URL>
        <Description>Web server for displaying and downloading THEMIS ground magnetometer data</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>THEMIS Web site ground magnetometer page.</Name>
        <URL>http://themis.ssl.berkeley.edu/instrument_gmags.shtml</URL>
        <Description>THEMIS Web Site page on ground magnetometers. Contains links to papers, general purpose information and caveats.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>NASA THEMIS Mission</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/THEMIS/Ground/GIMA</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
