<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_1.xsd">
 <Version>2.3.1</Version>
 <Repository>
  <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Repository/WALDO</ResourceID>
  <ResourceHeader>
   <ResourceName>WALDO</ResourceName>
   <AlternateName>Worldwide Archive of Low-frequency Data and Observations</AlternateName>
   <ReleaseDate>2020-06-03T16:39:32</ReleaseDate>
   <Description>
WALDO is a joint effort between Georgia Tech and CU-Denver, using data
collected by Stanford University from the 1970s until 2016, and then
by both Georgia Tech and CU-Denver starting in 2014. 

WALDO description
(from
https://eos.org/science-updates/returning-lightning-data-to-the-cloud)

We have developed an online interface that allows easy access to the
data, which can also be shared with anyone with a Google account upon
request. Through the website, users can view automatically generated
quick-look plots to make it easy to find out what’s available, for
example, maps of receiver sites from which data from a given day are
available, annual calendars showing data availability, and summary
charts of the data on a day-by-day basis.

WALDO enables direct access to raw data including:
 Broadband VLF data,  Broadband LF data,  Narrowband data.
 Quick-look plots of Broadband and Narrowband data are also available.
WALDO provides software tools mostly in Matlab but Python tools are planned as well.  
Anticipated total data volume will exceed 1000 TB.
The “What’s Available” page, and the “Availability Maps” show what sites are available for each day.

   </Description>
   <Acknowledgement>
     DATA USAGE POLICY
The data in the WALDO database have been collected by Stanford
University, the Georgia Institute of Technology, and the University of
Colorado Denver. Funding has been provided by the United States
government under various basic science research grants over many
years. 

To maximize the benefit of those investments, WALDO data are released
without restriction, and can be freely analyzed or published. 

The curators of WALDO are Morris Cohen (Georgia Tech) and Mark
Golkowski (CU-Denver). We request that the following acknowledgement
be added in any publication using data from WALDO 

"VLF data are provided by the WALDO database (http://waldo.world),
operated jointly by the Georgia Institute of Technology, and the
University of Colorado Denver, using data collected from those
institutions as well as Stanford University, and has been supported by
various US government grants from the NSF, NASA, and the Department of
Defense." 

If extensive amounts of WALDO data are used in a publication, the
curators request, but do not require, to be contacted to discuss the
possibility of joint authorship, with the WALDO curators providing
help analyzing and interpreting the large dataset. 
   </Acknowledgement>
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Morris.Cohen</PersonID>
    <Role>ArchiveSpecialist</Role>
   </Contact>
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Mark.Golkowski</PersonID>
    <Role>ArchiveSpecialist</Role>
   </Contact>
   <InformationURL>
     <Name>Returning Lightning Data to the Cloud
     </Name>
     <URL>https://doi.org/10.1029/2020EO142801
     </URL>
   </InformationURL>
  </ResourceHeader>
  <AccessURL>
   <Name>WALDO</Name>
   <URL>http://waldo.world</URL>
  </AccessURL>
 </Repository>
</Spase>
