<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios2/E7</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Galactic and Solar Cosmic Rays</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The detector complement of this experiment (E7) consisted of
three separate dE/dx vs E telescopes and a proportional counter for monitoring
solar X rays in the range 2-8 keV. The high-energy telescope had a geometric
factor of 0.22 sq cm-sr and measured electrons in three ranges between 2 and 8 MeV,
and protons and alpha particles in three ranges between 20 and 56 MeV/n. Protons
above 230 MeV were also measured. The first low-energy telescope (geometric factor
was 0.155 sq cm-sr) measured protons and Z&gt;1 particles in three ranges between
3 and 21 MeV/n. The second low-energy telescope (geometric factor was 0.015 sq cm-sr)
measured protons in several ranges between 0.12 and 2.1 MeV, alpha particles in the
ranges 0.6-2.1 and 6-21.2 MeV/n, and electrons in four ranges between 0.12 and 2 MeV.
For a number of coincidence modes, counting-rate data sectored into eight 45-deg
sectors were obtained. The data cycle time was dependent on the spacecraft telemetry
rate (variable between 4096 and 8 bits/s) and format. Under optimum conditions, five
events per second were pulse-height analyzed and the rate data cycle was of the order
of 5 min. At the slowest combination of bit rate and format, a complete data cycle
required about 2.5 h. See IEEE Trans. on Nuc. Sci., NS-22, p. 570, 1975, and
Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, pp. 258-260, 1975, for further details.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nand.Lal</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1976-003A&amp;ex=8</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar and Galactic Cosmic Ray experiment on the Helios-B mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Galactic and SolarCosmic Ray Experiment on Helios-B</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios2</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
