<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-1_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>1.2.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://nssdc/instrument/1973-078A-07</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cosmic Ray Nuclear Composition</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2005-07-07T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment used two telescopes to measure the composition and energy spectra of solar (and galactic) particles above about 0.5 MeV/nucleon. The main telescope consisted of five collinear elements (three solid state, one CsI, and one sapphire Cerenkov) surrounded by a plastic anticoincidence shield. The telescope had a 60-deg, full-angle acceptance cone with its axis approximately normal to the spacecraft spin axis, permitting eight-sectored information on particle arrival direction. Four elements of the main telescope were pulse-height analyzed, and low- and high-gain modes could be selected by command to permit resolution of the elements H through Ni or of electrons and the isotopes of H and He and light nuclei. A selection-priority scheme was included to permit sampling of less abundant particle species under normal and solar-flare conditions. The low-energy telescope was essentially a two-element shielded solid-state detector with a 70-deg full-angle acceptance cone. The first element was pulse-height analyzed, and data were recorded by sectors.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://nssdc/person/35235</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/database/MasterCatalog?sc=1973-078A&amp;ex=7</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cosmic Ray Nuclear Composition experiment on the IMP-J mission.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cosmic Ray Nuclear Composition on IMP-J</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://nssdc/observatory/1973-078A</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
  <Person>
    <ResourceID>spase://nssdc/person/35235</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2002-11-08T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Clifford Lopate</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of New Hampshire</OrganizationName>
    <Email>clifford.lopate@unh.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-603-862-5101</PhoneNumber>
  </Person>
</Spase>
