<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-1_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>1.2.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://nssdc/instrument/1990-090B-02</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cosmic Ray and Solar Particles (SIM/COSPIN)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>COSPIN</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>SIM</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2005-10-20T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objectives of this investigation are to study the energy, charge, and mass spectra of energetic charged particles in interplanetary space in the energy range from approximately 0.5 MeV/nucleon (for protons) to approximately 100 MeV/nucleon; and to study spatial gradients and the propagation of charged particles throughout the heliosphere by measuring absolute flux and vector anisotropy. The instrument consists of six charged-particle telescopes (CPT) and associated electronics. A high-energy telescope provides measurements of the chemical and isotopic composition and of the energy spectrum of the cosmic radiation above approximately 10 MeV/nucleon. A low-energy telescope (LET) extends chemical composition and spectral measurements downward to &lt;1 MeV/nucleon. The anisotropy telescopes, in conjunction with the LET, provide a means of determining the distribution of arrival directions in three dimensions of low-energy protons and He nuclei. A high-flux telescope provides measurements of the intensity and arrival direction of protons, He, C, N, O, and Fe-group nuclei in high-flux environments, such as intense solar flares or Jupiter's magnetosphere, where the other sensor systems may become saturated. Each CPT provides output to a data-processing unit (DPU). The electron telescope consists of a double Cerenkov and semiconductor detector telescope which interfaces with the DPU. The instrument has a mass of 14.6 kg including shielding and uses 14.6 W of power. The data rate is 80 bps in cruise mode and 160 bps in tracking mode.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://nssdc/person/6398</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/database/MasterCatalog?sc=1990-090B&amp;ex=2</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cosmic Ray and Solar Particles (SIM/COSPIN) experiment on the Ulysses mission.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cosmic Ray and Solar Particles (SIM/COSPIN) on Ulysses</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://nssdc/observatory/1990-090B</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
  <Person>
    <ResourceID>spase://nssdc/person/6398</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2002-11-08T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. R. Bruce McKibben</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of New Hampshire</OrganizationName>
    <Email>bruce.mckibben@unh.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-603-862-5087</PhoneNumber>
  </Person>
</Spase>
