<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-1_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>1.2.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://swg/instrument/1990-090B-03</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low-Energy Ions and Electrons (LAN/HI-SCALE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>HI-SCALE</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>LAN</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2005-10-20T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objectives of this investigation are (1) to investigate the solar-flare process with measurements of non-relativistic and relativistic electrons, and non-relativistic ions, and their dependence on heliolatitude; (2) to investigate solar elemental abundances with measurements of chemical composition of nuclei of solar origin at all heliolatitudes; (3) to investigate the interplanetary propagation of solar energetic particles by measurement of anisotropy and composition parameters; (4) to investigate acceleration processes; and (5) to investigate temporal and spatial variations of particle intensity in and near the Jovian magnetosphere. The instrumentation consists of two double-ended solid state detector systems which measure ions in the range 50 keV to 5 MeV and electrons in the range 30 to 300 keV, and a (dE/dX, E) telescope using a 5-micrometer-thick front detector for ion elemental abundances in the range 1 to 15 MeV/nucleon (Fe). Each double-ended system is composed on one end of a foil spectrometer in which a 0.35 mg/sq cm thin foil excludes ions below 0.350 keV, allowing electrons above 30 keV to be detected. Further, one of the other ends of one of the systems is a magnetic spectrometer, using a rare-earth magnet to separate electrons from ions (geometric factor for ions is approximately 0.5 sq cm-sr, and for electrons 0.05 sq cm-sr). Orientation of the sensor systems is such that complete pitch-angle coverage is obtained. The instrument has a mass of 5.8 kg including shielding, and uses 4.0 W of power. The data rate is 80 bps in cruise mode and 160 bps in tracking mode.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://swg/Person/Louis.J.Lanzerotti</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/database/MasterCatalog?sc=1990-090B&amp;ex=3</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low-Energy Ions and Electrons (LAN/HI-SCALE) experiment on the Ulysses mission.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low-Energy Ions and Electrons (LAN/HI-SCALE) on Ulysses</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://swg/observatory/1990-090B</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
