<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/MAGA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Magnetic Field Observations (MAG-A)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>MAG-A</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
         This investigation used a triaxial fluxgate magnetometer (MAG-A),
         similar to one on board DE 2, to obtain vector magnetic
         field data needed to study the magnetosphere-ionosphere-
         atmosphere coupling.
        
         The primary objective of this
         investigation was to obtain measurements of field-aligned
         currents in the auroral oval and over the polar cap at two
         different altitudes. This was accomplished using the two
         spacecraft and correlations of these measurements with
         observations of electric fields, plasma waves, suprathermal
         particles, thermal particles, and auroral images obtained from
         investigation 81-070A-03. Ultra low frequency (ULF) waves were
         also studied.
        
         The magnetometer incorporated its own 12-bit
         analog-to-digital converter, a 4-bit digital compensation
         register for each axis, and a system control to generate a 48-
         bit data word consisting of a 16-bit representation of the
         field measured along each of the three magnetometer axes. Track
         and hold modules were used to obtain simultaneous samples on
         all three axes. Instrument bandwidth was 25 Hz. The instrument
         dynamic range was plus or minus 6.2E4 nT, and the resolution
         was plus or minus 1.5 nT in the 6.2E4 nT region, plus or minus
         0.25 nT in the 1.E3 nT region, and plus or minus 0.02 nT in the
         80 nT region. The magnetometer's digital compensation of the
         ambient field was nominally in 8.E3 nT increments.
        
         Further
         details are in W. H. Farthing et al., Space Sci. Instrum., v.
         5, n. 4, p. 551, 1981.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Masahisa.Sugiura</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-070A&amp;ex=1</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Magnetic Field Observations (MAG-A) experiment on the Dynamics Explorer 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Magnetic Field Observations (MAG-A) on Dynamics Explorer 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
