<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/PWI</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Dynamics Explorer 1 Plasma Waves Instrument (PWI)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>DE 1 PWI</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
        The Plasma Wave Instrument (PWI) measured ac electric fields
        over the frequency range from 1 Hz to 2 MHz, and an amplitude
        range of 0.03 microvolt per meter to 100 mV per meter. Magnetic
        fields were measured from 1 Hz to 400 kHz over an approximately
        100-dB range.
       
        The objectives of this investigation were to
        measure the spatial, temporal, spectral, and wave
        characteristics (particularly the Poynting vector component
        along the magnetic field line) and the wave polarization for
        extremely-low-frequency (ELF), very-low-frequency (VLF), and
        high-frequency (HF) noise phenomena. Of special interest were
        the auroral kilometric radiation and VLF hiss, and a variety of
        electrostatic waves that may cause field-aligned acceleration of
        particles.
       
        The investigation made use of the long dipole
        antennas in the spin plane and along the Z axis, and a magnetic
        loop antenna. A single-axis search coil magnetometer and a short
        electric antenna were included for low-frequency measurements
        and electrostatic noise measurements at short wavelengths.
       
        The electronics consisted of
       
        * (1) a wideband/long baseline receiver
        with a bandwidth of 10 or 40 kHz in the range 0-2 MHz;
        * (2) a step-frequency correlator, containing two sweep-frequency
        receivers and phase detectors, sweeping 100 Hz to 400 kHz in 32
        s, and giving the phase between magnetic and electric components
        of the field;
        * (3) a low-frequency correlator containing two
        filter receivers and phase detectors (eight filters in the range
        1.78-100 Hz). The sweep rate is 8 s/spectra at the high frequency end
        (above 18 Hz); it is 32 s/spectra for frequencies for 1.8-10 Hz;
        * (4) dc monitors that measured
        the voltage difference between the two sets of long dipole
        antennas; and
        * (5) a linear wave receiver, selectable from
        1.5 to 3.0, 3 to 6, or 10 to 16 kHz bands.
       
        The wideband receiver
        was flown to transmit wideband waveform signals to the ground
        via an analog transmitter, so that detailed high-resolution
        frequency-time analysis could be performed.
       
        Since June 23, 1984
        a malfunction in the spacecraft data- handling system has
        prevented access to some PWI data. Digital measurements from the
        sweep frequency receiver system were no longer accessible.
       
        More
        details are found in S. D. Shawhan et al., Space Sci. Instrum.,
        v. 5, n. 4, p. 535, 1981.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-070A-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Plasma Waves Instrument (PWI) experiment on the Dynamics Explorer 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma Waves Instrument (PWI) on Dynamics Explorer 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
