<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/CRS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cosmic Ray System (CRS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>CRS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This investigation studied the origin and acceleration process, life history, and dynamic contribution of interstellar cosmic rays, the nucleosynthesis of elements in cosmic-ray sources, the behavior of cosmic rays in the interplanetary medium, and the trapped planetary energetic-particle environment. The instrumentation included a High-Energy Telescope System (HETS) and a Low-Energy Telescope System (LETS). The HETS covered an energy range between 6 and 500 MeV/nucleon for nuclei ranging in atomic numbers from 1 through 30. In addition, electrons in the energy range between 3 and 100 MeV/nucleon were measured by this telescope and an electron telescope. The LETS measured the energy and determined the identity of nuclei for energies between 0.15 and 30 MeV/nucleon and atomic numbers from 1 to 30. The instruments also measured the anisotropies of electrons and nuclei. In addition, electrons in the energy range between 3 and 100 MeV/nucleon were measured by an electron telescope.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.C.Stone.Jr</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-084A&amp;ex=8</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cosmic Ray System (CRS) experiment on the Voyager 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cosmic Ray System (CRS) on Voyager 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Voyager1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
