<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_1.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/PRA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Voyager 1 Planetary Radio Astronomy (PRA) experiment</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Voyager 1 PRA</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
 The Planetary Radio Astronomy (PRA) experiments' primary               
      objective is to locate and explain kilometric, hectometric, and        
      decametric radio emissions from the planets, to measure plasma         
      resonances near the giant planets, and to detect lightning on          
      the giant planets. They have also been successful at observing         
      solar radio emissions from the perspective of the outer solar          
      system.                                                                
                                                                             
      The Voyager Planetary Radio Astronomy experiment is designed to        
      investigate naturally-occurring radio emissions from the outer         
      planets and Sun. Radio emissions from Jupiter have been known          
      from Earth-based measurements since 1955 (Burke, B. F., and K. L. Franklin,
      Observations of a variable radio source associated with planet
      Jupiter, J. Geophys. Res., 60, 213–217, 1955.); PRA represents the           
      first attempt to survey those emissions, and to perform near-          
      encounter searches for radio emissions from the other gas              
      planets.                                                               
                                                                             
      Radio emissions can be used to determine the rate of rotation          
      of the inner core of a planet; to determine the existence of a         
      magnetic field and search for magnetic anomalies. Radio                
      emissions are often the only remote diagnostic for interactions        
      occurring in the portions of magnetospheres through which a            
      spacecraft does not pass. This is particularly true for the            
      inner magnetosphere, which usually goes unsampled.                     
                                                                             
      PRA is also sensitive to impacts on the spacecraft by micron-          
      sized dust particles. Particularly in its high data rate modes,        
      the information obtained therefrom produces insights into the          
      processes which occur under such situations.                           

      Instrument Description                                                 
      ======================                                                 
      There were two receivers on each spacecraft, for the
      lower and higher frequency ranges, respectively. The low-band
      receiver had 70 channels of 1.0 kHz bandwidth each, with center
      frequencies spaced at 19.2 kHz intervals from 1.2 kHz to 1326kHz.
      The high-band receiver consisted of 128 channels of 200 kHz
      bandwidth each, with center frequencies spaced at 307.2 kHz
      intervals from 1.2 MHz to 40.4 MHz. The high-band receiver was
      designed especially for the observation of Jovian decametric radio
      emissions.
                                                                             
      The PRA receivers were driven by two orthogonal antennas mounted          
      on the spacecraft body. Each antenna element is made of BeCu           
      hollow tubes 0.5 inches in diameter and is 10 meters in                
      length.  By combining the signals from the two antennas in a           
      90 degree hybrid, the PRA instrument can distinguish between           
      the opposing states, left hand and right hand, of circular             
      polarization of an incoming wave.                                      
                                                                             
      The Planetary Radio Astronomy (PRA) receivers were calibrated          
      under environmentally-controlled conditions and over the               
      entire frequency and dynamic range of the instruments. This            
      calibration consisted in application of a known narrow-band            
      signal across the inputs and recording the receiver outputs.           
                                                                             
      The laboratory calibrations provided  power levels for each            
      data number (DN) and each frequency in terms of known inputs           
      across the antenna terminals of each of the experiment's two           
      monopoles. Calibrations were carried out over a range of               
      receiver temperatures, but in practice the stability of the            
      receiver as a function of temperature and the stability of the         
      temperature of the receiver as a function of mission phase and         
      the status of the overall spacecraft were such that a single           
      calibration for each DN at each frequency could be used.               
                                                                             
      Receiver output levels were quantized. The minimum value for           
      the wave flux density was frequency dependent varying from             
      5.E-20 W M**-2 Hz**-1 at frequencies below 1.5 MHz to 5.E-19           
      at frequencies above 1.5 MHz. The maximum wave flux density            
      was typically 50 dB above the minimum value. The instrument            
      noise level also was frequency dependent. It was about 1.E-19          
      W M**-2 Hz**-1 below 1.5 MHz. The noise at 10 MHz was still            
      about 1E-19 W M**-2 Hz**-1, increased to about 1.E-17 W M**-2          
      Hz**-1 at 25 MHz, and then decreased to an intermediate value          
      at 40 MHz.                                                             
                                                                             
      The low-band and high-band operation of the receiver differ.           
      In low-band the receiver operated with a sharply tuned filter          
      only 1 kHz broad at the 3 dB points and in high-band, with a           
      200 kHz filter. The gain of the receivers was designed in such         
      a way that the output increased discontinuously by 23 dB               
      (corresponding to the 200:1 bandwidth ratio) between the               
      lowest frequency of high-band and the highest frequency of             
      low-band.  This caused the instrument output to remain                 
      constant across the high-band to low-band transition point if          
      its input was broadband noise.                                         
                                                                             
      If unpolarized radiation fell orthogonally on each monopole,           
      the total unpolarized flux density for signals below about 5           
      MHz could be roughly estimated to be                                   
                                                                             
            S = So (10**(m/1000)),                                           
                                                                             
      where m was the channel reading in millibels and So is                 
                                                                             
            So = 1.5E-21 (W/Hz m**2).                                        
                                                                             
      No reliable method for estimating the flux density exists for          
      frequencies above 5 MHz due to the increasing effect of                
      antenna resonances.                                                    
                                                                             
      Although the PRA instrument had 14 possible operating modes,           
      in practice the mode called POLLO was used more than 95% of            
      the time.  In POLLO, the receiver swept through all 198                
      channels in sequence from the highest frequency to the lowest.         
      At each frequency step, data were produced every 30 msec,              
      consisting of 25 msec of integration and 5 msec of switching           
      and settling time. Thus, a full sweep through all 200 channels         
      took 6 sec (including 60 msec for two status words).  Between          
      steps the 90 degree hybrid was switched such that the receiver         
      was sensitive to the alternate sense of circular polarization.         
      This toggling between left hand and right hand polarization            
      itself alternated with each 6 sec receiver sweep. Thus, for a          
      given frequency, a pair of left hand and right hand                    
      measurements were 6 sec apart.            

      For further details on the PRA instrument see
      Warwick, J.W. et al., Planetary Radio Astronomy Experiment for
      Voyager Missions, Space Science Reviews, 21, 309-327, 1977 and,

      Lang, G.J. and Peltzer, R.G., Planetary Astronomy Receiver,
      IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Elecronics Systems, AES-13, 466-472, 1977.
                                                                             
      For further details on calibration see Wang, L. and Carr, T.D.,
      Recalibration of the Voyager PRA antenna for polarization sense
      measurement, Astron. Astrophys., 281, 945-954, 1994. and references therein.
                                                                             
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.W.Warwick</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Joseph.K.Alexander.Jr</PersonID>
        <Role>DeputyPI</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Andre.C.Boischot</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Walter.E.Brown.Jr</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.D.Carr</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Samuel.L.Gulkis</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Fred.T.Haddock</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christopher.C.Harvey</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Michael.L.Kaiser</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Yolande.Leblanc</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/R.G.Peltzer</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Roger.J.Phillips</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Anthony.C.Riddle</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.H.Staelin</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-084A-10</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Planetary Radio Astronomy (PRA) instrument on the Voyager 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>PPI/PDS PRA Instrument catalog file PRAINST.CAT</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/ditdos/download?id=pds://PPI/VG_1601/CATALOG/PRAINST.CAT</URL>
        <Description>Information about the PRA instrument on the Voyager mission including operational mode descriptions.
</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>PPI/PDS PRA Instrument file INST.TXT</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/ditdos/download?id=pds://PPI/VG_1501/DATA/PRA/INST.TXT</URL>
        <Description>Information about the PRA instrument on the Voyager spacecraft.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>SpectralPowerReceiver</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>LongWire</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Planetary Radio Astronomy (PRA) instrument on Voyager 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Voyager1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
