<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Pioneer10/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Magnetic Fields</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The magnetometer on Pioneer 10 (also carried on Pioneer 11) is a triaxial helium magnetometer with seven dynamic ranges, from plus or minus 2.5 nT to plus or minus 10 gauss. The linearity was 0.1%, and the noise threshold was 0.01% rms for 0-1 Hz. The accuracy was 0.5% of full scale range. The experiment worked as planned until November 1975, when the spacecraft was at about 8 au. No further useful data were obtained. The experimenter has used RTN coordinates in his data analysis. In this system, R (or X) is radially outward from the sun, T (or Y) is parallel to the sun's equatorial plane and has its direction given by the cross product of the sun's spin vector into the radial direction (i.e., into R) and N (or Z) completes the right-handed orthogonal system (positive northward). A detailed instrument description may be found in Smith et al., IEEE Trans. On Magnetics, Mag-11, p. 962, July 1975. Some data also include the interplanetary region. This instrument failed in October 1975 and was turned off in June 1986.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.J.Smith</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1972-012A&amp;ex=1</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Magnetic Fields experiment on the Pioneer 10 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Magnetic Fields on Pioneer 10</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Pioneer10</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
