<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_1.xsd">
 <Version>2.3.1</Version>
 <Instrument>
  <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/SipleExperiment/VLF</ResourceID>
  <ResourceHeader>
   <ResourceName>Siple Experiment VLF</ResourceName>
   <ReleaseDate>2020-12-29T15:15:09</ReleaseDate>
   <Description>
     Receivers were set up at Siple station (75.93
   deg. S, 84.25 deg. W geographic, corresponding to an invariant
   latitude of 60.4 deg. S, at L = 4.2), and 
   near the geomagnetic conjugate point (first at Roberval, Quebec,
   Canada (48.52 deg. N, 72.23 deg. W) and in 1986
   near Lake Mistissini, Canada (50.42 deg. N, 73.87 deg. W)).
   The receiver system consisted of two delta-shaped crossed loops
     mounted on a central 30-foot-high(~9 m) support with a base of 60
     feet (18.3 m). These two mutually perpendicular antennas could be
     used for direction finding. In normal single-channel recording,
     one antenna is selected for minimum power line interference. A
     preamplifier at the base of the antenna boosts the received
     signal to an appropriate level for transmission to the recording
     equipment in the station. The receiving system includes provision
     for time marks, amplitude and frequency calibration, and
     automatic program control.
  Accurate timing of transmitted and received
   pulses were established by frequency standards at Siple and
   Roberval. These standards were calibrated regularly against Station
   WWV and are kept within a few milliseconds of UT. 
 
   Complete results of the Siple
   station experiment are summarized in Helliwell, R. A.,(1988)
   Rev. Geophys., 26, 551-578, but analysis
   work on this dataset continued well after the experiment
   ended. These data were originally stored on Ampex magnetic tapes
   then converted over to a digitized format with some error
   correction applied as described by Li et al., (2014) JGR, 119,1837-1850.  </Description> 
    <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.A.Helliwell</PersonID>
    <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
   </Contact>
  <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Morris.Cohen</PersonID>
    <Role>ArchiveSpecialist</Role>
   </Contact>
   <InformationURL>
    <URL>http://waldo.world/description-of-data/</URL>
   </InformationURL>
  </ResourceHeader>
  <InstrumentType>SpectralPowerReceiver</InstrumentType>
  <InvestigationName>Siple Experiment</InvestigationName>
  <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/SipleExperiment</ObservatoryID>
 </Instrument>
</Spase>
