<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/RF</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Soft Solar X-ray Photometer RF</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The X-ray photometer RF is designed to measure the solar X-ray radiation in the soft spectral range. In addition to continuous monitoring of the solar radiation in the X-ray range, the instrument can be used as an indicator for automatic switching-on of the scientific instrumentation for registering the processes of the active solar events, assuming a change in the solar X-ray radiation as a precursor of these phenomena. The photometer is oriented along the -Z-axis of the subsatellite, i.e. toward the Sun. The photometer consists of two units: the detector unit and electronics unit. The photometer is the scintillating detector with an aluminium foil in front of it to prevent penetration of soft particles and X-rays. The output signal is passed to the two-channel amplitude analyzer where it is selected in two ranges: 10-15 keV and 15-60 keV. The impulses from the channels with a fixed amplitude are transferred to the electronics unit where they are accumulated during 0.8 s (time of one exposure step). The maximum capacity of the detector is 183441 impulses/0.8 second, so for higher flux intensity (which is hardly probable) the detector data are not valid.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Frantisek.Farnik</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=7</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Soft Solar X-ray Photometer RF experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Photometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Soft Solar X-ray Photometer RF on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
