<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <Instrument>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DSX/DIME</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Dosimetry Inter-comparison and Miniaturization Experiment Board #1 (DIME-1) and Dosimetry Inter-comparison and Miniaturization Experiment Board #2 (DIME-2)</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>"Objectives:  Use five different COTS microdosimeters to characterize radiation induced total ionizing dose, displacement damage, and single event effects"
"Goals:    1) Provide data to permit appropriate dosimetry selection in future missions to characterize/resolve operational anomalies.  2) Validate particle transport codes by varying shielding thicknesses on RADFETs"
(SET-1 payload site)

"Dosimetry Intercomparison and Miniaturization Experiment (DIME) will measure space radiation environments which are detrimental to space system reliability using novel dosimetry techniques. DIME occupies two 3U card slots on the SET-1 carrier, and is being developed by Clemson University. Specific DIME measurements include: 1. Radiation-Sensing Field-Effect Transistor (RADFET) - threshold voltage shift as a function of time; converted to total ionizing dose (TID). 2. Erasable Programmable Read-only Memory (EPROM) - threshold voltage shift as a function of time; converted to TID. Also number of single event upsets (SEU) as a function of time to measure rates as a function of radiation level. 3. Ultraviolet erasable Programmable Read-only Memory (UVPROM) – charge stored on floating gates is neutralized with radiation exposure. Resulting bit flips reflect micro-dose deposited in gates. 4. Linear Energy Transfer (LET) Spectrometer - pulse height spectra as function of time; converted to LET to measure ions including protons. As with CEASE, one spectrometer is optimized for high LET ions and the other for low LET ions. 5. Optically Stimulated Luminescent (OSL) Films – visible emission spectrum as a function of time gives a sensitive measure of the ionizing dose." (THE DEMONSTRATION AND SCIENCE EXPERIMENTS (DSX): A FUNDAMENTAL SCIENCE RESEARCH MISSION ADVANCING TECHNOLOGIES THAT ENABLE MEO SPACEFLIGHT)</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peter.J.McNulty</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Michael.A.Xapsos</PersonID>
                <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>Demonstration and Science Experiments
(DSX) Satellite</Name>
                <URL>https://www.amostech.com/TechnicalPapers/2009/Space-Based_Assets/Scherbarth.pdf</URL>
                <Description>DSX Fact Sheet, Sept. 2005</Description>
</InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>THE DEMONSTRATION AND SCIENCE EXPERIMENTS (DSX): A FUNDAMENTAL SCIENCE RESEARCH MISSION ADVANCING TECHNOLOGIES THAT ENABLE MEO SPACEFLIGHT</Name>
                <URL>https://lws-set.gsfc.nasa.gov/documents/DSX_paper.pdf</URL>
                <Description>2006 Instrument paper</Description>
</InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>AFRL's demonstration and science experiments (DSX) mission</Name>
                <URL>https://dspace.mit.edu/handle/1721.1/52739</URL>
                <Description>2009 DSX Paper</Description>
</InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>DSX Mission/SET-1</Name>
                <URL>https://lws-set.gsfc.nasa.gov/documents/DSX_and%20_SET_for_public_release.pdf</URL>
                <Description>DSX powerpoint, includes data flow diagrams.</Description>
</InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>SET-1 payload site</Name>
                <URL>https://lws-set.gsfc.nasa.gov/mission.html</URL>
                <Description>NASA site detailing SET1 payload.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
        <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
        <InvestigationName>DSX/SET1</InvestigationName>
        <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DSX</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>