<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <Instrument>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DSX/LCI</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>DSX Wave Particle Interaction eXperiment (WPIx) Loss Cone Imager (LCI)</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>"The Loss Cone Imager (LCI) is an electron loss-cone particle experiment that will provide a measurement of three dimensional energetic particle distributions with emphasis on the measurement of the fluxes of energetic
electrons along the direction parallel and anti-parallel to the local geomagnetic field vector. The LCI consists of three sensor systems. There are two rotating sensor
heads (RSH), with ±180° motorized articulation capability, and each projects a 180° field of view fan with each scan head position, so that together the full 4π unit sphere may be imaged. In addition to full rotation modes each of the RSH can use data from the DC Vector Magnetometer (VMAG) for its motor pointing control loop and be oriented independently. The VMAG data is included in the LCI data stream for later
ground data correlation. The third sensor system is a separate Solid State
Detector (SSD) telescope called the High Sensitivity Telescope (HST). It will obtain fluxes of energetic electrons along the geomagnetic field vector direction.
This telescope is designed to have a geometric factor of 0.1 cm2 steradian with sufficient shielding to permit the detection of 100 particles/cm2-sec-steradian in the loss cone. The LCI is under development by Boston University, and also benefits from heritage obtained in the development and flight of similar instruments such as the Imaging Electron Spectrometer (IES) on the ESA-NASA Cluster mission and the NASA Polar mission. The LCI scanning heads and HST are shown in Fig. 12." (THE DEMONSTRATION AND SCIENCE EXPERIMENTS (DSX): A FUNDAMENTAL SCIENCE RESEARCH MISSION ADVANCING TECHNOLOGIES THAT ENABLE MEO SPACEFLIGHT)
"The LCI features a High Sensitivity Telescope (HST) which will measure 100 – 500 keV electrons with 0.1 cm2-str geometric factor with 6.5 degrees of loss cone. The LCI also features a Fixed Sensor Head (FSH) with 130 degrees x 10 degrees of pitch angle distribution for 50 – 700 keV electrons every 167 msec. Boston University is building the LCI instrument." (Fennelly, 2011)</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Theodore.Allan.Fritz</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>Demonstration and Science Experiments
(DSX) Satellite</Name>
                <URL>https://www.amostech.com/TechnicalPapers/2009/Space-Based_Assets/Scherbarth.pdf</URL>
                <Description>DSX Fact Sheet, Sept. 2005</Description>
</InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>THE DEMONSTRATION AND SCIENCE EXPERIMENTS (DSX): A FUNDAMENTAL SCIENCE RESEARCH MISSION ADVANCING TECHNOLOGIES THAT ENABLE MEO SPACEFLIGHT</Name>
                <URL>https://lws-set.gsfc.nasa.gov/documents/DSX_paper.pdf</URL>
                <Description>2006 Instrument paper</Description>
</InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>AFRL's demonstration and science experiments (DSX) mission</Name>
                <URL>https://dspace.mit.edu/handle/1721.1/52739</URL>
                <Description>2009 DSX Paper</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
        <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
        <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
        <!--InstrumentType>SSD</InstrumentType-->
        <InvestigationName>DSX-WPIx</InvestigationName>
        <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DSX</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>