<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/FAST/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Tri-Axial Fluxgate and Search-coil Magnetometers</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The FAST magnetic field instrumentation includes a DC fluxgate magnetometer and an AC search coil magnetometer. The fluxgate magnetometer is a three-axis instrument using highly stable low noise ring core sensors. It is boom-mounted at 2 m from the spacecraft body in a shielded housing. It provides magnetic field information from DC to 100 Hz to a 16-bit analog-to-digital converter. Time resolution is 2 ms and the sensitivity below 50 Hz close to 1 nT. The search coil magnetometer (also boom-mounted) uses a three axis sensor system that contains laminated permalloy cores, windings and preamplifiers. The design is based on the OGO-5 instrument with recent developments implemented on classified projects. The signals are further amplified in the electronics before analog-to-digital conversion. An AC magnetic field measurement is provided over the frequency range 10 Hz to 2.5 kHz with a time resolution of 0.1 ms and a frequency-dependent sensitivity between 10^-8 and 10^-10 nT^2/Hz.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.W.Carlson</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1996-049A&amp;ex=4</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Tri-Axial Fluxgate and Search-coil Magnetometers experiment on the FAST mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Tri-Axial Fluxgate and Search-coil Magnetometers on FAST</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/FAST</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
