<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Pioneer11/CPC</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Charged Particle Composition</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment used two telescopes to measure the composition and energy spectra of solar (and galactic) particles above about 0.5 MeV/nucleon. The main telescope consisted of five collinear elements (three solid state, one CsI, and one sapphire Cerenkov) surrounded by a plastic anticoincidence shield. The telescope had a 60-deg, full-angle acceptance cone with its axis approximately normal to the spacecraft spin axis, permitting 8-sectored information on particle arrival direction. Four elements of the main telescope were pulse-height analyzed, and low- and high-gain modes could be selected by command to permit resolution of the elements H through Ni or of electrons and the isotopes of H, He, and light nuclei. A selection-priority scheme was included to permit sampling of less abundant particle species under normal and solar-flare conditions. The low-energy telescope was essentially a two-element, shielded, solid-state detector with a 70-deg, full-angle acceptance cone. The first element was pulse-height analyzed, and data were recorded by sectors. Data include the interplanetary region.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.A.Simpson</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-019A&amp;ex=2</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Charged Particle Composition experiment on the Pioneer 11 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Charged Particle Composition on Pioneer 11</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Pioneer11</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
