<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_3.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.3</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/SCATHA/SC11</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>SCATHA Magnetometer (SC11)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>SC11</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The SC11 experiment is a triaxial fluxgate magnetometer.  Each axis has a range of 0 to +/- 500 nT.  The sensor is mounted on a 4 m boom extended perpendicular to the spin axis.  The field vector is measured four times per second.  The output from the spin axis aligned sensor is also fed to a set of SC10 filter channels to provide the same frequency band outputs.  The bandwidth of this magnetometer output is ~100 Hz.  The same axis can be placed on a brodband channel. The filter output from SC10 provides a sensitivity of 10^-1 nT in the 20 to 200 Hz channel while the broadband output provides a sensitivity of 0.2 nT/V.
     
      An error analysis performed by the spacecraft manufacturer estimated that the absolute accuracy measurements of the ambient magnetic field component along the space vehicle's X-axis would be better than 1nT at 1σ confidence level. Errors in the other two axes would be less than in the X-axis. The spacecraft's maneuvers and spin provided in-flight information about the magnetometer zero levels and the spacecraft magnetic field components along those two axes.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Brian.G.Ledley</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jonathan.Thomas.Niehof</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>SCATHA server at BU</Name>
        <URL>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1029/SP020p0065</URL>
        <Description>Spacecraft/instrument description and data.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Magnetometer at NSSDC</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1979-007A-08</URL>
        <Description>Magnetometer (SC11) on SCATHA.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft Charging At High Altitudes (SCATHA)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/SCATHA</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
