<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <Observatory>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/NOAA/19</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>NOAA 19</ResourceName>
            <AlternateName>2009-005A</AlternateName>
            <AlternateName>NOAA-N Prime</AlternateName>
            <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>NOAA 19, or NOAA-N Prime, was launched 06 February 2009 at 10:22 UT aboard a Delta 2 rocket from Vandenberg. The 1440 kg satellite was built by Lockheed Martin Space Systems Company. The NOAA polar operational environmental satellites collect global data on: cloud cover; surface conditions such as ice, snow, and vegetation; atmospheric temperatures; and, moisture, aerosol, and ozone distributions. They also collect and relay information from fixed and moving data platforms. The instruments on-board NOAA 19 include two radiometers, the Advanced Very High Resolution Radiometer/3 (AVHRR/3) and the Solar Backscatter Ultraviolet Radiometer/2 (SBUV-2); three sounders, the High Resolution Infrared Radiation Sounder (HIRS/4), Advanced Microwave Sounding Unit-A (AMSU-A), and the Microwave Humidity Sounder (MHS); a space weather monitor, the Space Environment Monitor/2 (SEM-2); and an Advanced Data Collection System (ADCS). In addition, the satellite carries two search and rescue instruments: the Search and Rescue Repeater; and, the Search and Rescue Processor and three Digital Data Recorders.</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/UNKNOWN</PersonID>
                <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
</Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
                <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=2009-005A</URL>
                <Description>Information about the NOAA 19 mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
        <Location>
            <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
</Spase>