<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/ULEIS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Ultra-Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ULEIS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Ultra Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) measures energetic ion fluxes over the charge range
   from He through Ni from about 20 keV/nucleon to 10 MeV/nucleon with mass resolution less than or equal to 0.3 amu.
   Ultra-heavy species (above Ni) are also measured in a limited energy range near 0.5 MeV/nucleon. The ULEIS telescope
   is a time-of-flight (TOF) mass spectrometer which identifies ions by TOF and by residual kinetic energy E of
   particles which enter the 24 deg. x 20 deg. aperture and stop in one of an array of silicon solid state detectors.
   The geometric factor is about one sq.cm.-sr. The TOF measurement is determined by start and stop signals from
   microchannel plate (MCP) assemblies detecting secondary electrons emitted from incident ion passage through a
   thin entrance foil and other such foils within the telescope. In order to prevent electronic pile-up during intense
   flux periods, a mechanical shutter ('iris') slides partially closed under on-board control dependent on the start
   MCP singles counting rate. The iris can decrease the ULEIS geometric factor by up to a factor of 100 during the
   most intense events. Full analysis of individual ions requires 128 bits/event for up to six events per second. Two
   types of rate data are included: sectored singles rates for each detector with 8 sectors for 18 rates at 12
   bits/rate in compressed format; sectored counts of 5 particle species in 20 energy ranges and 8 sectors at 12
   bits/s (compressed). These rate data are read out every 60 seconds at 189 b/s. Housekeeping and other
   miscellaneous data require 43 b/s, the total data rate being about 1 kbps. The ULEIS experiment manager
   is Dr. Robert E. Gold of the Applied Physics Laboratory of Johns Hopkins University.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.E.Gold</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-03</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Ultra-Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1005079930780</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Ultra-Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Ultra-Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
