<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.2</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES/15/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Triaxial Fluxgate Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>MAG</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2021-07-20T13:41:27Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Each of the GOES-N,O,P satellites have two identical magnetometers, provided by Science
Applications International Corporation (SAIC), Inc. in Columbia, Maryland. They can operate
independently and simultaneously to measure the magnitude and direction of the Earth’s
geomagnetic field, detect variations in the magnetic field near the spacecraft, provide alerts of
solar wind shocks or sudden impulses that impact the magnetosphere, and assess the level of
geomagnetic activity. Magnetometer data is archived for the scientific community and other
interested users. One magnetometer sensor is mounted on the end of the boom 27.9 feet (8.5 m)
from the spacecraft. The other is positioned on the same boom 2.6 feet (0.8 m) closer to the
spacecraft. The second magnetometer sensor serves as a backup in case the first magnetometer
sensor fails and provides for better calibration of the magnetometer data channel.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Dr. Howard Singer; National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; Science Applications International Corporation (SAIC), Inc.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.J.Singer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>GOES N, O, and P Brochure</Name>
        <URL>https://www.nasa.gov/pdf/112855main_GOESNOPWeb1.pdf</URL>
        <Description>Information about the magnetometers onboard GOES 13.</Description>
        <Language>en</Language>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES/15/MAG</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Triaxial Fluxgate Magnetometer on GOES 15</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/15</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
