<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.0</Version>
    <Service>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Service/POLAR/TIDE/SummarySpectrograms</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Polar TIDE Summary Spectrograms</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2009-10-08T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>The TIDE Summary Spectrograms:  There are four types of spectrogram plots.  Half-orbit spectrograms cover all the data in 
consecutive plots, each plot covers about 9.3 hours.  Perigee spectrograms cover the time period near perigee in 30-60 minute 
plots prior to 01/01/01 and 3 hour plots from 01/01/01 to 04/16/08.  Plasmasphere spectrograms cover passes through the 
radiation belts when TIDE was in stand-by mode.  6-hour PSI spectrograms are consecutive plots of data when the Plasma Source 
Instrument (PSI) was turned on.  

For 1996 ion data, there are spectrograms plots for H+, O+, and He+ for data from 03/28/96 to 12/07/96.  Each plot has three 
spectrograms.  Each spectrogram plots a parameter, color coded by level, and plotted in time-spin angle, time-particle energy, or 
time-polar angle bins. The top spectrogram is time versus spin angle.  The energy flux data has been averaged over polar angle and 
energy.  The middle spectrogram is time versus particle energy.  The energy flux data has been averaged over spin and polar angle.  
The bottom spectrogram is time versus polar angle.  The energy flux data has been averaged over spin angle and energy.  For the 
Total Ion (Stops) data, there are plots for data from 12/08/96 to 04/16/08.  Each plot has two spectrograms.  The top spectrogram is 
time versus spin angle.  The energy flux data has been averaged over energy.  The bottom spectrogram is time versus particle energy.  
The energy flux data has been averaged over spin angle.  The spin angle spectrogram indicates the spacecraft ram direction (X) and 
the magnetic field location (+ and -).  Additional spacecraft information is listed as part of the time axis at the bottom of the plot.  
Processing information including start and stop times are at the top and the bottom of each plot.

TIDE was originally designed to detect mass-resolved ions, H+, O+, He+, and NO+, for 32 energy steps (31 reported), 32 spin angle 
bins, and 7 polar angle channels.  The detection of time-of-flight direct-events deteriorated rapidly early in the mission, reducing the 
ability to resolve ion masses and resulting in the lost of information in one axis (Z). After 09/30/96, the ion data is of poor quality and 
as a result, only Total Ions (Stops) are reported starting 12/08/96. Total Ions is the sum over the 7 polar angle channels of the particle 
counts detected by the Stop microchannel plate (MCP) detectors. The resolution in the 32 energy steps and in the 32 spin angle bins 
is retained. 1996 H+, O+, and He+ data are reported in the TIDE H0 CDFs.  In order to avoid damage to the MCPs, starting 03/27/96 
and continuing throughout the rest of the mission, the high voltage on the MCPs is reduced during radiation belt passes.</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.E.Moore</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.D.Craven</PersonID>
                <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peggy.Sloan</PersonID>
                <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
            </Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE NSSTC Home Page</Name>
                <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/tide</URL>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE NSSTC View Thumbnails</Name>
                <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/tide/display_thumbnails.html</URL>
            </InformationURL>
        </ResourceHeader>
        <AccessURL>
            <Name>Polar TIDE Summary Spectrograms</Name>
            <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/tide/summary_plots-dir/summary_gif_walk_2.pl</URL>
        </AccessURL>
    </Service>
</Spase>
