<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
	xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" 
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
    <Version>2.0.0</Version>
    <Service>
        <ResourceID>spase://VMO/DisplayData/POLAR/TIDE/SummarySpectrograms</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Polar TIDE Summary Spectrograms</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2009-08-01T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
			<Description>
			    The TIDE Summary Spectrograms:  There are four types of spectrogram plots.  Half-orbit spectrograms cover all the data in 
			    consecutive plots, each plot covers about 9.3 hours.  Perigee spectrograms cover the time period near perigee in 30-60 minute 
			    plots prior to 01/01/01 and 3 hour plots from 01/01/01 to 04/16/08.  Plasmasphere spectrograms cover passes through the 
			    radiation belts when TIDE was in stand-by mode.  6-hour PSI spectrograms are consecutive plots of data when the Plasma Source 
			    Instrument (PSI) was turned on.  For 1996 ion data, there are spectrograms plots for H+, O+, and He+ for data from 03/28/96 to 
			    12/07/96.  Each plot has three spectrograms.  Each spectrogram plots a parameter, color coded by level, and plotted in time-spin angle 
			    time-particle energy, or time-polar angle bins. The top spectrogram is time versus spin angle.  The energy flux data has been 
			    averaged over polar angle and energy.  The middle spectrogram is time versus particle energy.  The energy flux data has been 
			    averaged over spin and polar angle.  The bottom spectrogram is time versus polar angle.  The energy flux data has been averaged 
			    over spin angle and energy.  For the Total Ion (Stops) data, there are plots for data from 12/08/96 to 04/16/08.  Each plot has two 
			    spectrograms.  The top spectrogram is time versus spin angle.  The energy flux data has been averaged over energy.  The bottom 
			    spectrogram is time versus particle energy.  The energy flux data has been averaged over spin angle.  The spin angle spectrogram 
			    indicates the spacecraft ram direction (X) and the magnetic field location (+ and -).  Additional spacecraft information is listed as part 
			    of the time axis at the bottom of the plot.  Processing information including start and stop times are at the top and the bottom of each 
			    plot.
			</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.E.Moore</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.D.Craven</PersonID>
                <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peggy.Sloan</PersonID>
                <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
            </Contact>
           <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE NSSTC Home Page</Name>
                <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/tide</URL>
            </InformationURL>
           <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE GSFC Home Page</Name>
                <URL>http://tide.gsfc.nasa.gov/</URL>
				<Description>
The TIDE Home Page contains links to all available information about the instrument, its data and software, summary plot viewing, 
interactive data processing (Custom Plots and Data Dumps), mission information, and documentation about the website, data, 
and the processing software.
				</Description>
            </InformationURL>
        </ResourceHeader>

        <AccessURL>
          <Name>TIDE GSFC Summary Plot Gifwalk</Name>
          <URL>http://tide.gsfc.nasa.gov/summary_plots.shtml/</URL>
          <Description>PDF and JPEG formats are also available via this access url</Description>
        </AccessURL>

    </Service>
</Spase>