<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
	xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" 
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
    <Version>2.0.0</Version>
    <Service>
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Service/POLAR/TIDE/SummarySpectrograms</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Polar TIDE Summary Spectrograms</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2009-10-08T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
			<Description>
The TIDE Summary Spectrograms:  There are four types of spectrogram plots.  Half-orbit spectrograms cover all the data in 
consecutive plots, each plot covers about 9.3 hours.  Perigee spectrograms cover the time period near perigee in 30-60 minute 
plots prior to 01/01/01 and 3 hour plots from 01/01/01 to 04/16/08.  Plasmasphere spectrograms cover passes through the 
radiation belts when TIDE was in stand-by mode.  6-hour PSI spectrograms are consecutive plots of data when the Plasma Source 
Instrument (PSI) was turned on.  

For 1996 ion data, there are spectrograms plots for H+, O+, and He+ for data from 03/28/96 to 12/07/96.  Each plot has three 
spectrograms.  Each spectrogram plots a parameter, color coded by level, and plotted in time-spin angle, time-particle energy, or 
time-polar angle bins. The top spectrogram is time versus spin angle.  The energy flux data has been averaged over polar angle and 
energy.  The middle spectrogram is time versus particle energy.  The energy flux data has been averaged over spin and polar angle.  
The bottom spectrogram is time versus polar angle.  The energy flux data has been averaged over spin angle and energy.  For the 
Total Ion (Stops) data, there are plots for data from 12/08/96 to 04/16/08.  Each plot has two spectrograms.  The top spectrogram is 
time versus spin angle.  The energy flux data has been averaged over energy.  The bottom spectrogram is time versus particle energy.  
The energy flux data has been averaged over spin angle.  The spin angle spectrogram indicates the spacecraft ram direction (X) and 
the magnetic field location (+ and -).  Additional spacecraft information is listed as part of the time axis at the bottom of the plot.  
Processing information including start and stop times are at the top and the bottom of each plot.

TIDE was originally designed to detect mass-resolved ions, H+, O+, He+, and NO+, for 32 energy steps (31 reported), 32 spin angle 
bins, and 7 polar angle channels.  The detection of time-of-flight direct-events deteriorated rapidly early in the mission, reducing the 
ability to resolve ion masses and resulting in the lost of information in one axis (Z). After 09/30/96, the ion data is of poor quality and 
as a result, only Total Ions (Stops) are reported starting 12/08/96. Total Ions is the sum over the 7 polar angle channels of the particle 
counts detected by the Stop microchannel plate (MCP) detectors. The resolution in the 32 energy steps and in the 32 spin angle bins 
is retained. 1996 H+, O+, and He+ data are reported in the TIDE H0 CDFs.  In order to avoid damage to the MCPs, starting 03/27/96 
and continuing throughout the rest of the mission, the high voltage on the MCPs is reduced during radiation belt passes.
			</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.E.Moore</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.D.Craven</PersonID>
                <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peggy.Sloan</PersonID>
                <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
            </Contact>
           <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE NSSTC Home Page</Name>
                <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/tide</URL>
            </InformationURL>
           <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE GSFC Home Page</Name>
                <URL>http://tide.gsfc.nasa.gov/</URL>
				<Description>
The TIDE Home Page contains links to all available information about the instrument, its data and software, summary plot viewing, 
interactive data processing (Custom Plots and Data Dumps), mission information, and documentation about the website, data, 
and the processing software.
				</Description>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE NSSTC Summary Plot Gifwalk</Name>
                <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/tide/summary_plots-dir/summary_gif_walk_2.pl</URL>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE GSFC Summary Plot Gifwalk</Name>
                <URL>http://tide.gsfc.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/tide/summary_plots-dir/summary_gif_walk_2.pl</URL>
				<Description>
The TIDE Summary Plot Gifwalk lets the user scan through TIDE high time resolution spectrogram plots for the entire Polar mission.  
The user selects the ion type: Total (Ion), H+, O+, or He+; the year, month, and day to start the viewing; the spectrogram type: half-orbit, 
perigee, 6-hr PSI operations, or plasmasphere passes; and then presses Update Date/Type/Ion.  Once the gif image is displayed, 
there are arrow keys that allow the user to move forward and backward in time.  The user can download the gif by right click / save 
picture as or click on Download the pdf version to see and download the higher quality pdf plot.  There is a TIDE Website navigation 
bar at the bottom of the webpage.  The user can zoom in on an area of interest by clicking on the image at that point.  That takes the 
user to the High Time Resolution Spectrogram Custom Plot Webpage, where after changing any default processing options and 
Submitting Request, a new spectrogram plot will be created.
				</Description>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE NSSTC View Thumbnails</Name>
                <URL>http://tideuviRA.nsstc.nasa.gov/tide/display_thumbnails.html</URL>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>TIDE GSFC View Thumbnails</Name>
                <URL>http://tide.gsfc.nasa.gov/display_thumbnails.shtml</URL>
				<Description>
The TIDE Thumbnails webpage provides a way to view several TIDE summary spectrograms quickly.  Just specify the time range 
and select the ion and the spectrogram type (either half-orbit or perigee) and submit request.  Thumbnails of each spectrogram in 
the time range are displayed 8 per row.  Move the mouse over a thumbnail to get the start time of the plot.  Click on the thumbnail to 
view the full size gif and get a link to the pdf.
				</Description>
            </InformationURL>
        </ResourceHeader>
       <AccessURL>
         <Name>Polar TIDE Summary Spectrograms</Name>
         <URL>http://tideuvira.nsstc.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/tide/summary_plots-dir/summary_gif_walk_2.pl</URL>
       </AccessURL>

    </Service>
</Spase>