<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--$Id$-->
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-1_3_0.xsd">
  <Version>1.3.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://VMO/Instrument/IMP8/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>IMP-8 Magnetic Field Experiment</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>IMP8 MAG</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2008-06-18T18:23:19Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The magnetic field experiment on the IMP-8 spacecraft utilizes a tri-axial fluxgate (saturable inductor) magnetometer. The instrument originally had three, automatically determined, ranges, ±12 nT, ±36 nT, and ±108 nT, full scale. Because of a range-change circuit failure occurring in early July 1975, the experiment was commanded into a fixed ±36 nT range on July 11, 1975 at 12:55:09 UT and has been in that range ever since. The measurements are A-to-D converted onboard, to an 8-bit resolution, yielding ±0.14 nT quantization sensitivity, which is larger than the intrinsic sensor noise level of 0.025 nT RMS. The data from the two-bit (per component) adaptive delta modulator, incorporated into the instrument, and applied to the intrinsic sample rate of 25 vectors/sec., was never utilized, and hence the rate of the full (8-bit) vector words, which occur every 320 ms, represents the effective sample period of the instrument. The sampling rate is synchronized to the spacecraft clock; the basic spacecraft clock frequency is 6.4 kHz. The sensor unit is mounted on the end of a boom approximately 4 m from the center of the spacecraft.
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>User will acknowledge the IMP-8 magnetometer team in any publication resulting from the use of these data.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Adam.Szabo</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>IMP-8 Magnetometer Home Page</Name>
        <URL>http://lep694.gsfc.nasa.gov/imp8/imp8_hm.html</URL>
        <Description>A web site hosting IMP-8 magnetic experiment instrument information as well as web utilities for plotting and downloading data.
        </Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/database/MasterCatalog?sc=1973-078A&amp;ex=1</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Magnetic Field Experiment experiment on the IMP 8 mission.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Magnetic Field Experiment</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/IMP8</ObservatoryID>
    <Caveats/>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
