<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_1.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Geotail/CPI</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Geotail CPI</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Geotail Comprehensive Plasma Instrumentation</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objective of the Comprehensive Plasma Instrumentation (CPI) investigation is to make comprehensive observations of the three-dimensional velocity distribution functions of electrons and positive ions, with identification of ion species. The instrument contains three sets of quadrispherical analyzers with channel electron multipliers. These three obtain three-dimensional measurements for hot plasma and solar wind electrons, for solar wind ions, and for positive-ion composition measurements. The positive-ion composition measurement of the Ion Composition (IC) analyzer includes five miniature imaging mass spectrometers at the exit aperture of the analyzer, and covers masses from 1 to 550 u/Q at 100 eV, and 1 to 55 u/Q at 10 keV. The Hot Plasma (HP) analyzer measures electrons and ions in the range 1-50,000 eV/Q. The Solar Wind (SW) analyzer measures ions from 150 to 7,000 eV/Q. Sequencing of the energy analyzers and mass spectrometers, and other control functions, are provided by two microprocessors.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Louis.A.Frank</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1992-044A-04</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Comprehensive Plasma Instrument (CPI)</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://nssdc/instrument/1992-044A-04</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>QuadrisphericalAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>CPI on GEOTAIL</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Geotail</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
