<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Geotail/EPIC</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Geotail Energetic Particles and Ion Composition</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2011-02-02T17:11:58Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The principal objective of the EPIC (Energetic 
Particles and Ion Composition) investigation is to explore the 
outer magnetosphere and the distant magnetotail region and obtain 
information on the origin, transport, storage, acceleration and 
dynamics of suprathermal and non-thermal particle populations. 
The instrument contains two main sensor heads. The STICS assembly 
(Supra-Thermal Ion Composition Spectrometer) uses a quadrispherical 
electrostatic analyzer followed by a foil/solid state detector 
time-of-flight (TOF) telescope to measure charge state, mass and 
energy of ions with energies of 10 - 230 keV/charge. The ICS 
assembly (Ion Composition Subsystem) measures the mass and energy 
of energetic ions with energies of less than 50 keV to 3 MeV. It 
uses a pair of collimators with sweeping magnets to reject 
electrons, followed by TOF and energy analysis. A thin foil/solid 
state detector electron telescope measures electrons higher than 
30 keV. Directional measurements with a time resolution less than
3 s for all species are possible. A detailed instrument description, 
and a complete set of EPIC summary plots from launch to the present, 
plus on-line access to the digital data set, is available at the 
EPIC link below.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Anthony.T.Y.Lui</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.J.Williams</PersonID>
        <Role>FormerPI</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>EPIC site at JHU_APL</Name>
        <URL>http://sd-www.jhuapl.edu/Geotail/</URL>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>QuadrisphericalAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energetic Particles and Ion Composition</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Geotail</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
