<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-E/BIMS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Bennett Ion-Mass Spectrometer (BIMS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>BIMS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was flown to measure, throughout the orbit, the individual concentrations of
   all thermal ion species in the mass range 1 to 72 atomic mass units (u) and in the ambient density range
   from 5 to 5.E6 ions/cc. The mass range was normally scanned in 1.7 s, but the scan time per range could
   be increased by command. Laboratory and inflight determination of spectrometer efficiency and mass
   discrimination permitted direct conversion of measured ion currents to ambient concentrations. Correlation
   of these measured data with the results from companion experiments, CEP (75-107A-01) and RPA (75-107A-04)
   permitted individual ion concentrations to be determined with high accuracy. The experiment's four
   primary mechanical components were guard ring and ion-analyzer tube, collector and preamplifier assembly,
   vent, and main electronics housing. A three-stage Bennett tube with 7- to 5-cycle drift spaces was
   flown; it was modified to permit ion concentration measurements to be obtained at low altitudes.
   The balance between ion-current sensitivity and mass resolution in a Bennett spectrometer may be altered
   by changing appropriate voltages. These voltage changes were controlled independently by ground command
   for each one of the three mass ranges: 1 to 4, 2 to 18, and 8 to 72. More complete experiment details
   can be found in H. C. Brinton et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 369, 1973.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Henry.C.Brinton</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-11</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Bennett Ion-Mass Spectrometer (BIMS) experiment on the AE-E mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00323</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Bennett Ion-Mass Spectrometer (BIMS) on the AE-E mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Bennett Ion-Mass Spectrometer (BIMS) on AE-E</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-E</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
