<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-E/NACE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Neutral Atmosphere Composition (NACE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>NACE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment measured in situ the spatial distribution and temporal changes of the
   concentrations of the neutral atmospheric species. In addition, new insight into in situ measurement
   techniques was obtained from comparisons of these measurements with those obtained from other onboard
   experiments; namely, open source spectrometer (75-107A-07), solar EUV spectrometer (75-107A-06), and
   atmospheric density accelerometer (75-107A-02). The mass-spectrometer sensor had a gold-plated stainless
   steel thermalizing chamber and ion source, a hyperbolic rod quadrupole analyzer, and an off-axis
   electron multiplier. When operating in the "normal" format, the analyzer measured all masses in the
   range 1 to 44 atomic mass units with emphasis on hydrogen, helium, oxygen, nitrogen, and argon.
   Another format was optimized for minor constituent studies of gas species in the measured range.
   Spatial resolution was determined primarily by the mode of spacecraft operation. In orbit, the presealed
   spectrometer was opened, and the atmospheric constituents passed through a knife-edged orifice into the
   thermalization chamber and ion source. Selected ions left the quadrupole analyzer through a weak
   focusing lens and were accelerated into an electron multiplier, where they were turned 90 deg to
   strike the first dynode. The spectrometer had a resolution of better than 1 u for all masses between
   1 and 44, and the measurement system had a planned dynamic range of approximately 1.E8. There was
   provision for the instrument orifice to be covered during spacecraft thruster operations. More
   experiment details can be found in D. T. Pelz et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 277, 1973.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alan.E.Hedin</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1975-107A-08</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Neutral Atmosphere Composition (NACE) experiment on the AE-E mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00277</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the neutral-atmosphere composition experiment on the AE-E mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Neutral Atmosphere Composition (NACE) on AE-E</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-E</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
