<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_0_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.0.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-E/NATE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>NATE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was designed to measure the kinetic temperature of the neutral atmosphere by
   determining the instantaneous density of molecular nitrogen in a spherical chamber coupled to the
   atmosphere through a knife-edged orifice. Analysis of the measured molecular nitrogen density variation
   over a spin cycle with a knowledge of the satellite's motion and orientation led to a determination
   of the ambient temperature, independent of scale height. Measurements of the ambient neutral composition
   were obtained when the instrument was commanded into the appropriate mode. Approximate values for the
   meridional wind were obtained from the measurement of the "stream" position relative to the satellite
   velocity. An alternate measurement of neutral temperature was also undertaken, using a baffle inserted
   in front of the orifice to intercept a portion of the gas particle stream entering the chamber. When the
   satellite was in the despun mode, the baffle was made to oscillate in a stepwise fashion in order to
   interrupt the particle stream seen by the orificed chamber. These chamber density variations were
   interpreted to yield the neutral gas kinetic temperature too. A dual-filament ion source sampled the
   thermalized molecular nitrogen in the chamber and produced an ion beam density proportional to the
   nitrogen chamber density. From the source, this ionized nitrogen beam was directed into a quadrupole
   analyzer, tuned to pass those particles with a mass-to-charge ratio of 28. The beam then struck an
   electron multiplier, and the output pulses were amplified and counted. The sensor was vacuum-sealed prior
   to launch and opened to the atmosphere after the spacecraft was in orbit. More experiment details can
   be found in N. W. Spencer et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 287, 1973.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nelson.W.Spencer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1975-107A-09</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE) experiment on the AE-E mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00287</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Neutral Atmosphere Temperature experiment on the AE-E mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE) on AE-E</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-E</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument>
</Spase>
