<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_2.xsd">
   <Version>2.3.2</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MAVEN/SWEA</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>MAVEN Solar Wind Electron Analyzer, SWEA, Instrument</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>MAVEN SWEA Instrument</AlternateName>
         <ReleaseDate>2021-05-30T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2021-05-30T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Updated to SPASE Version 2.3.2 if needed, Applied quality conntrol for DOI usage, LFB</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>The Solar Wind Electron Analyzer, SWEA, is designed to measure the Energy and Angular Distribution of Solar Wind and Ionospheric Electrons. The Analyzer covers an Energy Range of 5 eV to 5 keV with a Resolution of 12% below 50 eV, increasing to 18% at maximum Energy. The Field of View is 360&#176; &#215; 130&#176; with an Angular Resolution of 22.5&#176; &#215; 20&#176;. SWEA has two Measurement Modes, a Solar Wind Mode for Altitudes above 500 km and an Ionosphere Mode below 500 km. In Solar Wind Mode, Energy Spectra and Pitch Angle Distributions are measured every 8 s, and in Ionosphere Mode, every 2 s. The Instrument is mounted on the End of a 1.75 m Boom extended from the MAVEN Back Panel.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>National Aeronautics and Space Administration, NASA, Applied Physic Laboratory, Johns Hopkins University</Acknowledgement>
         <Funding>
            <Agency>National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Mars Scout Program</Agency>
            <Project>MAVEN Solar Wind Electron Analyzer Investigation</Project>
            <AwardNumber>UNKNOWN</AwardNumber>
         </Funding>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.G.Mitchell</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>The Mars Atmosphere and Volatile Evolution, MAVEN, Solar Wind Electron Analyzer Instrument Home Page, LASP, UC Boulder</Name>
            <URL>https://lasp.colorado.edu/home/maven/science/instrument-package/swea/</URL>
            <Description>The Mars Atmosphere and Volatile Evolution, MAVEN, Solar Wind Electron Analyzer Instrument Home Page, Laboratory of Atmospheric and Space Physics, LASP, University of Colorado, Boulder</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>MAVEN Solar Wind Electron Analyzer, SWEA, Instrument paper, Published by Space Sci. Rev., Date: 2016-02-22</Name>
            <URL>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11214-015-0232-1</URL>
            <Description>Author List: Mitchell, D. L., Mazelle, C., Sauvaud, J.-A., Thocaven, J.-J., Rouzaud, J., Fedorov, A., Rouger, P., Toublanc, D., Taylor, E. R., Gordon, D. A., Robinson, M., Heavner, S., Turin, P., Diaz-Aguado, M., Curtis, D. W., Lin, R. P., &amp; Jakosky, B. M.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>NSSDC Master Catalog Listing, MAVEN Solar Wind Electron Analyzer, SWEA, Instrument</Name>
            <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2013-063A-07</URL>
            <Description>NSSDC Master Catalog Listing for the MAVEN Solar Wind Electron Analyzer, SWEA, Instrument, NSSDCA/COSPAR ID: 2013-063A-07</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>MAVEN Solar Wind Electron Analyzer Investigation</InvestigationName>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>2013-11-18T18:28:00</StartDate>
         <Note>MAVEN Launch Date and Time until data are available</Note>
      </OperatingSpan>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/MAVEN</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
